Chapter 8 Make Your Attitudes Your Allies Can you read minds?
Reading minds is easier than you think.
Perhaps you've never thought of it, but you read the minds of other people and they read your mind every day.
How do we do it?
We do it automatically, through attitude appraisals.
Remember the song, You Don't Need to Know the Language to Say You're in Love?
Bing Crosby made it famous some years ago.
There's a whole book full of applied psychology packed into those simple lyrics.
You don't need to know the language to say you're in love.
Anyone who's ever been in love knows that.
And you don't need to know any language to say I like you,
or I despise you, or I think you're important, or unimportant, or I envy you.
You don't need to know words or to use words to say,
I like my job, or I'm bored, or I'm hungry.
People speak without a sound.
How we think shows through in how we act.
Attitudes are mirrors of the mind.
They reflect thinking.
You can read the mind of the fellow sitting at a desk.
You sense, by observing his expressions and mannerisms, how he feels toward his job.
You can read the minds of salesmen, students, husbands, and wives.
You not only can, you do.
The expert actors, those in demand in movies and television year after year,
in a sense are not actors at all.
They don't play their roles.
Instead, they lose their own identity and actually think and feel like the character they are playing.
They've got to.
Else they'd look like phonies and their ratings would plunge.
Attitudes do more than show through.
They sound through, too.
A secretary does more than identify an office when she says, good morning, Mr. Shoemaker's office.
In just five words, one secretary says, I like you.
I'm glad you're calling.
I think you are important.
I like my job.
But another secretary saying exactly the same words tells you, you bothered me.
I wish you hadn't called.
I'm bored with my job and I don't like people who bother me.
We read attitudes through expressions and voice tones and inflections.