He'll drink a couple of extra cups of coffee, maybe cruise around the neighborhood a while,
or do a dozen little things to postpone that first call.
I train each new man this way.
I explain to him that the only way to start is to start.
Don't deliberate.
Don't postpone getting started.
Do this.
Just park your car, get your sample case, walk to the door, ring the bell,
smile, say good morning, and make your presentation, all mechanically, without a lot of conscious thought.
Start making calls this way and you break the ice.
By the second or third call, your mind is sharp and your presentations become effective.
A humorist once said the most difficult problem in life was getting out of a warm bed into a cold room,
and he had a point.
The longer you lie there and think how unpleasant it will be to get up, the more difficult it becomes.
Even in such a simple operation as this, mechanical action, just throwing off the covers and putting your feet on the floor,
defeats dread.
The point is clear.
People who get things done in this world don't wait for the spirit to move them.
They move the spirit.
Try these two exercises.
1.
Use the mechanical way to accomplish simple but sometimes unpleasant business and household chores.
Rather than think about the unpleasant features of the task, jump right in and get going without a lot of deliberation.
Perhaps the most unpleasant household task to most women is washing dishes.
My mother is no exception.
But she has mastered a mechanical approach to dispensing with this task quickly,
so she can return to things she likes to do.
As she leaves the table, she always mechanically picks up several dishes, and without thinking about the task ahead,
just gets started.
In just a few minutes, she is through.
Doesn't this beat stacking dishes and dreading the unpleasant inevitable?
Do this today.
Pick the one thing you like to do least.
Then, without letting yourself deliberate on or dread the task, do it.
That's the most efficient way to handle chores.
Next, use the mechanical way to create ideas, map out plans, solve problems,