and the third was a brother-in-law.
Next, again, I don't know what made me do this.
I asked myself, what do my five friends have that I don't have, besides better jobs?
I compared myself with them on intelligence, but I honestly couldn't see that they excelled in the brains department,
nor could I truthfully say they had me beat on education, integrity, or personal habits.
Finally, I got down to another success quality one hears a lot about, initiative.
Here I hated to admit it, but I had to.
On this point, my record showed I was far below that of my successful friends.
It was now about three a.m., but my mind was astonishingly clear.
I was seeing my weak point for the first time.
I discovered that I had held back.
I had always carried a little stick.
I dug into myself deeper and deeper, and found the reason I lacked initiative was because I didn't believe inside that I was worth very much.
I sat there the rest of the night, just reviewing how lack of faith in myself had dominated me ever since I could remember.
How I had used my mind to work against myself.
I found I had been preaching to myself why I couldn't get ahead instead of why I could.
I had been selling myself short.
I found this streak of self-depreciation showed through in everything I did.
Then it dawned on me that no one else was going to believe in me until I believed in myself.
Right then I decided, I'm through feeling second class.
From here on in, I'm not going to sell myself short.
Next morning, I still had that confidence.
During the job interview, I gave my newfound confidence its first test.
Before coming for the interview, I'd hoped I would have the courage to ask for $750 or maybe even $1,000 more than my present job was paying.
But now, after realizing I was a valuable man, I upped it to $3,500.
And I got it.
I sold myself because, after that one long night of self-analysis, I found things in myself that made me a lot more saleable.
Within two years after I took that job, I had established a reputation as the fellow who can get business.
Then we went into a recession.
This made me still more valuable because I was one of the best business getters in the industry.
The company was reorganized and I was given a substantial amount of stock plus a lot more pay.
Believe in yourself and good things do start happening.