Because you got up at 5.30 a.m. to deliver papers or milk the cows when you were a youngster doesn't necessarily mean it's a good idea for you to require your children to do the same.
Imagine what would happen to the Ford Motor Company if its management allowed itself to think,
this year we've built the ultimate in automobiles.
Further improvement is impossible.
Therefore, all experimental engineering and designing activities are hereby permanently terminated.
Even the mammoth Ford Motor Company would shrivel fast with this attitude.
Successful people, like successful businesses, live with these questions.
How can I improve the quality of my performance?
How can I do better?
Absolute perfection in all human undertakings, from building missiles to rearing children, is unattainable.
This means there is endless room for improvement.
Successful people know this, and they are always searching for a better way.
Note, the successful person doesn't ask, can I do it better?
He knows he can.
So he phrases the question, how can I do it better?