6.
Five years is too long a time to spend before I'll get into the top ranks in your company.
Count me out.
Or, 5 years is not really a long time.
Just think, that leaves me 30 years to serve at a high level.
7.
The competition has all the advantage.
How do you expect me to sell against them?
Or, Competition is strong, there's no denying that, but no one ever has all the advantages.
Let's put our heads together and figure out a way to beat them at their own game.
8.
Nobody will ever want that product.
Or, in its present form, it may not be saleable, but let's consider some modifications.
9.
Let's wait until a recession comes along, then buy stocks.
Or, let's invest now.
Bet on prosperity, not depression.
10.
I'm too young-old for the job.
Or, being young-old is a distinct advantage.
11.
it won't work, let me prove it.
The image, dark, gloom, disappointment, grief, failure.
Or, it will work, let me prove it.
The image, bright, hope, success, fun, victory.