Just a few weeks ago, a friend who is an official with a state highway department in a Midwestern state related a mountain-moving experience to me.
Last month, my friend began, our department sent notices to a number of engineering companies that we were authorized to retain some firm to design eight bridges as part of our highway building program.
The bridges were to be built at a cost of five million dollars.
The engineering firm selected would get a four percent commission or two hundred thousand dollars for its design work.
I talked with twenty-one engineering firms about this.
The four largest decided right away to submit proposals.
The other seventeen companies were small, having only three to seven engineers each.
The size of the project scared off sixteen of these seventeen.
They went over the project, shook their heads, and said, in effect, it's too big for us.
I wish I thought we could handle it, but it's no use even trying.
But one of these small firms, a company with only three engineers, studied the plans and said,
we can do it, we'll submit a proposal.
They did, and they got the job.
Those who believe they can move mountains, do.
Those who believe they can't, cannot.
Belief triggers the power to do.