Third group, those who never surrender.
This group, maybe two or three percent of the total, doesn't let pessimism dictate,
doesn't believe in surrendering to suppressive forces, doesn't believe in crawling.
Instead, these people live and breathe success.
This group is the happiest because it accomplishes the most.
These people become top salesmen, top executives, top leaders in their respective fields.
These people find life stimulating, rewarding, worthwhile.
These people look forward to each new day, each new encounter with other people, as adventures to be lived fully.
Let's be honest.
All of us would like to be in the third group, the one that finds greater success each year,
the one that does things and gets results.
To get and stay in this group, however, we must fight off the suppressive influences of our environment.
To understand how persons in the first and second groups will unwittingly try to hold you back, study this example.
Suppose you tell several of your average friends with the greatest sincerity, someday I'm going to be vice president of this company.
What will happen?
Your friends will probably think you were joking, and if they should believe you mean it,
chances are they will say, you poor guy, you sure have a lot to learn.
Behind your back, they may even question whether you have all your marbles.
Now, assume you repeat the same statement with equal sincerity to the president of your company.
How will he react?
One thing is certain, he will not laugh.
He will look at you intently and ask himself, does this fellow really mean this?
But he will not, we repeat, laugh.
Because big men do not laugh at big ideas.
Or suppose you tell some average people you plan to own an expensive home,
and they may laugh at you because they think it's impossible.
But tell your plan to a person already living in an expensive home, and he won't be surprised.
He knows it isn't impossible because he's already done it.
Remember, people who tell you it cannot be done almost always are unsuccessful people,
are strictly average or mediocre at best in terms of accomplishment.