Several months ago, a very troubled executive in his early forties came to see me.
He had a responsible job as a buyer for a large retailing organization.
Worriedly, he explained, I am afraid of losing my job.
I've got that feeling that my days are numbered.
Why?
I asked.
Well, the pattern is against me.
Sales figures in my department are off 7% from a year ago.
This is pretty bad, especially since the store's total sales are up 6%.
I've made a couple of unwise decisions recently, and I've been singled out several times by the merchandise manager for not keeping pace with the company's progress.
I've never felt quite like this before," he continued.
I've lost my grip, and it shows.
My assistant buyer senses it.
The salespeople see it, too.
Other executives, of course, are aware that I'm slipping.
One buyer even suggested at a meeting of all head buyers the other day that part of my line should be put in his department,
where, he said, it could make money for the store.
It's like drowning and having a crowd of spectators just standing there waiting for me to sink away.
The executive talked on, elaborating further on his predicament.
Finally, I cut in and asked, what are you doing about it?
What are you trying to do to correct the situation?
Well, he answered, there isn't much I can do, I guess, but hope for the best.
To this comment, I asked, honestly now, is hope enough?
Pausing, but not giving him a chance to answer, I put another question to him.
Why not take action to support your hope?