It holds true not only on the golf course, but in every facet of life.
Four things you can do to lick health excusitis.
The best vaccine against health excusitis consists of these four doses.
1.
Refuse to talk about your health.
The more you talk about an ailment, even the common cold, the worse it seems to get.
Talking about bad health is like putting fertilizer on weeds.
Besides, talking about your health is a bad habit.
It bores people.
It makes one appear self-centered and old maidish.
Success-minded people defeat the natural tendency to talk about their bad health.
One may, and let me emphasize the word may, get a little sympathy,
but one doesn't get respect and loyalty by being a chronic complainer.
2.
Refuse to worry about your health.
Dr. Walter Alvarez, emeritus consultant to the world-famous Mayo Clinic, wrote recently,
I always beg worriers to exercise some self-control.
For instance, when I saw this man, a fellow who was convinced he had a diseased gallbladder,
although eight separate x-ray examinations showed that the organ was perfectly normal,
I begged him to quit getting his gallbladder x-rayed.
I have begged hundreds of heart-conscious men to quit getting electrocardiograms made.
3.
Be genuinely grateful that your health is as good as it is.
There's an old saying worth repeating often.
I felt sorry for myself because I had ragged shoes until I met a man who had no feet.
Instead of complaining about not feeling good, it's far better to be glad you are as healthy as you are.
Just being grateful for the health you have is powerful vaccination against developing new aches and pains and real illness.
4.
Remind yourself often, it's better to wear out than rust out.
Life is yours to enjoy.
Don't waste it.
Don't pass up living by thinking yourself into a hospital bed.