Tom's goal does not pilot him in vague generalities.
It gives him specific directions in all his activities.
When Tom buys a suit, the goal speaks and shows Tom the wise choice.
The goal helps to show Tom what steps to take to move up to the next job,
what to say in the business conference, what to do when conflict develops,
what to read, what stand to take.
Should Tom drift a little off course, his automatic instrumentation, housed securely in his subconscious mind,
alerts him and tells him what to do to get back on course.
Tom's goal has made him super sensitive to all the many forces at work that affect him.
Jack, on the other hand, lacking a goal, also lacks the automatic instrumentation to guide him.
He is easily confused.
His actions reflect no personal policy.
Jack wavers, shifts, guesses at what to do.
Lacking consistency of purpose, Jack flounders on the ruddy road to mediocrity.
May I suggest you listen to this section again right now.
Let this concept soak in.
Then, look around you.
Study the very top echelon of successful persons.
Note how they, without exception, are totally devoted to their objective.
Observe how the life of a highly successful person is integrated around a purpose.
Surrender to that goal.
Really surrender.
Let it obsess you and give you the automatic instrumentation you need to reach that goal.
On occasion, all of us have waked up on Saturday morning with no plans,
no agenda, either mental or written, that spells out what we're going to do.
On days like that, we accomplish next to nothing.