Pat them on the back for the job they're doing.
Give them hope.
Let them know you believe they can succeed, that you have faith in them.
Practice relieving worriers.
Make this little test regularly to keep you on the right track.
Whenever you leave a person, ask yourself, does that person honestly feel better because he has talked with me?
This self-training device works.
Apply it when talking with employees, associates, your family, customers, even with casual acquaintances.
A salesman friend is a real good news broadcaster.
He calls on his customers every month and always makes it a rule to have some good news to pass along.
Examples I met one of your good friends last week.
He said to tell you hello.
Since I was here last, big things have happened.
Over 350,000 new babies were born last month, and more babies means more business for both of us.
Usually, we think of bank presidents as overly reserved, unemotional people who never really warm up.
Not so with one bank president.
His favorite way to answer the phone is to say, Good morning, it's a wonderful world.
May I sell you some money?
Improper for a banker?
Some might say so.
But let me point out that the banker who uses this greeting is Mills Lane,
Jr., president of the Citizens and Southern Bank, the largest in the entire Southeast.
Good news gets good results.
Broadcast it.
The president of a brush manufacturing company I visited recently had this maxim neatly framed on his desk facing the visitor's chair.
Give me a good word or none at all.
I complimented him, saying that I thought the maxim was a clever way to encourage people to be optimistic.
He smiled and said, it is an effective reminder, but from where I sit, this is even more important.
He turned the frame around so I could see it from his side of the desk.
It said, give them a good word or none at all.
Broadcasting good news activates you, makes you feel better.
Broadcasting good news makes other people feel better too.