As part of a professional development program, I asked 13 trainees to closet themselves for one hour each day for two weeks.
The trainees were asked to shut themselves off from all distractions and think constructively about anything that came to mind.
At the end of two weeks, each trainee, without exception, reported the experience proved amazingly practical and worthwhile.
One fellow stated that before the managed solitude experiment, he was on the verge of a sharp break with another company executive.
But through clear thinking, he found the source of the problem and the way to correct it.
Others reported that they solved problems relating to such varied things as changing jobs,
marriage difficulties, buying a home, and selecting a college for a teenage child.
Each trainee enthusiastically reported that he had gained a much better understanding of himself,
his strengths and weaknesses, than he had ever had before.
The trainees also discovered something else that is tremendously significant.
They discovered that decisions and observations made alone in managed solitude have an uncanny way of being 100% right.
The trainees discovered that when the fog is lifted, the right choice becomes crystal clear.
Managed Solitude Pays Off One day recently, an associate of mine reversed her stand completely on a troublesome issue.
I was curious to know why she had switched her thinking, since the problem was very basic.
Her answer went like this.
Well, I haven't been at all clear in my mind as to what we should do.
So I got up at 3.30 this morning, fixed a cup of coffee,
and just sat on the sofa and thought until 7 a.m. I see the whole matter a lot clearer now,
so the only thing for me to do is reverse my stand.
And her new stand proved completely correct.
Resolve now to set aside some time each day, at least 30 minutes, to be completely by yourself.
Perhaps early in the morning before anyone else is stirring about would be best for you.
Or perhaps late in the evening would be a better time.
The important thing is to select a time when your mind is fresh and when you can be free from distractions.
You can use this time to do two types of thinking, directed and undirected.
To do directed thinking, review the major problem facing you.
In solitude, your mind will study the problem objectively and lead you to the right answer.
To do undirected thinking, just let your mind select what it wishes to think about.
In moments like these, your subconscious mind taps your memory bank, which in turn feeds your conscious mind.
Undirected thinking is very helpful in doing self-evaluation.
It helps you get down to the very basic matters, like, how can I do better?
What should be my next move?
Remember, the main job of the leader is thinking, and the best preparation for leadership is thinking.
Spend some time in managed solitude every day and think yourself to success.