Start your mental engine mechanically.
An aspiring young writer who wasn't experiencing success made this confession.
My trouble is, whole days and weeks pass that I can't get a thing written.
You see, he remarked, writing is creative.
You've got to be inspired.
Your spirit must move you.
True, writing is creative, but here's how another creative man, also a writer,
explained his secret for producing quantities of successful material.
I use a mind-force technique," he began.
I've got deadlines to meet, and I can't wait for my spirit to move me.
I've got to move my spirit.
Here's how my method works.
I make myself sit down at my desk.
Then I pick up a pencil and go through mechanical motions of writing.
I put down anything.
I doodle.
I get my fingers and arm in motion, and sooner or later, without my being conscious of it,
my mind gets on the right track.
Sometimes, of course, I get ideas out of the blue when I'm not trying to write,
" he went on, but these are just bonuses.
Most of the good ideas come from just getting to work.
Action must precede action.
That's a law of nature.
Nothing starts itself, not even the dozens of mechanical gadgets we use daily.
Your home is heated automatically, but you must select, take action, the temperature you want.
Your car shifts gears automatically only after you have set the right lever.
The same principle applies to mind action.
You get your mind in gear to make it produce for you.
A young branch sales manager for a door-to-door sales organization explained how he trained his sales force the mechanical way to start each day earlier and more successfully.
There's a tremendous resistance to the door-to-door salesman, as anyone who has ever sold house-to-house knows,
he commented, and it's hard, even for the veteran salesman, to make that first call in the morning.
He knows the odds are pretty good that he'll get some pretty rough treatment before the day is over.
So it's natural for him to put off getting started in the morning.
He'll drink a couple of extra cups of coffee, maybe cruise around the neighborhood a while,