Your mind is a thought factory.
It's a busy factory producing countless thoughts in one day.
Production in your thought factory is under the charge of two foremen, one of whom we will call Mr. Triumph and the other Mr. Defeat.
Mr. Triumph is in charge of manufacturing positive thoughts.
He specializes in producing reasons why you can, why you're qualified, why you will.
The other foreman, Mr. Defeat, produces negative, deprecating thoughts.
He is your expert in developing reasons why you can't, why you're weak, why you're inadequate.
His specialty is the why-you-will-fail chain of thoughts.
Both Mr. Triumph and Mr. Defeat are intensely obedient.
They snap to attention immediately.
All you need do to signal either foreman is to give the slightest mental beck and call.
If the signal is positive, Mr. Triumph will step forward and go to work.
Likewise, a negative signal brings Mr. Defeat forward.
To see how these two foremen work for you, try this example.
Tell yourself, Today is a lousy day.
This signals Mr. Defeat into action, and he manufactures some facts to prove you are right.
He suggests to you that it's too hot or it's too cold.
Business will be bad today.
Sales will drop.
Other people will be on edge.
You may get sick.
Your wife will be in a fussy mood.
Mr. Defeat is tremendously efficient.
In just a few moments he's got you sold.
It is a bad day.
Before you know it, it is a heck of a bad day.
But tell yourself, today is a fine day, and Mr. Triumph is signaled forward to act.
He tells you, this is a wonderful day, the weather is refreshing, it's good to be alive,
today you can catch up on some of your work, and then it is a good day.
In like fashion, Mr. Defeat can show you why you can't sell Mr. Smith.
Mr. Triumph will show you that you can.
Mr. Defeat will convince you that you will fail, while Mr. Triumph will demonstrate why you will succeed.
Mr. Defeat will prepare a brilliant case against Tom, while Mr. Triumph will show you more reasons why you like Tom.
Now, the more work you give either of these two foremen, the stronger he becomes.
If Mr. Defeat is given more work to do, he adds personnel and takes up more space in your mind.
Eventually, he will take over the entire thought-manufacturing division and virtually all thought will be of a negative nature.
The only wise thing to do is fire Mr. Defeat.
You don't need him.
You don't want him around telling you that you can't, you're not up to it,
you'll fail, and so on.
Mr. Defeat won't help you get where you want to go, so boot him out.
Use Mr. Triumph 100% of the time.
When any thought enters your mind, ask Mr. Triumph to go to work for you.
He'll show you how you can succeed.