Our combined carpentry talent equaled zero, and the end product clearly reflected that fact.
Shortly afterward a good friend stopped by, and upon seeing what we had done,
asked, What's that you've stuck up there among the trees?
That's not a doghouse, is it?
I replied that it was.
Then he pointed out just a few of our mistakes and summed it all up with,
Why didn't you get a plan?
Nobody these days builds a doghouse without a blueprint.
And please, as you visualize your future, don't be afraid to be blue sky.
People these days are measured by the size of their dreams.
No one accomplishes more than he sets out to accomplish.
So, visualize a big future.
Here is a word-for-word excerpt from the life plan of one of my former trainees.
Listen to it.
Note how well this fellow visualized his home future.
As he wrote this, it is obvious he really saw himself in the future.
My home goal is to own a country estate.
The house will be of the typical southern manor type, two stories, white columns and all.
We will have the grounds fenced in, and probably will have a fish pond or two on the place,
as my wife and I both enjoy fishing.
We will keep our Doberman kennels back of the house somewhere.
The thing I have always wanted is a long winding driveway with trees lining each side.
But a house is not necessarily a home.
I am going to do everything I can to make our house more than just a place to eat and sleep.
Of course we do not intend to leave God out of our plans,
and throughout the years we will spend a certain amount of time in church activities.
Ten years from now, I want to be in a position to take a family cruise around the world.
I would like very much to do this before the family gets scattered all over the world by marriages,
etc. If we can't find the time to make the cruise all at once,
we will put it into four or five separate vacations and visit a different part of the world each year.
Naturally, all these plans in Home Department depend on how well things go in my Work Department,
so I'll have to keep on the ball if I'm to accomplish all this.
This plan was written five years ago.
The trainee then owned two small dime stores.
Now he owns five, and he has purchased seventeen acres for his country estate.