My three disillusioned friends should have realized that top executives don't select major executives by drawing names from a hat.
I was talking about the seriousness of luck excusitis not long ago with a sales executive of a machine tool manufacturing company.
He became excited about the problem and began to talk about his own experience with it.
I've never heard it called that before," he said, but it is one of the most difficult problems every sales executive has to wrestle with.
Just yesterday, a perfect example of what you're talking about happened in my company.
One of the salesmen walked in about four o'clock with a $112,000 order for machine tools.
Another salesman, whose volume is so low he's a problem, was in the office at the time.
Hearing John tell the good news, he rather enviously congratulated him and then said, Well, John, you're lucky again.
Now, what the weak salesman won't accept is that luck had nothing to do with John's big order.
John had been working on that customer for months.
He had talked repeatedly to a half dozen people out there.
John had stayed up nights figuring out exactly what was best for them.
Then he got our engineers to make preliminary designs of the equipment.
John wasn't lucky, unless you can call carefully planned work and patiently executed plans luck.
Suppose luck were used to reorganize General Motors.
If luck determined who does what and who goes where, every business in the nation would fall apart.
Assume for a moment that General Motors were to be completely reorganized on the basis of luck.
To carry out the reorganization, the names of all employees would be placed in a barrel.
The first name drawn would be the President, the second name the Executive Vice President,
and so on down the line.
Sounds stupid, doesn't it?
Well, that's how luck would work.
People who rise to the top in any occupation, business management, selling, law,
engineering, acting, or what have you, get there because they have superior attitudes and use their good sense in applied hard work.