He's developed a hard format for his stories.
He has never experimented with his material, his plots and characters, and perhaps even style.
But what I'm trying to do now is to get this client to try some new approaches and some new techniques.
He has ability, and if he'll do some experimenting, I'm sure he'll sell much of what he writes.
But until he does, he'll just go on receiving one rejection slip after another.
The advice of the literary consultant is good.
We must have persistence.
But persistence is only one of the ingredients of victory.
We can try and try and try and try and try again and still fail unless we combine persistence with experimentation.
Edison is credited with being one of America's most persistent scientists.
It's reported that he conducted thousands of experiments before he invented the electric light bulb.
But note, Edison conducted experiments.
He persisted in his goal to develop a light bulb.
but he made that persistence pay off by blending it with experimentation.
Persisting in one way is not a guarantee of victory, but persistence blended with experimentation does guarantee success.
Recently, I noticed an article about the continuous search for oil.
It said that oil companies study the rock formations carefully before they drill a well.
Yet, despite their scientific analysis, seven out of eight wells drilled turn out to be dry holes.
Oil companies are persistent in their search for oil, not by digging one hole to ridiculous depths,
but rather by experimenting with a new well when good judgment says the first well won't produce.
Many ambitious people go through life with admirable persistence and show of ambition,
but they fail to succeed because they don't experiment with new approaches.
Stay with your goal, don't waver an inch from it, but don't beat your head against a wall.
If you aren't getting results, try a new approach.