In one of my first jobs, I worked closely with another young fellow,
whom I'll call F.H. F.H. was like many persons you know.
He was preoccupied with why he needed more money instead of being preoccupied with ways to make money.
Each week, F.H. spent hours of company time working on his personal budget problems.
His favorite topic of conversation was, I'm the most underpaid man here, let me tell you why.
F.H. had the not uncommon attitude of, this is a big company,
it's netting millions, it's paying a lot of people big salaries,
so it ought to pay me more, too.
F.H. had been passed over several times for pay increases.
Finally, one day he decided that it was high time he went in there and demanded more money.
About thirty minutes later, F.H. was back, all heated up.
His expression made it obvious that next month's check would look exactly like this month's check.
Immediately, F.H. began to let go.
Boy, am I mad.
What do you suppose the old man said when I told him I wanted more money?
He had the gall to ask me, Why do you believe you are justified in asking for an increase?
I gave him plenty of reasons, F.H. went on.
I told him I'd been passed over when others around here were getting pay raises.
I told him my bills are getting larger and my paycheck isn't.
And I told him that I do everything around here they ask me to do.
Can you beat that?
I need a raise, but instead of paying me more, they give out raises to other guys around here who don't need it half as much as I do.
Why, the way he acted, F.H. continued, you'd think I was asking for charity.
All he would say is, when your record shows that you deserve more money, you'll get more money.
Sure, I could do a better job if they paid me for it,
but only a fool does something he isn't paid for.
F.H. is an example of the breed that is blind to the how of making money.
His last remark sums up his mistake.
In effect, FH wanted the company to pay him more and then he would produce more.
But this is not how the system works.
You don't get a raise on the promise of better performance.
You get a raise only by demonstrating better performance.
You can't harvest money unless you plant the seeds that grow money.
And the seed of money is service.
Put service first and money takes care of itself.