And it didn't take a brilliant man or a wealthy man or a lucky man.
All, and I hesitate to use the word all because all means so much sometimes,
all it took was a persistent man who never thought he was defeated.
Behind this prosperous and respected company is the story of a man fighting,
battling his way upward, losing ten years' savings in his first six months in business,
living in his office several months because he lacked money to pay rent on an apartment,
turning down numerous good jobs because he wanted more to stay with his idea and make it work,
hearing prospects for his service say no a hundred times as often as they said yes,
During the seven unbelievably hard years it took him to succeed, I never heard my friend complain once.
He'd explain, Dave, I'm learning.
This is competitive business, and because it's intangible, it's hard to sell.
But I'm learning how.
And he did.
Once I told my friend that this experience must be taking a lot out of him,
but he replied, no, it's not taking something out of me, it's putting something into me instead.
Check the lives of the people in Who's Who in America, and you'll find that those who have succeeded in a major way have been pounded by losing situations.
Each person in this elite corps of successful men has encountered opposition, discouragement, setbacks, personal misfortune.
Read the biographies and autobiographies of great people, and again you discover that each of these people could have surrendered to setbacks many times.
Or do this.
Learn the background of the president of your company or the mayor of your city,
or select any person you consider a real success.
When you probe, you'll discover the individual has overcome big, real obstacles.
It is not possible to win high-level success without meeting opposition, hardship, and setback.
But it is possible to use setbacks to propel you forward.
Let's see how.
I saw some commercial airline statistics recently showing that there is only one fatality per 10 billion miles flown.
Air travel is a magnificently safe way to go these days.
Unfortunately, air accidents still occur.
But when they do, the Civil Aviation Administration is on the scene quickly to find out what caused the crash.
Fragments of metal are picked up from miles around and pieced together.
A variety of experts reconstruct what probably happened.
Witnesses and survivors are interviewed.
The investigation goes on for weeks, months, until the question, what caused this crash, is answered.
Once the CAA has the answer, immediate steps are taken to prevent a similar accident from happening again.
If the crash was caused by a structural defect, other planes of that type must have that defect corrected.
Or if certain instruments are found faulty, corrections must be made.
Literally hundreds of safety devices on modern aircraft have resulted from CAA investigations.
The CAA studies setbacks to pave the way to safer air travel, and it's obvious that their efforts pay off.