Look important.
It helps you think important.
Rule.
Remember, your appearance talks.
Be sure it says positive things about you.
Never leave home without feeling certain you look like the kind of person you want to be.
The most honest advertisement ever appearing in print is the Dress Right, You Can't Afford Not To slogan,
sponsored by the American Institute of Men's and Boyswear.
This slogan deserves to be framed in every office, restroom, bedroom, and schoolroom in America.
In one ad, a policeman speaks.
He says, you can usually spot a wrong kid just by the way he looks.
Sure, it's unfair, but it's a fact.
People today judge a youngster by appearance.
And once they've tabbed a boy, it's tough to change their minds about him, their attitude toward him.
Look at your boy.
Look at him through his teacher's eyes, your neighbor's eyes.
Could the way he looks, the clothes he wears, give them the wrong impression?
Are you making sure he looks right, dresses right, everywhere he goes?
This advertisement, of course, refers primarily to children, but it can be applied to adults as well.
In the sentence beginning with look, substitute the word yourself for him, your for his,
superiors for teachers, and associates for neighbors, and repeat the sentence.
Look at yourself through your superior's eyes, your associate's eyes.
It costs so little to be neat.
Take the slogan literally.
Interpret it to say, dress right, it always pays.
Remember, look important because it helps you to think important.
Use clothing as a tool to lift your spirits, build confidence.
An old psychology professor of mine used to give this advice to students on last-minute preparations for final examinations.
Dress up for this important exam.
Get a new tie.
Have your suit pressed.
Shine your shoes.
Look sharp because it will help you think sharp.
The professor knew his psychology.
Make no mistake about it.
Your physical exterior affects your mental interior.
How you look on the outside affects how you think and feel on the inside.
All boys, I'm told, go through the hat stage.
That is, they use hats to identify themselves with the person or character they want to be.
I will always remember a hat incident with my own son, Davey.
One day, he was dead set on being the Lone Ranger, but he had no Lone Ranger hat.
I tried to persuade him to substitute another.
His protest was, but Dad, I can't think like the Lone Ranger without a Lone Ranger hat.
I gave in finally and bought him the hat he needed.
Sure enough, donning the hat, he was the Lone Ranger.
I often recall that incident because it says so much about the effect of appearance on thinking.
Anyone who has ever served in the army knows a soldier feels and thinks like a soldier when he is in uniform.
A woman feels more like going to a party when she is dressed for a party.
By the same token, an executive feels more like an executive when he is dressed like one.
A salesman expressed it to me this way.
I can't feel prosperous, and I have to if I am going to make big sales,
unless I know I look that way.
Your appearance talks to you, but it also talks to others.
It helps determine what others think of you.
In theory, it's pleasant to hear that people should look at a man's intellect, not his clothes.
But don't be misled.
People do evaluate you on the basis of your appearance.
Your appearance is the first basis for evaluation other people have, and first impressions last,
out of all proportion to the time it takes to form them.
In a supermarket one day, I noticed one table of seedless grapes marked 15 cents a pound.
On another table were what appeared to be identical grapes, this time packaged in polyethylene bags and marked 2 pounds for 35 cents.
I asked the young fellow at the weighing station, what's the difference between the grapes priced at 15 cents a pound and those priced at 2 pounds for 35 cents?
The difference, he answered, is polyethylene.
We sell about twice as many of the grapes in the polyethylene bags.
They look better that way.