Believing they will succeed, and that it's not impossible, these folks study and observe the behavior of senior executives.
They learn how successful people approach problems and make decisions.
They observe the attitudes of successful people.
The how-to-do-it always comes to the person who believes he can do it.
A young woman I am acquainted with decided two years ago that she was going to establish a sales agency to sell mobile homes.
She was advised by many that she shouldn't and couldn't do it.
She had less than three thousand dollars in savings and was advised that the minimum capital investment required was many times that.
Look how competitive it is," she was advised.
And besides, what practical experience have you had in selling mobile homes, let alone managing a business?" her advisors asked.
But this young lady had belief in herself and her ability to succeed.
She quickly admitted that she lacked capital, that the business was very competitive, and that she lacked experience.
But, she said, all the evidence I can gather shows that the mobile home industry is going to expand.
On top of that, I've studied my competition.
I know I can do a better job of merchandising trailers than anybody else in this town.
I expect to make some mistakes, but I'm going to be on top in a hurry.
And she was.
She had little trouble getting capital.
Her absolutely unquestioned belief that she could succeed with this business won her the confidence of two investors.
And armed with complete belief, she did the impossible.
She got a trailer manufacturer to advance her a limited inventory with no money down.
Last year, she sold over one million dollars worth of trailers.
Next year, she says, I expect to gross over $2 million.
Belief, strong belief, triggers the mind to figure ways and means and how to.
And believing you can succeed makes others place confidence in you.
Most people do not put much stock in belief, but some, the residents of Successfulville, U.S.A., do.