Summary To be a more effective leader, put these four leadership principles to work.
1.
Trade minds with the people you want to influence.
It's easy to get others to do what you want them to do if you'll see things through their eyes.
Ask yourself this question before you act.
What would I think of this if I exchanged places with the other person?
Two, apply the Be Human rule in your dealings with others.
Ask, what is the human way to handle this?
In everything you do, show that you put other people first.
Just give other people the kind of treatment you like to receive.
You'll be rewarded.
Three, think progress, believe in progress, push for progress.
Think improvement in everything you do.
Think high standards in everything you do.
Over a period of time, subordinates tend to become carbon copies of their chief.
Be sure the master copy is worth duplicating.
Make this a personal resolution.
At home, at work, in community life, if it's progress, I'm for it.
4.
Take time out to confer with yourself and tap your supreme thinking power.
Managed solitude pays off.
Use it to release your creative power.
Use it to find solutions to personal and business problems.
So, spend some time alone every day just for thinking.
Use the thinking technique all great leaders use.
Confer with yourself.
How to Use the Magic of Thinking Big in Life's Most Crucial Situations There is magic in thinking big,
but it is so easy to forget.
When you hit some rough spots, there is danger that your thinking will shrink in size,
and when it does, you lose.
Here are some brief guides for staying big when you're tempted to use the small approach.
Perhaps you'll want to put these guides on small cards for even handier reference.
A.
When little people try to drive you down, think big.
To be sure, there are some people who want you to lose, to experience misfortune, to be reprimanded.
But these people can't hurt you if you'll remember three things.
One, you win when you refuse to fight petty people.
Fighting little people reduces you to their size.
Stay big.
Two, expect to be sniped at.
It's proof you're growing.
Three, remind yourself that snipers are psychologically sick.
Be big.
Feel sorry for them.
Think big enough to be immune to the attacks of petty people.
B, when that I haven't got what it takes feeling creeps up on you, think big.
Remember, if you think you are weak, you are.
If you think you're inadequate, you are.
If you think you're second class, you are.
Whip that natural tendency to sell yourself short with these tools.
1.
Look important.
It helps you think important.
How you look on the outside has a lot to do with how you feel on the inside.
2.
Concentrate on your assets.
Build a sell-yourself-to-yourself commercial and use it.
Learn to supercharge yourself.
Know your positive self.
3.
Put other people in proper perspective.
The other person is just another human being, so why be afraid of him?
Think big enough to see how good you really are.
C. When an argument or quarrel seems inevitable, think big.