Why Joan Failed in Retailing Joan is an intelligent, well-educated, attractive girl of 24.
Fresh from college, Joan got a job as an assistant buyer in ready-to-wear goods at a low-to-medium-priced department store.
She came highly recommended.
Joan has ambition, talent, and enthusiasm, one letter read.
She is certain to succeed in a big way.
But Joan did not succeed in a big way.
Joan lasted only eight months, and then quit retailing for other work.
I knew her buyer well, and one day I asked him what happened.
Joan is a fine girl, and she has many fine qualities, he said.
But she had one major limitation.
What was that, I asked.
Well, Joan was forever buying merchandise that she liked, but most of our customers didn't.
She selected styles, colors, materials, and prices she liked without putting herself in the shoes of the people who shop here.
When I'd suggest to her that maybe a certain line wasn't right for us,
she'd say, oh, they'll love this.
I do.
I think this will move fast.
Joan had been brought up in a well-to-do home.
She had been educated to want quality.
Price was not important to her.
Joan just couldn't see clothing through the eyes of low- to middle-income people.
So, the merchandise she bought just wasn't suitable.
The point is this.
To get others to do what you want them to do, you must see things through their eyes.
When you trade minds, the secret of how to influence other people effectively shows up.
A very successful salesman friend told me he spends a lot of time anticipating how prospects will react to his presentation before he gives it.
Trading minds with the audience helps the speaker design a more interesting, harder-hitting talk.
Trading minds with employees helps the supervisor provide more effective, better-received instructions.
A young credit executive explained to me how this technique worked for him.
When I was brought into this store, a medium-sized clothing store, as assistant credit manager,
I was assigned the job of handling all collection correspondence.