I learned a big lesson.
There were many other replies.
One fellow reported that he got in trouble with the Bureau of Internal Revenue because he used a bargain accountant.
Another went to a cut-rate doctor and later learned he had received a completely wrong diagnosis.
Others related the costs of going second class in home repairs, hotels, and other goods and services.
Of course, I've heard the argument many times, but I can't afford to go first class.
The simplest answer is, you cannot afford to go any other way.
Certainly, in the long run, going first class actually costs you less than going second class.
Then, too, it's better to have fewer things and have quality than to have many things and have junk.
It's better, for example, to have one really good pair of shoes than to have three pairs of second-class shoes.
People rate you for quality, often subconsciously, perhaps.
Develop an instinct for quality.
It pays, and it costs no more, often costs less, than second-class.
Make your environment make you successful.
1.
Be environment-conscious.
Just as body diet makes the body, mind diet makes the mind.
2.
Make your environment work for you, not against you.
Don't let suppressive forces—the negative, you-can't-do-it people—make you think defeat.
3.
Don't let small-thinking people hold you back.
Jealous people want to see you stumble.
Don't give them that satisfaction.
Four, get your advice from successful people.
Your future is important.
Never risk it with freelance advisors who are living failures.
Five, get plenty of psychological sunshine.
Circulate in new groups.
Discover new and stimulating things to do.
Six, throw thought poison out of your environment.
Avoid gossip.
Talk about people, but stay on the positive side.
7.
Go first class in everything you do.
You can't afford to go any other way.