and do other work that requires top mental performance.
Rather than wait for the spirit to move you, sit down and move your spirit.
Here's a special technique guaranteed to help you.
Use a pencil and paper.
A simple pencil is the greatest concentration tool money can buy.
If I had to choose between an ultra-fancy, deeply carpeted, beautifully decorated soundproof office and a pencil and paper,
I'd choose the pencil and paper every time.
With a pencil and paper, you can tie your mind to a problem.
When you write a thought on paper, your full attention is automatically focused on that thought.
That's because the mind is not designed to think one thought and write another at the same time.
When you write on paper, you write on your mind, too.
Tests prove conclusively that you remember something much longer and much more exactly if you write the thought on paper.
And once you master the pencil and paper technique for concentration, you can think in noisy or other distracting situations.
When you want to think, start writing or doodling or diagramming.