Build your own sell-yourself, to-yourself commercial.
Think for a moment about one of America's most popular products, Coca-Cola.
Every day, your eyes or ears come in contact many times with the good news about Coke.
The people who make Coca-Cola are continually reselling you on Coke, and for a good reason.
If they stopped reselling you, chances are you'd grow lukewarm and eventually cold to Coke.
Then sales would drop.
But the Coca-Cola company isn't going to let this happen.
They resell you and resell you and resell you on Coke.
Every day, you and I see half-alive people who are no longer sold on themselves.
They lack self-respect for their most important product, themselves.
These folks are indifferent.
They feel small.
They feel like nobodies.
And because they feel that way, that's what they are.
The half-alive person needs to be resold on himself.
He needs to realize that he's a first-class person.
He needs honest, sincere belief in himself.
Tom Staley is a young fellow who is going places, and fast.
Tom regularly resells himself on himself three times every day, with what he calls Tom Staley's 60-second commercial.
He carries his personalized commercial in his billfold at all times.
Here is exactly what it says.
Tom Staley, meet Tom Staley, an important, a really important person.
Tom, you're a big thinker, so think big.
Think big about everything.
You've got plenty of ability to do a first-class job, so do a first-class job.
Tom, you believe in happiness, progress, and prosperity.
So, talk only happiness.
Talk only progress.
Talk only prosperity.
You have lots of drive, Tom.
Lots of drive.
So put that drive to work.
Nothing can stop you, Tom.
Nothing.
Tom, you're enthusiastic.
Let your enthusiasm show through.
You look good, Tom, and you feel good.
Stay that way.
Tom Staley, you were a great fellow yesterday, and you're going to be an even greater fellow today.
Now, go to it, Tom.
Go forward.
Tom credits his commercial with helping him become a more successful, dynamic person.
Before I started selling myself to myself, says Tom, I thought I was inferior to just about anybody and everybody.
Now, I realize that I've got what it takes to win, and I'm winning,
and I'm always going to win.
Here's how to build your sell-yourself-to-yourself commercial.
First, select your assets, your points of superiority.
Ask yourself, what are my best qualities?
Don't be shy in describing yourself.
Next, put these points down on paper in your own words.
Write your commercial to you.
Reread Tom Staley's commercial.
Notice how he talks to Tom.
Talk to yourself.
Be very direct.
Don't think of anyone but you as you say your commercial.
Third, practice your commercial out loud in private at least once a day.
It helps a lot to do this before a mirror.
Put your body into it.
Repeat your commercial forcefully with determination.
Make your blood travel faster through your body.
Get yourself warmed up.
Fourth, read your commercial silently several times every day.
Read it before you tackle anything that demands courage.
Read it every time you feel let down.
Keep your commercial handy at all times, then use it.
Just one thing more.