The other fellow does not become too important relative to you in your thinking.
The other fellow might look frightfully big, frightfully important, but remember, he is still a human being with essentially the same interests,
desires, and problems as you.
Two.
Develop an understanding attitude.
People who want figuratively to bite you, growl at you, pick on you,
and otherwise chop you down are not rare.
If you're not prepared for people like that, they can punch big holes in your confidence and make you feel completely defeated.
You need a defense against the adult bully, the fellow who likes to throw his meager weight around.
A few months ago, at the reservations desk of a Memphis hotel, I saw an excellent demonstration of the right way to handle folks like this.
It was shortly after 5 p.m., and the hotel was busy registering new guests.
The fellow ahead of me gave his name to the clerk in a commanding way.
The clerk said, Yes, sir, Mr. R. We have a fine single for you.
Single?
shouted the fellow.
I ordered a double.
The clerk said, very politely, Let me check, sir.
He pulled the guest's reservation from the file and said, I'm sorry, sir, your telegram specified a single.
I'd be happy to put you in a double room, sir, if we had any available,
but we simply do not.
Then the irate customer said, I don't care what the H that piece of paper says,
I want a double.
Then he started in with that, do you know who I am, bit,
followed with, I'll have you fired, you'll see, I'll have you fired.
As best he could, under the verbal tornado, the young clerk injected, Sir,
we're terribly sorry, but we acted on your instructions.
Finally, the customer, really furious now, said, I wouldn't stay in the best suite in this blank-blank hotel now that I know how badly managed it is,
and stormed out.
I stepped up to the desk, thinking the clerk, who had taken one of the worst public tongue lashings I'd seen in some time,
would be upset.
Instead, he greeted me with one of the finest good evening sirs I'd ever heard.
As he went through the routine of processing my room, I said to him,
I certainly admire the way you handled yourself just a moment ago.
You have tremendous temper control.
Well, sir, he said, I really can't get mad at a fellow like that.
You see, he really isn't mad at me.
I was just the scapegoat.
The poor fellow may be in bad trouble with his wife, or his business may be off,
or maybe he feels inferior and this was his golden chance to feel like a wheel.
I'm just the guy who gave him a chance to get something out of his system.
The clerk added, underneath, he's probably a very nice guy.
Most folks are.
Walking toward the elevators, I caught myself repeating aloud, Underneath he's probably a very nice guy.
Remember those two short sentences next time someone declares war on you.
Hold your fire.
The way to win in situations like this is to let the other fellow blow his stack and then forget it.