Put the action principle to work.
Next time you experience big fear or little fear, steady yourself.
Then search for an answer to this question, what kind of action can I take to conquer my fear?
Isolate your fear, then take appropriate action.
Here are some examples of fear and some possible action cures.
Type of fear.
1.
Embarrassment because of personal appearance.
Action.
Improve it.
Go to a barbershop or beauty salon.
Shine your shoes.
Get your clothes cleaned and pressed.
In general, practice better grooming.
It doesn't always take new clothes.
2.
Fear of losing an important customer.
Work doubly hard to give better service.
Correct anything that may have caused customers to lose confidence in you.
3.
Fear of failing an examination.
Convert worry time into study time.
4.
Fear of things totally beyond your control.
Turn your attention to helping to relieve the fear of others.
Pray.
5.
Fear of being physically hurt by something you can't control, such as a tornado or an airplane out of control.
Switch your attention to something totally different.
Go out into your yard and pull up weeds.
Play with your children.
Go to a movie.
6.
Fear of what other people may think and say.
Make sure that what you plan to do is right, then do it.
No one ever does anything worthwhile for which he is not criticized.
7.
Fear of making an investment or purchasing a home.
Analyze all factors, then be decisive.
Make a decision and stick with it.
Trust your own judgment.
8.
Fear of people.
Put them in proper perspective.
Remember, the other person is just another human being pretty much like yourself.
Use this two-step procedure to cure fear and win confidence.
1.
Isolate your fear.
Pin it down.
Determine exactly what you are afraid of.
2.
Then take action.
There is some kind of action for any kind of fear.
And remember, hesitation only enlarges, magnifies the fear.
Take action promptly.
Be decisive.