A lot of people, maybe even a majority, may laugh at this success-rewarding technique.
That's because they refuse to believe that success comes from managed thinking.
But please, don't accept the judgment of average people.
You are not average.
If you have any doubts as to the basic soundness of the sell-yourself-to-yourself principle,
ask the most successful person you know what he thinks about it.
Ask him, and then start selling yourself to yourself.
Upgrade your thinking.
Think like important people think.
Upgrading your thinking upgrades your actions, and this produces success.
Here is an easy way to help you make more of yourself by thinking like important people think.
Use the following form as a guide.
How am I thinking checklist.
Situation, when I worry.
Ask yourself, would an important person worry about this?
Would the most successful person I know be disturbed about this?
Situation, an idea.
Ask yourself, what would an important person do if he had this idea?
Situation, my appearance.
Ask yourself, do I look like someone who has maximum self-respect?
Situation, my language.
Ask yourself, am I using the language of successful people?
Situation, what I read.
Ask yourself, would an important person read this?
Situation, conversation.
Ask yourself, is this something successful people would discuss?
Situation.
When I lose my temper.
Ask yourself, Would an important person get mad at what I'm mad at?
Situation.
My jokes.
Ask yourself, Is this the kind of joke an important person would tell?
Situation.
My job.
Ask yourself, How does an important person describe his job to others?
Cement in your mind the question, Is this the way an important person does it?
Use this question to make you a bigger, more successful person.
In a nutshell, remember 1.
Look important.
It helps you think important.
Your appearance talks to you.
Be sure it lifts your spirits and builds your confidence.
Your appearance talks to others.
Make certain, it says, here is an important person, intelligent, prosperous, and dependable.
2.
Think your work is important.
Think this way, and you will receive mental signals on how to do your job better.
Think your work is important, and your subordinates will think their work is important, too.
3.
Give yourself a pep talk several times daily.
Build a sell-yourself-to-yourself commercial.
Remind yourself at every opportunity that you're a first-class person.
4.
In all of life's situations, ask yourself, is this the way an important person thinks?
Then obey the answer.