Paul, I'm pleased to say, got the point.
He learned the practical value of doing what's right.
I then proposed he sit down and retake the examination.
In answer to his question, but what about my dismissal?
I said, I know what the regulations say about cheating.
But you know, if we dismissed all students who have cheated in any way,
half the professors would have to leave.
And if we dismissed all students who thought about cheating, the university would have to shut down.
So I'm forgetting this whole incident if you'll do me a favor.
Gladly, he said.
I walked over to my bookshelf, took down my personal copy of Fifty Years with the Golden Rule,
and said, Paul, read this book and return it.
See how, in J.C. Penney's own words, just doing what's right made him one of America's richest men.
Doing what's right keeps your conscience satisfied, and this builds self-confidence.
When we do what is known to be wrong, two negative things happen.
First, we feel guilt and this guilt eats away confidence.
Second, other people sooner or later find out and lose confidence in us.
Do what's right and keep your confidence.
That's thinking yourself to success.