A student related this pertinent incident to me, explaining why he'll never again eat in a certain cafeteria.
For lunch one day, the student began, I decided to try a new cafeteria that had just opened a couple of weeks before.
Nickels and dimes are pretty important to me right now, so I watch what I buy pretty closely.
Walking past the meat section, I saw some turkey and dressing that looked pretty good,
and it was plainly marked 39 cents.
When I got to the cash register, the checker looked at my tray and said $1.09.
I politely asked her to check it again because my tally was $0.99.
After giving me a mean glare, she recounted.
The difference turned out to be the turkey.
She had charged me $0.49 instead of $0.39.
Then I called her attention to the sign which read $0.39.
This really set her off.
I don't care what that sign says.
It's supposed to be 49 cents.
See?
Here's my price list for today.
Somebody back there made a mistake.
You'll have to pay the 49 cents.
Then I tried to explain to her the only reason I selected the turkey was because it was 39 cents.
If it had been marked 49 cents, I'd have taken something else.
To this, her answer was, you'll just have to pay the 49 cents.
I did because I didn't want to stand there and create a scene.
But I decided on the spot that I'd never eat there again.
I spend about $250 a year for lunches, and you can be sure they'll not get one penny of it.
There's an example of the little view.
The checker saw one thin dime, not the potential $250.
3.
The Case of the Blind Milkman It's surprising how people sometimes are blind to potential.
A few years ago, a young milkman came to our door to solicit our dairy business.
I explained to him that we already had milk delivery service and we were quite satisfied.
Then I suggested that he stop next door and talk to the lady there.
To this he replied, I've already talked to the lady next door,
but they use only one quart of milk every two days, and that's not enough to make it worthwhile for me to stop.
That may be, I said, but when you talked to our neighbor, did you not observe that the demand for milk in that household will increase considerably in a month or so?
There will be a new addition over there that will consume lots of milk.
The young man looked for a moment like he had been struck, and then he said,
how blind can a guy be?
Today, that same one quart every two days family buys seven quarts every two days from a milkman who had some foresight.
That first youngster, a boy, now has two brothers and one sister, and I'm told there'll be another young one soon.
How blind can we be?
See what can be, not just what is.
The school teacher who thinks of Jimmy only as he is, an ill-mannered,
backward, uncouth brat, certainly will not aid Jimmy's development.
But the teacher who sees Jimmy not as he is now, but as he can be, she'll get results.
Most folks driving through Skid Row see only broken down stumble bums, hopelessly lost to the bottle.
A few devoted people see something else in the Skid Rowite.
They see a reconstructed citizen, and because they see this, they succeed in many cases in doing an excellent rehabilitation job.
4.
What determines how much you're worth?