Do something special for your family often.
It doesn't have to be something expensive.
It's thoughtfulness that counts.
Anything that shows that you put your family's interests first will do the trick.
Get the family on your team.
Give them planned attention.
In this busy age, a lot of people never seem able to find time for their families.
But if we plan, we can find it.
One company vice president told me of this method, which he says works well for him.
My job carries a lot of responsibility, and I have no choice but to bring quite a lot of work home every night.
But I will not neglect my family, because it's the most important thing in my life.
It's the main reason I work as hard as I do.
I've worked out a schedule that enables me to give attention to my family as well as to my work.
From 7.30 to 8.30 every evening, I devote my time to my two young children.
I play games with them, read them stories, draw, answer questions, anything they want me to do.
After an hour with those kids of mine, they're not only satisfied, but I'm 100% fresher.
At 8.30, they trot off to bed, and I settle down to work for two hours.
At 10.30, I quit working and spend the next hour with my wife.
We talk about the kids, her various activities, our plans for the future.
This hour, undisturbed by anything, is a wonderful way to cap off the day.
I also reserve Sundays for my family.
The whole day is theirs.
I find my organized program for giving my family the attention it deserves is good not only for them but also good for me.
It gives me new energy.
Want to make money?