On the bright side, companionship with people with big ideas raises the level of our thinking.
Close contact with ambitious people gives us ambition.
Experts agree that the person you are today, your personality, ambitions, present status in life,
are largely the result of your psychological environment.
And experts agree also that the person you will be 1, 5, 10,
20 years from now, depends almost entirely on your future environment.
You will change over the months and years, this we know.
But how you will change depends on your future environment, the mind food you feed yourself.
Let's look now at what we can do to make our future environment pay off in satisfaction and prosperity.
Recondition yourself for success.
The number one obstacle on the road to high-level success is the feeling that major accomplishment is beyond reach.
This attitude stems from many, many suppressive forces that direct our thinking toward mediocre levels.
To understand these suppressive forces, let's go back to the time we were children.
As children, all of us set high goals.
At a surprisingly young age, we made plans to conquer the unknown, to be leaders,
to attain positions of high importance, to do exciting and stimulating things, to become wealthy and famous.
In short, to be first, biggest, and best.
And in our blessed ignorance, we saw our way clear to accomplish these goals.
But what happened?
Long before we reached the age when we could begin to work toward our great objectives,
a multitude of suppressive influences went to work.
From all sides we heard, it's foolish to be a dreamer, and that our ideas were impractical,
stupid, naive, or foolish, that you have got to have money to go places,
that luck determines who gets ahead, or you've got to have important friends,
or you're too old or too young.
As a result of being bombarded with the you-can't-get-ahead-so-don't-bother-to-try propaganda,
most people you know can be classified into three groups.