Finally, it was agreed.
The builder would, in effect, advance J.M. the $1,200 to be repaid at $100 a month plus interest.
Now all J.M. had to do was to find $100 a month.
Mr. and Mrs. J.M. sharpened their pencils and figured out a way to cut expenditures $25 a month.
But that still left $75, which J.M. would have to raise each month.
Then, J.M. got another idea.
The next morning, he went in to see his boss.
He explained to his employer what he was doing.
His boss was glad to learn that J.M. was going to buy a new home.
Then J.M. said, Look, Mr. T, to work this deal out, I've got to earn at least $75 more each month.
Now I know, J.M. continued, you'll give me a raise when you feel that I deserve it.
What I want now is just a chance to earn more money.
There are some things around here that could best be done on weekends.
Would you make it possible for me to work then?
The employer was impressed with J.M.'s sincerity and ambition.
He proposed a way for J.M. to work ten extra hours each weekend,
and Mr. and Mrs. J.M. moved into their new home.
1.
The resolution to take action ignited JM's mind to think of ways to accomplish his goal.
2.
JM gained tremendously in new confidence.
It will be much easier for him to take action in other major situations.
3.
J.M. provided his wife and child the living standard they deserved.
Had he waited, postponed buying the house until conditions were perfect, there is a real possibility they never would have owned a home of their own.
Case Number 3.
C.D. wanted to start his own business, but...
Mr. C.D. represents another case of what happens to big ideas when one waits until conditions are perfect before taking action on those ideas.