A retired owner-manager of a medium-sized printing company, sixty employees, explained to me how his successor was picked.
Five years ago, my friend began, I needed an accountant to head up our accounting and office routine.
The fellow I hired was named Harry and was only twenty-six.
He knew nothing about the printing business, but his record showed he was a good accountant.
Yet, a year and a half ago, when I retired, we made him president and general manager of the company.
Looking back on it, Harry had one trait that put him out in front of everyone else.
Harry was sincerely and actively interested in the whole company, not just writing checks and keeping records.
Whenever he saw how he could help other employees, he jumped right in.
The first year Harry was with me, we lost a few men.
Harry came to me with a fringe benefit program which he promised would cut down turnover at low cost.
And it worked.
Harry did many other things, too, which helped the whole company, not just this department.
He made a detailed cost study of our production department and showed me how a $30,000 investment in new machinery would pay off.
Once, we experienced a pretty bad sales slump.
Harry went to our sales manager and said, in effect, I don't know much about the sales end of the business,
but let me try to help.
And he did.
Harry came up with several good ideas, which helped us sell more jobs.
When a new employee joined us, Harry was right there to help the fellow get comfortable.
Harry took a real interest in the entire operation.
When I retired, Harry was the only logical person to take over.
But don't misunderstand, my friend continued.
Harry didn't try to put himself over on me.
He wasn't a mere meddler.
He wasn't aggressive in a negative way.
He didn't stab people in the back, and he didn't go around giving orders.
He just went around helping.
Harry simply acted as if everything in the company affected him.
He made company business his business.
We can all learn a lesson from Harry.
The I'm-doing-my-job-and-that's-enough attitude is small, negative thinking.
Big thinkers see themselves as members of a team effort, as winning or losing with the team, not by themselves.
They help in every way they can, even when there is no direct and immediate compensation or other reward.
The fellow who shrugs off a problem outside his own department with the comment,
well, that's no concern of mine, let them worry about it, hasn't got the attitude it takes for top leadership.
Practice this.
Practice being a big thinker.
See the company's interest as identical with your own.
Probably only a very few persons working in large companies have a sincere, unselfish interest in their company.
But after all, only a relatively few persons qualify as big thinkers, and these few are the ones eventually rewarded with the most responsible,
best-paying jobs.