The progressive business knows that how strong it will be five years from now depends not on what it does five years in the future,
but rather on what it does, invests, this year.
Profit comes from only one source—investment.
There's a lesson for each of us.
To profit—to get the extra reward above a normal income in the years ahead—we must invest in ourselves.
We must invest to achieve our goals.
Here are two sound self-investments that will pay handsome profits in the years ahead.
1.
Invest in education.
True education is the soundest investment you can make in yourself.
But let's be sure we understand what education really is.
Some folks measure education by the number of years spent in school or the number of diplomas,
certificates, and degrees earned.
But this quantitative approach to education doesn't necessarily produce a successful person.
Ralph J. Cordner, chairman of General Electric, expressed the attitude of top business management toward education this way.
Two of our most outstanding presidents, Mr. Wilson and Mr. Coffin, never had an opportunity to attend college.
Although some of our present officers have doctor's degrees, 12 out of 41 have no college degrees.
We are interested in competency, not diplomas.
A diploma or degree may help you get a job, but it will not guarantee your progress on the job.
Business is interested in competency, not diplomas.
To others, education means the quantity of information a person has stashed away in his brain.
But the soak-up-facts method of education won't get you where you want to go.
More and more we depend on books, files and machines to warehouse information.
If we can do only what a machine can do, we're in a real fix.
Real education, the kind worth investing in, is that which develops and cultivates your mind.
How well educated a person is, is measured by how well his mind is developed,
in brief, by how well he thinks.
Anything that improves thinking ability is education, and you can obtain education in many ways,
but the most efficient sources of education for most people are nearby colleges and universities.