When you help others feel important, you help yourself feel important, too.
One of the elevator operators who carried me up and down for several months had the look of complete unimportance written all over.
She was fiftiesh, unattractive, and certainly uninspired in her work.
It was obvious that her longing to be important was completely unfulfilled.
She was one of the millions of people who live for months at a time without ever being given a reason to believe that someone notices them or cares about them.
One morning, shortly after I became one of her regular uppers and downers,
I noticed that she had had her hair redone.
It was nothing fancy.
It was obviously a homemade job.
But it had been cut and it did look better.
So I said, Miss S. Note, I had learned her name.
I do like what you've done to your hair.
It really looks fine." She blushed, said, thank you, sir, and nearly missed her next stop.
She appreciated the compliment.
Next morning, lo and behold, when I stepped into the elevator I heard, Good morning, Dr. Schwartz.
Not one time before had I heard this operator address anyone by name.
And in the remaining months that I had an office in the building,
I never heard anyone called by name except me.
I had made the operator feel important.
I had sincerely complimented her and called her by name.
I had made her feel important.
Now she was repaying me by making me feel important.
Let's not kid ourselves.
People who do not have a deep-down feeling of self-importance are slated for mediocrity.
Again and again, this point must be driven home.
You must feel important to succeed.
Helping others to feel important rewards you because it makes you feel more important.
Try it and see.
Here's how to do it.
1.
Practice appreciation.
Make it a rule to let others know you appreciate what they do for you.
Never, never let anyone feel he is taken for granted.
Practice appreciation with a warm, sincere smile.
A smile lets others know you notice them and feel kindly toward them.
Practice appreciation by letting others know how you depend on them.
An earnest, Jim, I don't know what we'd do without you,
type of remark makes people feel necessary, and when they feel necessary, they do increasingly better work.
Practice appreciation with honest, personalized compliments.
People thrive on compliments, whether 2 or 20, 9 or 90.
A person craves praise.
He wants to be assured that he's doing a good job, that he is important.
Don't feel that you should hand out praise only for big accomplishments.
Compliment people on little things, their appearance, the way they do their routine work, their ideas, their loyal efforts.
Praise by writing personal notes complimenting people you know on their achievements.
Make a special phone call or a special trip to see them.
Don't waste time or mental energy trying to classify people as very important persons, important persons, or unimportant persons.
Make no exceptions.
A person, whether he is garbage collector or company vice president, is important to you.
Treating someone as second class never gets you first class results.