Here is how you can develop your power to see what can be, not just what is.
I call these the practice adding value exercises.
1.
Practice adding value to things.
Remember the real estate example.
Ask yourself, what can I do to add value to this room or this house or this business?
Look for ideas to make things worth more.
A thing, whether it be a vacant lot, a house, or a business,
has value in proportion to the ideas for using it.
2.
Practice adding value to people.
As you move higher and higher in the world of success, more and more of your job becomes people development.
Ask, what can I do to add value to my subordinates?
What can I do to help them to become more effective?
Remember, to bring out the best in a person, you must first visualize his best.
3.
Practice adding value to yourself.
Conduct a daily interview with yourself.
Ask, what can I do to make myself more valuable today?
Visualize yourself not as you are, but as you can be.
Then specific ways for attaining your potential value will suggest themselves.
Just try and see.