He wanted improvements.
All day, this third salesman gave me his ideas for getting new business,
providing better service to customers, reducing wasted time, revising the compensation plan to give more incentive,
all so that he and the company would make more.
He had mapped out a new advertising campaign he had been thinking about.
When I left him, his parting remark was, I sure appreciate the chance to tell someone about some of my ideas.
We've got a good outfit, but I believe we can make it better.
My recommendation, of course, was for the third man.
It was a recommendation that coincided perfectly with the feelings of the company president.
Believe in expansion, efficiency, new products, new processes, better schools, increased prosperity, Believe in and push for progress,
and you'll be a leader.
As a youngster, I had an opportunity to see how the different thinking of two leaders can make an amazing difference in the performance of followers.
I attended a country elementary school.
Eight grades, one teacher, and 40 children all jammed together inside four brick walls.
A new teacher was always a big deal.
Led by the big boys, the seventh and eighth graders, the pupils set out to see how much they could get away with.
One year there was little more than chaos.
Every day there were dozens of the usual school pranks, wars of spitballs and paper airplanes.
Then there were the major incidents, such as locking the teacher outside the school for half a day at a time,
or on another occasion the opposite, barricading her within the building for hours.
Another day, each boy in the upper grades brought his dog into the schoolroom.
Let me add that these children were not delinquents.
Stealing, physical violence, and deliberate harm were not their objectives.
They were healthy kids, conditioned by vigorous rural living, and needing an outlet for their tremendous pent-up energies and ingenuities.
Well, the teacher somehow managed to stay with the school until the end of that year.
To no one's surprise, there was a new teacher the following September.
The new teacher extracted strikingly different performance from the children.
She appealed to their personal pride and sense of respect.
She encouraged them to develop judgment.
Each child was assigned a specific responsibility, like washing blackboards or cleaning erasers,
or practicing paper grading for the younger grades.
The new teacher found creative ways to use the energy that had been so misdirected a few months before.
Her educational program was centered on building character.
Why did the children act like young devils one year and like young angels the next?
The difference was the leader, their teacher.
In all honesty, we cannot blame the kids for playing pranks an entire school year.
In each instance, the teacher set the pace.
The first teacher, deep down, didn't care whether the children made progress.
She set no goals for the children.
She didn't encourage them.
She couldn't control her temper.