I've learned that when you've been sniped at, one fine way to prevent a war of words is to take a long pause before answering.
Then I said to my student friend, much of what you say is true.
There are many, many highly successful people who know absolutely nothing about the subject matter in this course.
And it is possible for you to win success without this knowledge.
In the total scheme of life, this course content won't make or break you.
but your attitude toward this course may." What do you mean by that?" he asked.
Just this," I answered.
Outside, they grade you just as we grade you.
What counts there, just as what counts here, is doing the job.
Outside, they won't promote you or pay you more for doing second-class work.
I paused again to make certain the point got through.
Then I said, May I make a suggestion?
You're highly disappointed now.
I can appreciate how you feel.
And I don't think any less of you if you're a little sore at me.
But look at this experience positively.
There's a tremendously important lesson here.
If you don't produce, you don't get where you want to go.
Learn this lesson and five years from now you'll regard it as one of the most profitable lessons you learned in all the time you invested here.
I was glad when I learned a few days later that this student had re-enrolled for the course.
This time he passed with flying colors.
Afterward, he made a special call to see me to let me know how much he had appreciated our earlier discussion.
I learned something from flunking your course the first time," he said.
It may sound odd, but you know, Professor, now I'm glad I did not pass the first time.
We can turn setbacks into victories.
Find the lesson, apply it, and then look back on defeat and smile.
Moviegoers will never forget the great Lionel Barrymore.