Let me share with you an example of why we must have long-run goals to achieve real success.
Just last week, a young man, let me call him F.B., came to me with a career problem.
F.B. looked well-mannered and intelligent.
He was single and had finished college four years ago.
We talked for a while about what he was doing now, his education, his aptitudes, and general background.
Then I said to him, you came to see me for help on making a job change.
What kind of job are you looking for?
Well, he said, that's what I came to see you about.
I don't know what I want to do.
His problem, of course, was a very common one.
But I realized that just to arrange for the young man to have interviews with several possible employers would not help him.
Trial and error is a pretty poor way to select a career.
With dozens of career possibilities, the odds of stumbling into the right choice are several dozen to one.
I knew I had to help F.B. see that before he starts going someplace career-wise,
he's got to know where that someplace is.
So I said, let's look at your career plan from this angle.
Will you describe for me your image of yourself ten years from now?
F.B., obviously studying the question, finally said, well, I guess I want what just about everyone else wants,
a good job that pays well and a nice home.
Really, though, he continued, I haven't given it too much thought.
This, I assured him, was quite natural.
I went on to explain that his approach to selecting a career was like going to an airline ticket counter and saying,
give me a ticket.
The people selling the tickets just can't help you, unless you give them a destination.
So I said, and I can't help you find a job until I know what your destination is,
and only you can tell me that.
This jarred F.B. into thinking.
We spent the next two hours not talking about the merits of different kinds of jobs,