Four, practice speaking up.
In working with many kinds of groups of all sizes, I've watched many persons with keen perception and much native ability freeze and fail to participate in discussions.
It isn't that these folks don't want to get in and wade with the rest.
Rather, it's a simple lack of confidence.
The conference clam thinks to himself, my opinion is probably worthless.
If I say something, I'll probably look foolish.
I'll just say nothing.
Besides, the others in the group probably know more than I. I don't want the others to know how ignorant I am.
Each time the conference clam fails to speak, he feels even more inadequate, more inferior.
Often he makes a faint promise to himself, that deep down he knows he won't keep,
to speak next time.
This is very important.
Each time our clam fails to speak, he takes one more dose of confidence poison.
He becomes less and less confident of himself.
But on the positive side, the more you speak up, the more you add to your confidence,
and the easier it is to speak up the next time.
Speak up.
It's a confidence-building vitamin.
Put this confidence builder to use.
Make it a rule to speak up at every open meeting you attend.
Speak up.
Say something voluntarily at every business conference, committee meeting, community forum you attend.
Make no exception.
Comment, make a suggestion, ask a question, and don't be the last to speak.
Try to be the icebreaker, the first one in with a comment.
And never worry about looking foolish.
You won't.
For each person who doesn't agree with you, odds are another person will.
Quit asking yourself, I wonder if I dare speak.
Instead, concentrate on getting the discussion leader's attention so you can speak.
For special training and experience in speaking, consider joining your local Toastmasters club.
Thousands of conscientious people have developed confidence through a planned program to feel at ease talking with people and to people.