First group, those who surrendered completely.
The majority of people are convinced deep down inside that they haven't got what it takes,
that real success, real accomplishment, is for others who are lucky or fortunate in some special respect.
You can easily spot these people because they go to great lengths to rationalize their status and explain how happy they really are.
A very intelligent man, age 32, who has dead-ended himself in a safe but mediocre position,
recently spent hours telling me why he was so satisfied with his job.
He did a good job of rationalizing, but he was only kidding himself and he knew it.
What he really wanted was to work in a challenging situation where he could grow and develop.
but that multitude of suppressive influences had convinced him that he was inadequate for big things.
This group is, in reality, just the other extreme of the discontented job-switcher searching for opportunity.
Rationalizing yourself into a rut, which, incidentally, has been described as a grave with both ends open,
can be as bad as wandering aimlessly, hoping opportunity will somehow, someday, hit you in the face.
Second group.
Those who surrendered partially.
A second but much smaller group enters adult life with considerable hope for success.
These people prepare themselves.
They work.
They plan.
But after a decade or so, resistance begins to build up.
Competition for top-level jobs looks rugged.
This group then decides that greater success is not worth the effort.
They rationalize, we're earning more than the average and we live better than the average.
Why should we knock ourselves out?
Actually, this group has developed a set of fears.
Fear of failure, fear of social disapproval, fear of insecurity, fear of losing what they already have.
These people aren't satisfied because deep down they know they have surrendered.
This group includes many talented, intelligent people who elect to crawl through life because they are afraid to stand up and run.