A young man told me how he concentrated on seeing the good side when he lost his job.
He explained it this way.
I was working for a large credit reporting company.
One day I was given short notice to leave.
There was an economy wave on, and they dismissed the employees who were least valuable to the company.
The job didn't pay too well, but by the standards I grew up with, it was pretty good.
I really felt terrible for a few hours, but then I decided to look at being bounced as a blessing in disguise.
I really didn't like the job much, and had I stayed there, I'd never have gone far.
Now I had a chance to find something I really liked to do.
It wasn't long until I found a job that I liked a lot better that paid more money, too.
Being fired from that credit company was the best thing that ever happened to me.
Remember, you see in any situation what you expect to see.
See the good side and conquer defeat.
All things do work together for good if you'll just develop clear vision.
In quick review, The difference between success and failure is found in one's attitudes toward setbacks,
handicaps, discouragements, and other disappointing situations.
Five guideposts to help you turn defeat into victory are 1.
Study setbacks to pave your way to success.
When you lose, learn, and then go on to win next time.
2.
Have the courage to be your own constructive critic.
Seek out your faults and weaknesses and then correct them.
This makes you a professional.
3.
Stop blaming luck.
Research every setback.
Find out what went wrong.
Remember, blaming luck never got anyone where he wanted to go.
Four, blend persistence with experimentation.
Stay with your goal, but don't beat your head against a stone wall.
Try new approaches, experiment.
Five, remember, there is a good side in every situation.