Success just naturally followed.
Think for a moment about a club or a civic organization you know that is fading away.
Chances are, all it needs is enthusiasm to bring it back to life.
Results come in proportion to enthusiasm applied.
Enthusiasm is simply, this is great, here's why.
Here is a three-step procedure that will help you to develop the power of enthusiasm.
1.
Dig into it deeper.
Make this little test.
Think of two things in which you have little or no interest, maybe cards, certain kinds of music, a sport.
Now ask yourself, how much do I really know about these things?
Odds are 100 to 1 that your answer is not much.
I confess that for years I had absolutely no interest in modern art.
It was just so many botched up lines, until I let a friend who knows and loves modern art explain it to me.
Really, now that I've dug into it, I find it fascinating.
That exercise supplies one important key for building enthusiasm.
To get enthusiastic, learn more about the thing you are not enthusiastic about.
chances are you are quite unenthusiastic about bumblebees.
But if you study bumblebees, find out what good they do, how they relate to other bees,
how they reproduce, where they live in winter.
If you find out all you can about bumblebees, you will soon find yourself really interested in bumblebees.
To show trainees how enthusiasm can be developed through the dig-into-it-deeper technique,
I sometimes use a greenhouse example.
In a deliberately casual way, I ask the group, Are any of you interested in manufacturing and selling greenhouses?
Not once have I gotten an affirmative answer.
Then I make a few points about greenhouses.
I remind the group how, as our standard of living rises, people become more and more interested in non-necessities.
I suggest how much Mrs. America would enjoy growing her own orchids and orange blossoms.
I point out that if tens of thousands of families can afford private swimming pools,
millions could afford greenhouses, because greenhouses are relatively inexpensive.
I show them that if you could sell a $600 greenhouse to only one family in 50,