Here is the first step toward success.
It's a basic step.
It can't be avoided.
Step one, believe in yourself.
Believe you can succeed.
How to develop the power of belief.
Here are the three guides to acquiring and strengthening the power of belief.
1.
Think success, don't think failure.
At work, in your home, substitute success thinking for failure thinking.
When you face a difficult situation, think, I'll win, not, I'll probably lose.
When you compete with someone else, think, I'm equal to the best, not, I'm outclassed.
When opportunity appears, think, I can do it, never I can't.
Let the master thought, I will succeed, dominate your thinking process.
Thinking success conditions your mind to create plans that produce success.
Thinking failure does the exact opposite.
Failure thinking conditions the mind to think other thoughts that produce failure.
2.
Remind yourself regularly that you are better than you think you are.
Successful people are not supermen.
Success does not require a super intellect.
Nor is there anything mystical about success.
And success isn't based on luck.
Successful people are just ordinary folks who have developed belief in themselves and what they do.
Never, yes, never sell yourself short.
3.
Believe big.
The size of your success is determined by the size of your belief.
Think little goals and expect little achievements.
Think big goals and win big success.
Remember this, too.
Big ideas and big plans are often easier, certainly no more difficult, than small ideas and small plans.
Mr. Ralph J. Cordoner, chairman of the board of the General Electric Company, said this to a leadership conference.
We need from every man who aspires to leadership, for himself and his company,
a determination to undertake a personal program of self-development.
Nobody is going to order a man to develop.
Whether a man lags behind or moves ahead in his specialty is a matter of his own personal application.
This is something which takes time, work, and sacrifice.
Nobody can do it for you.
Mr. Cordoner's advice is sound and practical.
Live it.