I spent a very interesting evening recently with a friend who is the president of a young but rapidly growing manufacturing concern.
The TV set happened to be turned to one of the most popular quiz programs.
The fellow being quizzed had been on the show for several weeks.
He could answer questions on all sorts of subjects, many of which seemed nonsensical.
After the fellow answered a particularly odd question, something about a mountain in Argentina,
my host looked at me and said, How much do you think I'd pay that guy to work for me?
How much, I asked.
Not a cent over three hundred dollars, not per week, not per month, but for life.
I've sized him up.
That expert can't think.
He can only memorize.
He's just a human encyclopedia.
And I figure for $300 I can buy a pretty good set of encyclopedias.
In fact, maybe that's too much.
90% of what that guy knows I can find in a $2 almanac.
What I want around me, he continued, are people who can solve problems, who can think up ideas.
People who can dream and then develop the dream into a practical application.
An idea man can make money with me.
A fact man can't.