Chapter 13 How to Think Like a Leader Remind yourself once again that you are not pulled to high levels of success.
Rather, you are lifted there by those working beside and below you.
Achieving high-level success requires the support and the cooperation of others, and gaining this support and cooperation of others requires leadership ability.
Success and the ability to lead others, that is, getting them to do things they wouldn't do if they were not led,
go hand in hand.
The success-producing principles explained in the previous chapters are valuable equipment in helping you develop your leadership capacity.
At this point, we want to master four special leadership rules or principles that can cause others to do things for us in the executive suite,
in business, in social clubs, in the home, anywhere we find people.
These four leadership rules or principles are 1.
Trade minds with the people you want to influence.
2.
Think.
What is the human way to handle this?
Three, think progress, believe in progress, push for progress.
Four, take time out to confer with yourself and develop your supreme thinking power.
Practicing these rules produces results.
Putting them to use in everyday situations takes the mystery out of that gold-plated word, leadership.
Let's see how.
Leadership rule number one, trade minds with the people you want to influence.
Trading minds with the people you want to influence is a magic way to get others,
friends, associates, customers, employees, to act the way you want them to act.
Study these two case histories and see why.
Ted B. worked as a television copywriter and director for a large advertising agency.
When the agency obtained a new account, a children's shoe manufacturer, Ted was assigned responsibility for developing several TV commercials.
A month or so after the campaign had been launched, it became clear that the advertising was doing little or nothing to increase product movement in retail outlets.
Attention was focused on the TV commercials, because in most cities only television advertising was used.
Through research of television viewers, they found that about 4% of the people thought it was simply a great commercial.
One of the best, these 4% said.
The remaining 96% were either indifferent to the commercials or, in plain language, thought they smelled.
Hundreds of comments like these were volunteered.
It's wacky.
The rhythm sounds like a New Orleans band at 3 a.m. My kids like to watch most TV commercials,
but when that shoe thing comes on, they go to the bathroom or refrigerator.
I think it's too uppity-up.
Seems to me someone's trying to be too clever.
Something especially interesting turned up when all the interviews were put together and analyzed.
The 4% who liked the commercial were people pretty much like Ted in terms of income, education, sophistication, and interests.
The remaining 96% were definitely in a different socioeconomic class.
Ted's commercials, which cost a lot of money, flopped because Ted thought only of his own interests.
He had prepared the commercials thinking of the way he buys shoes, not the way the great majority buys shoes.
He developed commercials that pleased him personally, not commercials that pleased the great bulk of the people.
The results would have been much different had Ted projected himself into the minds of the masses of ordinary people and asked himself two questions.
If I were a parent, what kind of a commercial would make me want to buy those shoes?
If I were a child, what kind of a commercial would make me go tell my mom or dad that I want those shoes?