Excusitis appears in a wide variety of forms, but the worst types of this disease are health excusitis,
intelligence excusitis, age excusitis, and luck excusitis.
Now let's see just how we can protect ourselves from these four common ailments.
1.
But my health isn't good.
Health excusitis ranges all the way from the chronic, I don't feel good,
to the more specific, I've got such and such wrong with me.
Bad health, in a thousand different forms, is used as an excuse for failing to do what a person wants to do,
failing to accept greater responsibilities, failing to make more money, failing to achieve success.
Millions and millions of people suffer from health excusitis.
But is it in most cases a legitimate excuse?
Think for a moment of all the highly successful people you know who could,
but who don't, use health as an excuse.
My physician and surgeon friends tell me the perfect specimen of adult life is non-existent.
There is something physically wrong with everybody.
Many surrender in whole or in part to health excusitis, but success-thinking people do not.
Two experiences happened to me in one afternoon that illustrate the correct and incorrect attitudes toward health.
I had just finished a talk in Cleveland.
Afterward, one fellow, about thirty, asked to speak to me privately for a few minutes.
He complimented me on the meeting, but then said, I'm afraid your ideas can't do me much good.
You see, he continued, I've got a bad heart, and I've got to hold myself in check.
He went on to explain that he'd seen four doctors, but they couldn't find his trouble.
He asked me what I would suggest he do.
Well, I said, I know nothing about the heart, but as one layman to another,
here are three things I'd do.
First, I'd visit the finest heart specialist I could find and accept his diagnosis as final.
You've already checked with four doctors, and none of them has found anything peculiar with your heart.
Let the fifth doctor be your final check.
It may very well be you've got a perfectly sound heart.
But if you keep on worrying about it, eventually you may have a very serious heart ailment.
Looking and looking and looking for an illness often actually produces illness.