We learn in different ways, I said.
I think you can learn a real success lesson from this experience.
When you used your pony in there, your conscience bothered you terribly.
This gave you a guilt complex that in turn broke your confidence.
As you expressed it, you went to pieces.
Most of the time, Paul, this matter of right and wrong is approached from a moral or religious standpoint.
Now understand, I'm not here to preach to you, give you a sermon about right and wrong.
But let's look at the practical side.
When you do anything that goes contrary to your conscience, you feel guilty,
and this guilty feeling jams your thought processes.
You can't think straight because your mind is asking, will I get caught?
Will I get caught?
Paul, I continued, you wanted an A so badly, you did something you knew was wrong.
There are many times in life when you'll want to make an A so badly,
you'll be tempted to do something that is contrary to your conscience.
For example, someday you may want to make a sale so badly you'll think of deliberately misleading the customer to buy,
and you may succeed.
But here's what will happen.
Your guilty feeling will grab hold of you, and the next time you see your customer,
you'll be self-conscious, ill at ease.
You'll be wondering, has he discovered that I put something over?
Your presentation will be ineffective because you can't concentrate.
Chances are you'll never make the second, third, fourth, and the many repeat sales.
In the long run, making that sale using tactics that hurt your conscience will cost you a lot of income.
I went on and pointed out to Paul how an occasional business or professional man loses his grip because of an intense fear that his wife will learn about a secret love affair he is having with another woman.
Will she find out?
eats away the man's confidence until he can't do a good job at work or in the home.
I reminded Paul that many criminals are captured not because any clues point to them,
but because they act guilty and self-conscious.
Their guilt-feeling puts them on the suspect list.
There is within each of us a desire to be right, think right, and act right.
When we go against that desire, we put a cancer in our conscience.
This cancer grows and grows by eating away at our confidence.
Avoid doing anything that will cause you to ask yourself, will I get caught?
Will they find out?
Will I get away with it?
Don't try to make an A if it means violating your confidence.