This prompted several of the finest families in the area to sell their homes at a loss and move on.
As so often happens, the do-care families caught the don't-care attitude from their don't-care neighbors.
Everyone, that is, except Harry L. Harry, did care, and he decided to crusade for a fine neighborhood.
Harry began by calling together some friends.
He pointed out that this subdivision had tremendous potential, but that something must be done now or the area would soon be a strictly second-class neighborhood.
Harry's enthusiasm and initiative quickly won support.
Soon there were clean-up-the-vacant-lots projects.
Garden clubs were organized.
A massive tree-planting project was started.
A playground was built for the youngsters.
A community swimming pool was constructed.
The don't-care families became eager supporters.
The whole subdivision took on new life and new sparkle.
It's really a pleasure now to drive through that community.
It shows what a Crusader can do.
Do you feel your business should develop a new department, make a new product, or in some other way expand?
Well then, Crusade for it.
Feel your church needs a new building?
Crusade for it.
Would you like your children's school to have better equipment?
Crusade and get it for them.
And you can bank on this.
While Crusades may start out as one-man Crusades, if the idea behind the Enterprise is good,
soon you'll have lots of support.
Be an Activationist and Crusade.
2.
Be a Volunteer Each of us has been in situations in which we wanted to volunteer for some activity but didn't.
Why?
Because of fear.
Not fear that we couldn't accomplish the task, but rather fear of what our associates would say.
The fear of being laughed at, of being called an eager beaver, of being accused of bucking for a raise holds many people back.
It's natural to want to belong, to be accepted, to have group approval.
But ask yourself, which group do I want to have accept me?
The group that laughs because it is secretly jealous, or the group that is making progress by doing things?
The right choice is obvious.
The volunteer stands out.
He receives special attention.