Several years ago, while checking student examination papers, I came across one that especially disturbed me.
The student who wrote the examination had demonstrated in class discussions and previous tests that he was far better qualified than his paper indicated.
He was, in fact, the fellow who I thought would finish at the top of the class.
Instead, his paper put him at the bottom.
As was my custom in such cases, I had my secretary call the student and ask him to come by my office on an urgent matter.
Paul W. appeared shortly.
He looked as though he had been through a terrible experience.
After he was comfortably seated, I said to him, What happened, Paul?
This just isn't the quality paper I expected you to write.
Paul struggled with himself, looked in the direction of his feet, and replied,
Sir, after I saw that you had spotted me cheating, I just went to pieces.
I couldn't concentrate on anything.
Honest, this is the first time I've ever cheated at the university.
I desperately wanted an A, so I worked up a little pony to use.
He was terribly upset.
But now that he was talking, he wouldn't stop.
I suppose you'll have to recommend me for dismissal.
The university rule says any student found cheating in any manner is subject to permanent dismissal.
Here Paul started bringing up the shame this incident would bring to his family,
how it would wreck his life, and all sorts of repercussions.
Finally, I said, hold it now.
Slow down.
Let me explain something.
I didn't see you cheat.
Until you walked in and told me, I hadn't the faintest idea that was the trouble.
I am sorry, Paul, that you did.
Then I continued, Paul, tell me, just what do you want to gain from your university experience?
He was a little calmer now, and after a short pause he said,
well, doctor, I think my overall aim is to learn how to live,
but I guess I'm failing pretty badly.