This is a fact of paramount significance.
Each human being, whether he lives in India or Indianapolis, whether he's ignorant or brilliant,
civilized or uncivilized, young or old, has this desire.
He wants to feel important.
Ponder on that.
Everyone, yes everyone, your neighbor, you, your wife, your boss, has a natural desire to feel he is somebody.
The desire to be important is man's strongest, most compelling non-biological hunger.
Successful advertisers know that people crave prestige, distinction, recognition.
Headlines that produce sales read like this.
For smart young homemakers, persons with distinctive tastes use, you want only the best.
Be the envy of everyone.
for women who want to be envied by women and admired by men.
These headlines, in effect, tell people, buy this product and you put yourself in the important class.
Satisfying the craving, the hunger, to be important, carries you forward to success.
It is basic equipment in your success tool chest.
Yet, even though displaying the attitude, you are important, gets results, and even though it costs nothing,
few persons use it.
A little fill-in is needed here to show why.
On the philosophical side, our religions, our laws, our entire culture are based on the belief of the importance of the individual.
Suppose, for example, you were flying your own plane and were forced down in an isolated mountain region.
As soon as your accident was known, a large-scale search for you would begin.
No one would ask, is that fellow important?
Without knowing anything about you except that you are a human being, helicopters,
other aircraft, and searching parties on foot would begin looking for you.
and they would keep on looking for you, spending thousands of dollars in the process,
until they found you, or until not one trace of hope remained.
When a little child wanders off into a woods, falls into a well,
or gets into some other dangerous predicament, no one is concerned with whether or not the child comes from an important family.
Every effort is made to rescue the child, because every child is important.
It's not too wild to guess that of all living creatures, probably not more than one in ten million is a human being.
A person is a biological rarity.
He is important in God's scheme of things.
Now let's look at the practical side.
When most people shift their thinking from philosophical discussions to everyday situations, they tend to forget,
unfortunately, their ivory tower concepts of the importance of individuals.
Tomorrow, take a good look at how most people exhibit an attitude that seems to say,