Mr. Activationist plans a vacation.
He takes it.
Mr. Passivationist plans a vacation, but he postpones it until next year.
Mr. A decides he should attend church regularly.
He does.
Mr. P thinks it's a good idea to go to church regularly,
too, but he finds ways to postpone acquiring this new habit.
Mr. A feels that he should drop a note to someone he knows to congratulate him on some achievement.
He writes the note.
Under the same circumstances, Mr. P finds a good reason to put off writing the note,
and it never gets written.
The difference shows up in big things, too.
Mr. A wants to go into business for himself.
He does.
Mr. P also wants to go into business for himself, but he discovers just in the nick of time a good reason why he had better not.
Mr. A, age forty, decides he wants to take up a new line of work.
He does.
The same idea occurs to Mr. P, but he debates himself out of doing anything about it.
The difference between Messer's activationist and passivationist shows through in all forms of behavior.
Mr. A gets the things done he wants done, and as byproducts he gains confidence,
a feeling of inner security, self-reliance, and more income.
Mr. P doesn't get the things done he wants done because he won't act.
As byproducts, he loses confidence in himself, destroys his self-reliance, lives in mediocrity.
Mr. Activationist does.
Mr. Passivationist is going to do, but doesn't.
Everyone wants to be an Activationist.
So, let's get the action habit.
A lot of Passivationists got that way because they insisted on waiting until everything was 100% favorable before they took action.
Perfection is highly desirable, but nothing man-made or man-designed is or can be absolutely perfect.
So to wait for the perfect set of conditions is to wait forever.
Here are three case histories that show how three persons reacted to conditions.