Here are two specific things to do to build confidence through efficient management of your memory bank.
1.
Deposit only positive thoughts in your memory bank.
Let's face it squarely.
Everyone encounters plenty of unpleasant, embarrassing, and discouraging situations.
But unsuccessful and successful people deal with these situations in directly opposite ways.
Unsuccessful people take them to heart, so to speak.
They dwell on the unpleasant situations, thereby giving them a good start in their memory.
They don't take their minds away from them.
At night, the unpleasant situation is the last thing they think about.
Confident, successful people, on the other hand, don't give it another thought.
Successful people specialize in putting positive thoughts into their memory bank.
What kind of performance would your car deliver if every morning before you left for work,
you scooped up a double handful of dirt and put it into your crankcase?
That fine engine would soon be a mess, unable to do what you want it to do.
Negative unpleasant thoughts deposited in your mind affect your mind the same way.
Negative thoughts produce needless wear and tear on your mental motor.
They create worry, frustration, and feelings of inferiority.
They put you beside the road while others drive ahead.
Do this.
In these moments when you're alone with your thoughts, when you're driving your car or eating alone,
recall pleasant, positive experiences.
Put good thoughts in your memory bank.
This boosts confidence.
It gives you that, I sure feel good feeling.
It helps keep your body functioning right too.
Here is an excellent plan.
Just before you go to sleep, deposit good thoughts in your memory bank.
Count your blessings.
Recall the many good things you have to be thankful for.
Your wife or husband, your children, your friends, your health.
Recall the good things you saw people do today.
Recall your little victories and accomplishments.
Go over the reasons why you are glad to be alive.