Case number one.
Why G.N. hasn't married.
Mr. G.N. is now in his late thirties, is well-educated, works as an accountant,
and lives alone in Chicago.
G.N.'s big desire is to get married.
He wants love, companionship, a home, children, the works.
G.N. has been close to marriage.
Once he was only one day away.
But each time he has been near marriage, he discovers something wrong with the girl he's about to marry.
Just in time before I made an awful mistake.
One instance stands out.
Two years ago, Jian thought he finally had met just the right girl.
She was attractive, pleasant, intelligent.
But Jian had to be absolutely sure that marriage was the right thing.
As they were discussing marriage plans one evening, the future Mrs. Jian made a few remarks that bothered Jian.
So, to make certain he was marrying the right girl, G.N. drew up a four-page document of stipulations she was to agree to before they got married.
The document, neatly typed and looking very legal, covered every segment of living G.N. could think of.
There was one section on religion, what church they would go to, how often they would attend,
how much they would donate.
Another section covered children, how many and when.
In detail, G.N. outlined the kind of friends they would have, his future wife's employment status,
where they would live, how their income would be spent.
To finish the document, G.N. devoted half a page to listing specific habits the girl must break or must acquire.
This covered such habits as smoking, drinking, makeup, entertainment, and so on.
When Jian's prospective bride reviewed his ultimatum, she did what you would expect.
She sent it back with a note saying, the usual marriage clause, for better or for worse,
is good enough for everyone else, and it's good enough for me.
The whole thing is off.
As Jian was relating his experience to me, he said worriedly, now what was so wrong in writing out this agreement?
After all, marriage is a big step.
You can't be too careful.
But Jian was wrong.
You can be too careful, too cautious.
Not only in planning a marriage, but in planning anything in the world where things get done.
The standards can be too high.
Jian's approach to marriage was very much like his approach to his work, his savings, his friendships, everything else.
The test of a successful person is not an ability to eliminate all problems before they arise,
but to meet and work out difficulties when they do arise.
We must be willing to make an intelligent compromise with perfection, lest we wait forever before taking action.
It's still good advice to cross bridges as we come to them.
Case number two.