2.
Practice calling people by their names.
Every year, shrewd manufacturers sell more briefcases, pencils, Bibles, and hundreds of other items just by putting the buyer's name on the product.
People like to be called by name.
It gives everyone a boost to be addressed by name.
Two special things you must remember.
Pronounce the name correctly and spell it correctly.
If you mispronounce or misspell someone's name, that person feels that you feel he is unimportant.
And here's one special reminder.
When talking with people you don't know well, add the appropriate title,
Miss, Mr. or Mrs. The office boy prefers Mr. Jones to just Jones.
So does your junior assistant.
So do people at every level.
These little titles help tremendously to make people feel important.
3.
Don't hog glory.
Invest it instead.
Just recently I was a guest at an all-day sales convention.
After dinner that evening, the vice president in charge of sales for the company passed out awards to the two district managers,
a man and a woman, whose sales organizations had attained the best records for the year just ended.
Then the vice president asked those district managers to take fifteen minutes to tell the entire group how their organizations did so exceptionally well.
The first district manager, who I later learned had been appointed a manager only three months before and was therefore only partially responsible for his organization's record,
got up and explained how he did it.
He conveyed the impression that his efforts, and his efforts alone, caused the sales increase.
Remarks such as, When I took over, I did such and such.
Things were in a mess, but I cleared them up.
It wasn't easy, but I just grabbed hold of the situation and wouldn't let go, characterized his talk.
As he talked, I could see the increasing resentment gathering in the faces of his salesmen.
They were being ignored for the sake of the district manager's personal glory.
Their hard work, which was responsible for the sales increase, was completely unrecognized.
Then the second district manager got up to make her short talk, but this lady used an entirely different approach.
First, she explained that the reason for her organization's success was the wholehearted effort of her sales force.
Then she asked each one to stand and paid a sincere personal compliment to each for his or her efforts.
Note this difference.
The first manager squandered the vice president's praise entirely on himself.
In doing so, he offended his own people.
His sales force was demoralized.
The second passed the praise on to her sales force, where it could do more good.
This manager knew that praise, like money, can be invested to pay dividends.
She knew that passing the credit on to her sales people would make them work even harder next year.
Remember, praise is power.