You can't even fool a dog.
Your mannerisms, eyes, facial expressions, all spell P-H-O-N-Y when you pretend.
Now, when I'm gathering information about a prospect, I do what every other agent does.
I get his age, where he works, how much he makes, how many kids he's got, and so on.
But I also get something else, which most salesmen never search for.
That is, some sound reasons why I can like the prospect.
Maybe the job he's doing will supply the reason, or perhaps I can find it someplace in his past record.
But I find some good reasons to like him.
Then, whenever my attention is focused on the prospect, I review the reasons why I like him.
I build a likable image of the prospect before I say one word to him about insurance.
This little technique works.
Because I like him, he sooner or later likes me.
Pretty soon, instead of sitting across the table from him, I'm on the same side with him,
and we're working out his insurance plan together.
He trusts and believes in my judgment because I am a friend.
Now, people don't always accept me right off the bat, but I've found that so long as I continue to like a fellow,
he'll come around and we can get down to business.
Just last week, my friend went on, I was making the third call on a difficult prospect.
He met me at the door, and before I could even say good evening, he proceeded to give me hell.
He went on and on, not even stopping for a breath until he had run down and finished with,
and don't ever come back here again.
After he had said that, I just stood there looking into his eyes for about five seconds,
and then said softly and with genuine sincerity, because I meant it, but Mr. S,
I'm calling tonight as your friend.
Yesterday, he bought a $250,000 endowment policy.
Sol Polk is popularly called the appliance king of Chicago.
Starting with nothing, Sol Polk now sells millions of dollars worth of appliances in a year in metropolitan Chicago.
Sol Polk credits a lot of his success to his attitude toward shoppers.
Customers, says Mr. Polk, should be treated like they are guests in my home.
Isn't that thinking toward people?
And isn't it about the simplest success formula one can put to work?
Just treat customers like guests in your home.
This technique works outside the store too.
Substitute the word employees for customers so that it reads, employees should be treated like guests in my home.
Give first class treatment to your employees and you get first class cooperation, first class output.
Think first class about everyone around you and you'll receive first class results in return.