Shortly after World War II, Seedy got a job with the Customs Division of the U.S. Post Office Department.
He liked his work, but after five years he became dissatisfied with the confinement,
regular hours, low pay, and the seniority system with its relatively narrow chances for advancement.
Then he got an idea.
He had learned a great deal about what it takes to be a successful importer.
Why not set himself up in the business of importing low-cost gift items and toys?
C.D. knew many successful importers who didn't have his knowledge of the ins and outs of this business.
It's been ten years now since C.D. decided he wanted to go into business for himself.
But today, he's still working for the customs office.
Why?
Well, every time C.D. was just about ready to cut loose on his own,
something happened that stopped him from taking action.
Lack of money, economic recession, new baby, need for temporary security, trade restrictions,
and more excuses all served as reasons for waiting, for postponing.
The real truth is that C.D. let himself develop into a passivationist.
He wanted conditions to be perfect before he took action.
Since conditions were never perfect, C.D. never took action.
Here are two things to do to help you avoid the costly mistake of waiting until conditions are perfect before you act.