If the answer is no, back off.
If yes, press ahead.
It's clear we do not make one big jump to success.
We get there one step at a time.
An excellent plan is to set monthly quotas for accomplishment.
Here is a guide to help achieve these goals.
Examine yourself.
Decide what specific things you should do to make yourself more effective.
Then, when the 30-day period is up, check your progress and build a new 30-day goal.
Always keep working on the little things to get you in shape for the big things.
30-Day Improvement Guide.
Between now and the next 30 days, I will... A.
Break these habits.
Suggestions.
1.
Putting off things.
2.
Negative language.
3.
Watching TV more than 60 minutes per day.
4.
Gossip.
B. Acquire these habits.
Suggestions.
1.
A rigid morning examination of my appearance.
2.
Plan each day's work the night before.
3.
Compliment people at every possible opportunity.
C. Increase my value to my employer in these ways.
Suggestions.
1.
Do a better job of developing my subordinates.
2.
Learn more about my company, what it does, and the customers it serves.
3.
Make three specific suggestions to help my company become more efficient.
D. Increase my value to my home in these ways.
Suggestions 1.
Show more appreciation for the little things my wife does that I've been taking for granted.
2.
Once each week, do something special with my whole family.
3.
Give one hour each day of my undivided attention to my family.
E. Sharpen my mind in these ways.
Suggestions.
1.
Invest two hours each week in reading professional magazines in my field.
2.
Read one self-help book.
3.
Make four new friends.
4.
Spend 30 minutes daily in quiet, undisturbed thinking.
Next time you see a particularly well-poised, well-groomed, clear-thinking, effective person,
remind yourself that he wasn't born that way.
Lots of conscious effort, invested day by day, made the person what he is.
Building new positive habits and destroying old negative habits is a day-by-day process.
Create your first 30-day improvement guide right now.
Often, when I discuss setting goals, someone comments along these lines.
I see that working toward a purpose is important, but so often things happen that upset my plans.