I was assigned the job of handling all collection correspondence.
The collection letters the store had been using greatly disappointed me.
They were strong, insulting, and threatening.
I read them and thought, Brother, I'd be mad as hell if somebody sent me letters like these.
I never would pay.
So I just got to work and started writing the kind of letter that would move me to pay an overdue bill if I received it.
It worked.
By putting myself in the shoes of the overdue customer, so to speak, collections climbed to a record high.
Numerous political candidates lose elections because they fail to look at themselves through the minds of the typical voters.
One political candidate for a national office, apparently fully as qualified as his opponent,
lost by a tremendous margin for one single reason.
He used a vocabulary that only a small percentage of the voters could understand.
His opponent, on the other hand, thought in terms of the voters' interests.
When he talked to farmers, he used their language.
When he spoke to factory workers, he used words they were easily familiar with.
When he spoke on TV, he addressed himself to Mr. Typical Voter, not to Dr. College Professor.
Keep this question in mind.
What would I think of this if I exchanged places with the other person?
It paves the way to more successful action.
Thinking of the interests of the people we want to influence is an excellent thought rule in every situation.
A few years ago, a small electronics manufacturer developed a fuse that would never blow out.
The manufacturer priced the product to sell for $1.25 and then retained an advertising agency to promote it.
The account executive placed in charge of the advertising immediately became intensely enthusiastic.
His plan was to blanket the country with mass advertising on TV, radio, and newspapers.
This is it, he said.
We'll sell 10 million the first year.
His advisors tried to caution him, explaining that fuses are not a popular item,
they have no romantic appeal, and people want to get by as cheaply as possible when they buy fuses.
Why not, the advisors said, use selected magazines and sell it to the high income levels?
They were overruled, and the mass campaign was underway, only to be called off in six weeks because of disappointing results.
The trouble was this.
The advertising executive looked at the high-priced fuses with his eyes, the eyes of a high-income person.
He failed to see the product through the eyes of the mass market income levels.
Had he put himself in their position, he would have seen the wisdom of directing the promotion toward the upper income groups and the account would have been saved.
Develop your power to trade minds with the people you want to influence.