We made three suggestions.
1.
Recognize the fact that no person is perfect.
Some people are more nearly perfect than others, but no man is absolutely perfect.
The most human quality about human beings is that they make mistakes, all kinds of them.
2.
Recognize the fact that the other fellow has a right to be different.
Never play God about anything.
Never dislike people because their habits are different from your own or because they prefer different clothes,
religion, parties, or automobiles.
You don't have to approve of what another fellow does, but you must not dislike him for doing it.
3.
Don't be a reformer.
Put a little more live and let live into your philosophy.
Most people intensely dislike being told you're wrong.
You have a right to your own opinion, but sometimes it's better to keep it to yourself.
Ted conscientiously applied these suggestions.
A few months later he had a fresh outlook.
He now accepts people for what they are, neither 100% good nor 100% bad.
Besides, he says, the things that used to annoy the heck out of me I now find amusing.
It finally dawned on me what a dull world this would be if people were all alike and everybody was perfect.
Note this simple but key fact.
No person is all good, and no person is all bad.
The perfect person just doesn't exist.
Now, if we let our thinking go uncontrolled, we can find much to dislike in almost anyone.