The overwhelming majority of really successful people work much longer than 40 hours a week,
and you don't hear them complain of overwork.
Successful people have their eyes focused on a goal, and this provides energy.
The point is this.
Energy increases, multiplies, when you set a desired goal and resolve to work toward that goal.
Many people, millions of them, can find new energy by selecting a goal and giving all they've got to accomplish that goal.
Goals cure boredom.
Goals even cure many chronic ailments.
Let's probe a little deeper into the power of goals.
When you surrender yourself to your desires, when you let yourself become obsessed with a goal,
you receive the physical power, energy, and enthusiasm needed to accomplish your goal.
But you receive something else, something equally valuable.
You receive the automatic instrumentation needed to keep you going straight to your objective.
The most amazing thing about a deeply entrenched goal is that it keeps you on course to reach your target.
This isn't double talk.
What happens is this.
When you surrender to your goal, the goal works itself into your subconscious mind.
Your subconscious mind is always in balance.
Your conscious mind is not, unless it is in tune with what your subconscious mind is thinking.
Without full cooperation from the subconscious mind, a person is hesitant, confused, indecisive.
Now, with your goal absorbed into your subconscious mind, you react the right way automatically.
The conscious mind is free for clear, straight thinking.
Let's illustrate this with two hypothetical persons.
As you listen, you'll recognize these characters among the real people you know.
We'll call them Tom and Jack.
These fellows are comparable in all respects except one.
Tom has a firmly entrenched goal.
Jack does not.
Tom has a crystal clear image of what he wants to be.
He pictures himself as a corporation vice president ten years hence.
Because Tom has surrendered to his goal, his goal through his subconscious mind signals to him saying,
do this or don't do that.
It won't help get you where you want to go.
The goal constantly speaks, I am the image you want to make real.
Here is what you must do to make me real.