By the same token, if we manage our thinking properly, if we think right toward people,
we can find many qualities to like and admire in the same person.
View it this way.
Your mind is a mental broadcasting station.
This broadcasting system transmits messages to you on two equally powerful channels, channel P, positive, and channel N, negative.
Let's see how your broadcasting system works.
Suppose that today your business superior, we'll call him Mr. Jacobs, called you into his office and reviewed your work with you.
He complimented you on your work, but he also made some specific suggestions on how you can do it better.
Tonight, it's only natural for you to recall the incident and do some thinking about it.
If you tune in Channel N, the announcer will be saying something like this.
Watch out!
Jacobs is out to get you.
He's a crab.
You don't need any of his advice, to heck with it.
Remember what Joe told you about Jacobs?
He was right.
Jacobs wants to grind you down like he did Joe.
Resist him.
Next time he calls you in, fight back.
Better still, don't wait.
Tomorrow, go in and ask him just what he really meant by his criticism.
But tune in Channel P and the announcer will say something along these lines.
You know, Mr. Jacobs is a pretty good fellow.
Those suggestions he made to me seem pretty sound.
If I put them to use, I can probably do a better job and position myself for an increase.
The old boy did me a favor.
Tomorrow I'll go in and thank him for his constructive help.
Bill was right.
Jacobs is a good man to work with.
In this specific case, if you listen to Channel N, you're almost certain to make some bad,
perhaps fatal mistake in your relations with your superior.
But if you are tuned to Channel P, you are definitely certain to benefit from your superior's suggestions and at the same time draw yourself closer to him.
He will appreciate that visit.
Try it and see.
Bear in mind that the longer you stay tuned to either Channel P or Channel N,
the more interested you become and the harder it is to switch channels.
This is true because one thought, positive or negative, sets off a whole chain reaction of similar thought.
You may, for example, start off with such a simple minor negative thought as a person's accent,
and find yourself soon thinking negatively about such unrelated topics as his political and religious beliefs,
the car he drives, his personal habits, his relationship with his wife, even the way he combs his hair.
And thinking this way surely won't get you where you want to go.
You own it, so manage your thought broadcasting station.
When your thoughts turn to people, make Channel P your listening habit.