Here's why.
In the long, long history of humankind, a speaking language, even remotely resembling what we use today,
is a very recent invention.
So recent, you might say, in terms of the great clock of time,
that we developed a language only this morning.
For millions and millions of years, people got by with little more than moans and groans and grunts and growls.
So for millions of years, people communicated with other people by body and facial expressions and sounds, not words.
And we still communicate our attitudes, our feelings toward people and things the same way.
Aside from direct body contact, body movements, facial expressions and sound are the only ways we have to communicate with infants.
And those young ones show an uncanny ability to spot the phony.
Professor Erwin H. Schell, one of America's most respected authorities on leadership,
says, Obviously, there is something more than facilities and competence that makes for accomplishment.
I have come to believe that this linkage factor, this catalyst, if you will,
can be defined in a single word—attitude.
When our attitude is right, our abilities reach a maximum of effectiveness, and good results inevitably follow.
Attitudes do make the difference.
Salesmen with the right attitude beat their quotas.
Students with the right attitude make A's.
Right attitudes pave the way to really happy married life.
Right attitudes make you effective in dealing with people, enable you to develop as a leader.
Right attitudes win for you in every situation.
Grow these three attitudes.