Now, what's the effect of these two home environments on John and Milton?
Over a period of a week or two, there probably is no perceptible effect,
but over a period of months and years, the effect is tremendous.
John's environmental pattern leaves him refreshed, gives him ideas, tunes up his thinking.
He's like an athlete being fed steak.
Milton's environmental pattern leaves him psychologically starved.
His thinking mechanism is impaired.
He's like an athlete being fed candy and beer.
John and Milton may be on the same level today, but there will gradually be a wide gap between them in the months ahead,
with John in the lead position.
Casual observers will say, well, I guess John has more on the ball than Milton.
But those of us who know will explain that much of the difference in job performance is the result of the difference in the mind food consumed by the two fellows.
Every farmer in the Corn Belt knows that if he puts plenty of fertilizer with his corn,
he's going to get a bigger yield.
Thinking, too, must be given additional nourishment if we want to get better results.
My wife and I, along with five other couples, spent a wonderful evening last month as guests of a department store executive and his wife.
My wife and I lingered just a little longer than the others, so I had a chance to ask our host,
whom I know well, a question that had been in my mind all evening.
This was really a wonderful evening, I said, but I'm puzzled about one thing.
I'd expected to meet mainly other retailing executives here tonight, but your guests all represented different fields.
There was a writer, a doctor, an engineer, an accountant, and a teacher." He smiled and said,
"'Well, we often do entertain retailing people, but Helen and I find it's very refreshing to mix with people who do something else for a living.
I'm afraid if we can find our entertaining to people who have only interests similar to our own,
we'd find ourselves in the old well-known rut.
Besides, he went on, people are my business.
Every day thousands of people of every occupational group imaginable visit our store.