One.
Expect future obstacles and difficulties.
Every venture presents risks, problems, and uncertainties.
Let's suppose you wanted to drive your car from Chicago to Los Angeles,
but you insisted on waiting until you had absolute assurance that there would be no detours,
no motor trouble, no bad weather, no drunken drivers, no risk of any kind.
When would you start?
Never.
In planning your trip to Los Angeles, it makes sense to map your route,
check your car, in other ways to eliminate as much risk as possible before you start.
But you can't eliminate all risks.
2.
Meet problems and obstacles as they arise.
The test of a successful person is not the ability to eliminate all problems before he takes action,
but rather the ability to find solutions to difficulties when he encounters them.
In business, marriage, or in any activity, cross bridges when you come to them.
We can't buy an insurance policy against all problems.
Make up your mind to do something about your ideas.