Go on, he said.
Well, there are two kinds of action that seem to fit your case.
First, start this afternoon to move those sales figures upward.
We've got to face it.
There's a reason your sales are slipping.
Find it.
Maybe you need a special sale to clear out your slow-moving merchandise,
so you'll be in a position to buy some fresh stock.
Perhaps you can rearrange your display counters.
Maybe your salespeople need more enthusiasm.
I can't pinpoint what will turn your sales volume upward, but something will.
And it would probably be wise to talk privately with your merchandise manager.
He may be on the verge of putting you out, but when you talk it over with him and ask his advice,
he'll certainly give you more time to work things out.
It's too expensive for the store to replace you as long as top management feels there's a chance you'll find a solution." I went on.
Then get your assistant buyers on the ball.
Quit acting like a drowning man.
Let people around you know that you're still alive.
Courage was again in his eyes.
Then he asked, You said there are two kinds of action I should take.
What's the second?
The second type of action, which you might say is an insurance policy,
is to let two or three of your closest business friends in the trade know you might consider an offer from another store,
assuming, of course, it is substantially better than your present job.
I don't believe your job will be insecure after you take some affirmative action to get those sales figures on the rise.
But just in case, it's good to have an offer or two.
Remember, it's ten times easier for a man with a job to get another job than it is for someone unemployed to connect.
Two days ago, this once-troubled executive called me.
After our talk, I buckled down.
I made a number of changes, but the most basic one was with my salespeople.
I used to hold sales meetings once a week, but now I'm holding one every morning.
I've got those people really enthusiastic.
I guess once they saw some life in me, they were ready to push harder, too.
They were just waiting for me to start things moving again.
things sure are working out okay.
Last week my sales were well ahead of a year ago and much better than the store's average." Oh,
by the way," he continued, I want to tell you some other good news.
I got two job offers since we talked.
Naturally I'm glad, but I've turned them both down since everything is looking good here again.
When we face tough problems, we stay mired in the mud until we take action.
Hope is a start, but hope needs action to win victories.