One, get a balanced view of the other fellow.
Keep these two points in mind when dealing with people.
First, the other fellow is important.
Emphatically, he is important.
Every human being is.
But remember this also.
You are important too.
So when you meet another person, make it a policy to think, we're just two important people sitting down to discuss something of mutual interest and benefit.
A couple of months ago, a business executive phoned to tell me he had just employed a young man whom I had recommended to him shortly before.
Do you know what really sold me on that fellow, asked my friend.
What, I asked.
Well, it was the way he handled himself.
Most job applicants, when they walk in here, are half scared.
They give me all the answers they think I want to hear.
In a way, most job applicants are a little like beggars.
They'll accept anything, and they aren't particular.
But G handled himself differently.
He respected me, but what's just as important, he respects himself.
What's more, he asked me as many questions as I asked him.
He's no mouse.
He's a real man, and he's going to do all right.
This mutually important attitude helps you keep the situation balanced.