We spent the next two hours not talking about the merits of different kinds of jobs,
but rather discussing how to set goals.
FB learned, I believe, the most important lesson in career planning.
Before you start out, know where you want to go.
Like the progressive corporation, plan ahead.
You are, in a sense, a business unit.
Your talents, skills, and abilities are your products.
You want to develop your products so they command the highest possible price.
Forward planning will do it.
Here are two steps that will help.
First, visualize your future in terms of three departments, work, home, and social.
Dividing your life this way keeps you from becoming confused, prevents conflicts, helps you look at the whole picture.
Second, demand of yourself clear, precise answers to these questions.
What do I want to accomplish with my life?
What do I want to be?
And what does it take to satisfy me?
Using this planning guide will help.
An image of me ten years from now.
Ten Years Planning Guide.
A. Work Department.
Ten years from now.
1.
What income level do I want to attain?
2.
What level of responsibility do I seek?
3.
How much authority do I want to command?
4.
What prestige do I expect to gain from my work?
B, home department, 10 years from now.
One, what kind of standard of living do I want to provide for my family and myself?
Two, what kind of house do I want to live in?
Three, what kind of vacations do I want to take?
Four, what financial support do I want to give my children in their early adult years?
C, social department, 10 years from now.
1.
What kinds of friends do I want to have?
2.
What social groups do I want to join?
3.
What community leadership positions would I like to hold?
4.
What worthwhile causes do I want to champion?
A few years ago, my young son insisted the two of us build a doghouse for Peanut,
an intelligent pup of dubious pedigree and my son's pride and joy.
His persistence and enthusiasm won, so we proceeded to build a home Peanut could call her own.