Cecil now realized that how old we are is not important.
It's one's attitude toward age that makes it a blessing or a barricade.
Curing yourself of age excusitis often opens doors to opportunities that you thought were locked tight.
A relative of mine spent years doing many different things, selling, operating his own business,
working in a bank, but he never quite found what he really wanted to do most.
Finally, he concluded that the one thing he wanted more than anything else was to be a minister.
But when he thought about it, he found he was too old.
After all, he was forty-five, had three young children, and little money.
But fortunately, he mustered all of his strength and told himself, Forty-five or not,
I'm going to be a minister.
With tons of faith but little else, he enrolled in a five-year ministerial training program in Wisconsin.
Five years later, he was ordained as a minister and settled down with a fine congregation in Illinois.
Old?
Of course not.
He still has twenty years of productive life ahead of him.
I talked with this man not long ago, and he said to me,
You know, if I had not made that great decision when I was forty-five,
I would have spent the rest of my life growing old and bitter.
Now I feel every bit as young as I did twenty-five years ago.
And he almost looked it, too.
When you lick age-excusitis, the natural result is to gain the optimism of youth and feel of youth.
When you beat down your fears of age limitations, you add years to your life, as well as success.
A former university colleague of mine provides an interesting angle on how age-excusitis was defeated.
Bill was graduated from Harvard in the 1920s.
After 24 years in the stock brokerage business, during which time he made a modest fortune,
Bill decided he wanted to become a college professor.
Bill's friends warned him that he would overtax himself in the rugged learning program ahead.
But Bill was determined to reach his goal and enrolled in the University of Illinois at the age of 51.
At fifty-five, he had earned his degree.
Today, Bill is chairman of the Department of Economics at a fine liberal arts college.
He's happy, too.
He smiles when he says, I've got almost a third of my good years left.
Old age is a failure disease.
Defeat it by refusing to let it hold you back.