2.
Be a comfortable person, so there is no strain in being with you.
Be an old-shoe kind of individual.
3.
Acquire the quality of relaxed, easy-going, so that things do not ruffle you.
4.
Don't be egotistical.
Guard against the impression that you know it all.
5.
Cultivate the quality of being interesting, so people will get something of value from their association with you.
6.
Study to get the scratchy elements out of your personality, even those of which you may be unconscious.
7.
Sincerely attempt to heal, on an honest basis, every misunderstanding you have had or now have.
Drain off your grievances.
8.
Practice liking people until you learn to do so genuinely.
9.
Never miss an opportunity to say a word of congratulation upon anyone's achievement or express sympathy in sorrow or disappointment.
10.
Give spiritual strength to people, and they will give genuine affection to you.
Living these ten simple but tremendously powerful like-people rules makes President Johnson easier to vote for,
easier to support in Congress.
Living these ten rules makes President Johnson easier to lift.
Listen to these rules again.
Notice that there's no get-even philosophy here.
There's no let-the-other-fellow-come-to-me to patch up differences.
There's no I-know-it-all-other-people-are-stupid.
Big people, those on top in industry, the arts, sciences, and politics, are human, warm.
They specialize in being likable.
But don't try to buy friendship.
It's not for sale.
Giving gifts is a wonderful practice if the gift is backed up with genuine sincerity,
a liking to give, and liking for the person to whom it is given.
But without real sincerity, the gift is often regarded as nothing more than a payoff or a bribe.
Last year, just a few days before Christmas, I was in the office of the president of a medium-sized trucking firm.