Action feeds and strengthens confidence.
Inaction, in all forms, feeds fear.
To fight fear, act.
To increase fear, wait, put off, postpone.
Once I heard a young paratrooper instructor explain, the jump really isn't so bad.
It's the waiting to jump that gets a fellow.
On the trip to the jump site, I always try to make the time pass quickly for the men.
It's happened more than once that a trainee thought too much about what may happen and panicked.
If we can't get him to jump the next trip, he's through as a paratrooper.
Instead of gaining confidence, the longer he postpones the jump, the more scared he gets.
Waiting even makes the experts nervous.
Time magazine reported that Edward R. Murrow, the nation's top newscaster, perspires and is on edge just before he telecasts.
But once he's in action, fear disappears.
Many veteran actors experience the same sensation.
They agree that the only cure for stage fright is action.
Getting right out there before the audience is the cure for dread, worry, fear.
Action Cures Fear One evening, we were visiting in a friend's home when their five-year-old boy,
who had been put to bed thirty minutes before, cried out.
The youngster had been overstimulated by a science fiction film and was afraid the little green monsters were going to enter his room and kidnap him.
I was intrigued by the way the boy's father relieved the lad's worry.
He didn't say, don't worry son, nothing is going to get you, go back to sleep.
Instead, he took positive action.
He made quite a show for the boy by inspecting the windows to be sure they were tight.
Then he picked up one of the boy's plastic guns and put it on a table beside his bed and said,
Billy, here's a gun for you just in case.
The little fellow had a look of complete relief.
Four minutes later, he was fast asleep.
Many physicians give neutral, harmless medication to people who insist they've got to have something to make them sleep.
To lots of folks, the act of swallowing a pill, even though unknown to them the pill has no medication,
makes them feel better.
It's perfectly natural to experience fear in one of many forms, but the usual methods of combating it simply don't work.
I've been with many salesmen who tried to cure fear, which creeps up on even the most experienced of them at times,
by going around the block a few times or drinking extra coffee.
But these things don't get results.
The way to combat that kind of fear, yes, any kind of fear, yes, any kind of fear, is action.
Dread making a certain phone call?
Make it, and dread disappears.
Put it off, and it will get harder and harder to make.
Dread going to a doctor for a checkup?
Go, and your worry vanishes.
Chances are nothing serious is wrong with you, and if there is, you know where you stand.
Put off that checkup, and you feed your fear until it may grow so strong that you actually are sick.
Dread discussing a problem with your superior?
Discuss it and discover how those worries are conquered.
Build confidence.
Destroy fear through action.