Joe Salesman, Joe Executive, Joe Professional Worker, Josephine Housewife.
They all often try to build strength and get ready with office chats,
coffee breaks, sharpening pencils, reading, personal business, getting the desk cleared off, TV,
and dozens of other little escape devices.
But there's a way to break this habit.
Tell yourself, I'm in condition right now to begin.
I can't gain a thing by putting it off.
I'll use the get ready time and energy to get going instead.
What we want more than anything else in our business, an executive in a machine tool company said in an address to a group of sales executives,
is more people who get sound ideas and then push them through.
There's not one job in our production and marketing setup that can't be done better, a lot better.
I don't want to infer that we're not doing a good job now.
We are.