Conversation generosity is the easiest, simplest, and surest way there is to win a friend.
The second benefit of conversation generosity, learning more about other people, is important too.
As we said in Chapter 1, people are what we study in our success lab.
The more we can learn from them, their thought processes, their strong and weak points,
why they do what and as they do, the better equipped we are to influence them effectively in the way that we want.
Let me illustrate.
A large New York advertising agency, like all advertising agencies, specializes, of course,
in telling the public why it should buy the products it advertises.
But this agency does something else, too.
It requires its copywriters to spend one week each year behind counters so they can listen to what the people say about the products they promote.
Listening provides the clues these copywriters need to write better, more effective ads.
Many progressive businesses conduct so-called terminal interviews with employees who are leaving.
The reason is not to sell the employees on staying with the company,
but to find out why he is quitting.
Then the company can bring about improvements in its employee relations.
Listening pays off.
Listening pays off for the salesman, too.
Often people think of a good salesman as a good talker or a fast talker.
Sales managers, however, are not as impressed by a good talker as they are by a good listener,
a fellow who can ask questions and get desired answers.
Don't be a conversation hog.
Listen, win friends, and learn.
Courtesy, practiced in every relationship with another person, is the finest tranquilizer you can use.
No commercial preparation is one-tenth as effective in relaxing you as doing little things for other people.
Thinking right toward people removes frustrations and stress.
When you boil it all down, the big cause of stress is negative feelings toward other people.
So think positive toward people and discover how wonderful, really wonderful, this world is.
The real test for thinking right toward people comes when things don't go exactly the way we want.
How do you think when you're passed up for a promotion or when you fail to win an office in a club you belong to?
or when you're criticized for the job you've done.
Remember this, how you think when you lose determines how long it will be until you win.
The answer for thinking right toward people when things don't go exactly our way comes from Benjamin Fairless,
one of the century's most outstanding persons.
Mr. Fairless, who rose from very modest circumstances to become Chief Executive of the United States Steel Corporation,
said this, quoted in Life magazine, October 15, 1956.
It depends on how you look at things.
For example, I never had a teacher I hated.
Naturally, I was disciplined just like every other pupil, but I always figured it was my fault that the discipline was necessary.
I have also liked every boss I ever had.
I always tried to please him and do more than he expected if I possibly could, nevertheless.
I have had some disappointments, times when I greatly wanted a promotion and somebody else got it.
But I never figured that I was the victim of office politics or prejudice or bad judgment on the boss's part.
Instead of sulking or quitting in a huff, I reasoned things out.
Obviously the other fellow deserved the promotion more than I did.
What could I do to make myself deserving of the next opportunity?
At the same time, I never got angry with myself for losing, and never wasted any time berating myself.
Remember Benjamin Fairless when things go wrong.
Just do two things.
One, ask yourself, what can I do to make myself more deserving of the next opportunity?
Two, don't waste time and energy being discouraged.
Don't berate yourself.
Plan to win next time.
In a capsule, put these principles to work.
1.
Make yourself lighter to lift.
Be likable.
Practice being the kind of person people like.
This wins their support and puts fuel in your success-building program.
2.
Take the initiative in building friendships.
Introduce yourself to others at every opportunity.
Make sure you get the other person's name straight, and make certain he gets your name straight, too.
Drop a personal note to your new friends you want to get to know better.
3.
Accept human differences and limitations.
Don't expect anyone to be perfect.
Remember, the other person has a right to be different.
And don't be a reformer.
4.
Tune in to Channel P, the Good Thoughts Station.
Find qualities to like and admire in a person, not things to dislike.
And don't let others prejudice your thinking about a third person.
Think positive thoughts toward people and get positive results.
5.
Practice conversation generosity.
Be like successful people.
Encourage others to talk.
Let the other person talk to you about his views, his opinions, his accomplishments.
6.
Practice courtesy all the time.
It makes other people feel better.
It makes you feel better, too.
7.
Don't blame others when you receive a setback.
Remember, how you think when you lose determines how long it will be until you win.