you'd develop a $600 million business in producing greenhouses, and perhaps a $250 million industry supplying plants and seeds.
The only difficulty with this exercise is that the group, ten minutes before completely cold about greenhouses,
now is so enthusiastic they don't want to move on to the next subject.
Use the dig into a deeper technique to develop enthusiasm toward other people.
Find out all you can about another person, what he does, his family,
his background, his ideas and ambitions, and you'll find your interest in and enthusiasm about him mounting.
Keep digging and you're certain to find some common interests.
Keep digging and you'll eventually discover a fascinating person.
The dig-into-it-deeper technique works also in developing enthusiasm toward new places.
Several years ago, some young friends of mine decided to move from Detroit to a small town in mid-Florida.
They sold their home, closed out their business connections, said goodbye to their friends, and were gone.
Six weeks later they were back in Detroit.
The reason had nothing to do with employment.
Rather, as they put it, we just couldn't stand living in a small town.
Besides, all our friends are in Detroit.
We just had to come back.
In later conversations with these people, I learned the real reason why they didn't like the small Florida city.
During their short stay there, they had taken only a surface view of the community,
its history, its plans for the future, its people.
They moved their bodies to Florida, but left their minds in Detroit.
I've talked with dozens of executives, engineers, and salesmen who have developed career trouble because their companies want to move them to another location,
but they don't want to go.
I just can't see moving to Chicago, or San Francisco, or Atlanta,
or New York, or Miami, is a remark spoken many times a day.
There's one way to build enthusiasm toward a new location.
Simply resolve to dig into the new community.
Learn all you can about it.
Mix with the people.
Make yourself feel and think like a community citizen from the very first day.
Do this, and you'll be enthusiastic about your new environment.
Today, millions of Americans invest in corporate securities.
But there are many millions more who have no interest at all in the stock market.
That's because they are people who have not familiarized themselves with what the securities market is,
how it operates, the day-to-day romance of American business.
To get enthusiasm about anything—people, places, things—dig into it deeper.
Dig into it deeper, and you'll develop enthusiasm.