If Channel N cuts in, say, Stop, then switch channels.
To make the switch, all you must do is think of one positive quality about the individual.
In true chain reaction style, this one thought will lead to another and another, and you will be glad.
When you are alone, you and only you can decide whether you will listen to Channel P or Channel N. But when you are talking with someone else,
that person has a measure of control over how you think.
We must remember that most people do not understand the concepts of thinking right toward people.
So it's a very common experience for people to come rushing to you,
just aching to say something negative about a person you both know.
A co-worker wants to tell you about the objectionable qualities of another employee.
A neighbor wants to let you know the domestic problems of another neighbor.
or a customer wants to itemize the faults of his competitor, whom you will call on next.
Thoughts breed like thoughts.
There is real danger that if you listen to negative comments about another person,
you too will go negative toward that person.
In fact, if you are not on guard, you may actually find yourself adding fuel to the fire with,
yes, and that's not all, did you hear?
type of comment.
These things backfire.
Boomerang.
There are two ways to prevent others from switching us from Channel P to Channel N. One way is to switch topics as quickly and quietly as possible with some remark like,
Pardon me, John, but while I think of it, I've been meaning to ask you.
A second way is to excuse yourself with a Sorry, John, I'm late now,
or I have a deadline to meet.
Will you excuse me?
Make a forceful promise to yourself.
Refuse to let others prejudice your thinking.
Stay tuned to Channel P. Once you've mastered the technique of thinking only good thoughts about people,
greater success is guaranteed.
Let me tell you what an unusually successful insurance salesman told me about how thinking good thoughts about people pays off for him.
When I first got in the insurance business, he began, the going was tough, believe me.
At first, it seemed there were about as many competing agents as there were prospects.
And I soon learned what all insurance men know, that nine prospects out of ten firmly believe they don't need any more insurance.
I'm doing well, but let me tell you, it's not because I know a lot about the technical side of insurance.
That's important, don't misunderstand me, but there are men trying to sell insurance who know policies and contracts better than I. In fact,
I know one man who wrote a book about insurance, but he couldn't sell a policy to a man who knew he had only five days to live.
My success, he continued, is based on one thing.
I like, really like the guy I'm selling.
Let me say again, I really like him.
Some of my fellow salesmen try to pretend they like the other fellow, but this won't work.