The following exercises will help.
Practice trading minds exercises.
Situation.
Giving someone work instructions.
For best results, ask yourself, Looking at this from the viewpoint of someone who is new to this,
have I made myself clear?
Situation.
Writing an advertisement.
For best results, ask yourself, If I were a typical prospective buyer, how would I react to this ad?
Situation, telephone manners.
For best results, ask yourself, if I were the other person, what would I think of my telephone voice and manners?
Situation, gift.
For best results, ask yourself, is this gift something I would like or is it something he will like?
Often there is an enormous difference.
Situation, the way I give orders.
For best results, ask yourself, would I like to carry out orders if they were given to me the way I give them to others?
Situation, child discipline.
For best results, ask yourself, if I were the child, considering his age,
experience, and emotions, how would I react to this discipline?
Situation, my appearance.
For best results, ask yourself, what would I think of my superior if he were dressed like me?
Situation, preparing a speech.
For best results, ask yourself, considering the background and interests of the audience, what would I think of this remark?
situation, entertainment.
For best results, ask yourself, if I were my guests, what kinds of food,
music, and entertainment would I like best?
Put the trading minds principle to work for you.
1.
Consider the other person's situation.
Put yourself in his shoes, so to speak.
Remember, his interests, income, intelligence, and background may differ considerably from yours.
2.
Now ask yourself, if I were in his situation, how would I react to this?
Whatever it is you want him to do.
3.
Then take the action that would move you if you were the other person.
Leadership rule number two.
Think.