Practice these three procedures to help yourself think about trivialities.
1.
Keep your eyes focused on the big objective.
Many times, we're like the salesman who, failing to make the sale,
reports to his manager, yes, but I sure convinced the customer he was wrong.
In selling, the big objective is winning sales, not arguments.
In marriage, the big objective is peace, happiness, tranquility, not winning quarrels or saying, I could have told you so.
In working with employees, the big objective is developing their full potential, not making issues out of their minor errors.
In living with neighbors, the big objective is mutual respect and friendship, not seeing if you can have their dog impounded because once in a while it barks at night.
Paraphrasing some military lingo, it is much better to lose a battle and win the war than to win a battle and lose the war.
Resolve to keep your eyes on the big ball.
2.
Ask, is it really important?
Before becoming negatively excited, just ask yourself, is it important enough for me to get all worked up about?
There is no better way to avoid frustration over petty matters than to use this medicine.
At least 90% of quarrels and feuds would never take place if we just faced troublesome situations with,
is this really important?
Three, don't fall into the triviality trap.
In making speeches, solving problems, counseling employees, think of those things that really matter, things that make the difference.
Don't become submerged under surface issues.
Concentrate on important things.