Now, there's a way I check attitudes and what they mean to job success.
All recommendations for promotions, pay increases, and special privileges are channeled to me by the employee's immediate supervisor.
Almost invariably, it's a Group A person who was recommended.
And again, almost without exception, problems come from the Group B category.
The biggest challenge in my job, he said, is to try and help people move from Group B to Group A. It's not easy,
though, because until a person thinks his job is important and thinks positively about it,
he can't be helped.
This is concrete evidence that you are what you think you are, what your thought power directs you to become.
Think you're weak.
Think you lack what it takes.
Think you will lose.
Think you are second class.
Think this way, and you are doomed to mediocrity.
But think instead, I am important.
I do have what it takes.
I am a first class performer.
My work is important.
Think this way, and you're headed straight to success.
The key to winning what you want lies in thinking positively toward yourself.
The only real basis other people have for judging your abilities is your actions,
and your actions are controlled by your thoughts.
You are what you think you are.
Wear the shoes of a supervisor for a few moments and ask yourself which person you would recommend for a raise or a promotion.
1.
The secretary who, when the executive is out of the office, spends her time reading magazines,
or the secretary who uses such time to do the many little things that help the executive to accomplish more when he returns.
2.
The employee who says, oh, well, I can always get another job.
If they don't like the way I do my work, I'll just quit.
Or the employee who views criticism constructively and sincerely tries to do higher quality work.
3.
The salesman who tells a customer, oh, I just do what they tell me to do.
They said come out and see if you need anything.
Or the salesman who says, Mr. Brown, I'm here to help you.
Four.
The foreman who says to an employee, to tell you the truth, I don't like my job much.
Those guys up top give me a pain in the neck.
I don't know what they're talking about half the time.
Or the supervisor who says, you've got to expect some unpleasantness on any job.
But let me assure you, the men in the front office are on the ball.
They'll do right by us.
Isn't it obvious why many people stay at one level all their lives?
Their thinking alone keeps them there.
An advertising executive once told me about his agency's informal training to break in new inexperienced men.