YJM lives in a new home.
In every big decision, the mind battles with itself, to act or not to act,
to do or not to do.
Here's how one young fellow elected to act and reaped big rewards.
J.M.'s situation is similar to that of a million other young men.
He is in his twenties, has a wife and child, and still has only a modest income.
Mr. and Mrs. J.M. lived in a small apartment.
Both wanted a new home.
They wanted the advantage of more space, cleaner surroundings, a place for the youngster to play,
and a chance to build up equity in their own property.
But there was a hitch to buying a new home, the down payment.
One day, as J.M. was writing next month's rent check, he became very disgusted with himself.
He observed that the rent payment was as much as monthly payments on a new home.
J.M. called his wife and said, How would you like to buy a new home next week?
What's got into you?
she asked.
Why make jokes?
You know we can't.
We haven't even got the money for the down payment.
but J.M. was determined.
There are hundreds of thousands of couples like us who are going to buy a new home someday,
but only about half of them ever do.
Something always comes up to stop them.
We're going to buy a home.
I don't know yet how we'll raise the down payment, but we will.
Well, the next week, they found a house they both liked, quite unpretentious but nice, for $1,200 down.
Now, the obstacle was to find a way to raise $1,200.
J.M. knew he couldn't borrow it through the usual channels, for this would encumber his credit so that he couldn't get a mortgage for the sale price.
Where there's a will, there's always a way.
Suddenly, J.M. got a brainstorm.
Why not contact the builder and work out a private loan arrangement for $1,200?
This J.M. did.
At first, the builder was cold to the idea, but J.M. persisted.
Finally, it was agreed.