Think about the grape example the next time you're selling yourself.
Properly packaged, you have a better chance to make the sale, and at a higher price.
The point is, the better you are packaged, the more public acceptance you will receive.
Tomorrow, watch who is shown the most respect and courtesy in restaurants, on buses,
in crowded lobbies, in stores, and at work.
People look at another person, make a quick and often subconscious appraisal, and then treat them accordingly.
We look at some people and respond with the, hey, Mac, attitude.
We look at others and respond with the, yes, sir, feeling.
Yes, a person's appearance definitely talks.
The well-dressed person's appearance says positive things.
It tells people, here is an important person, intelligent, prosperous, and dependable.
This man can be looked up to, admired, trusted.
He respects himself, and I respect him.
The shabby-looking fellow's appearance says negative things.
It says, here is a person who isn't doing well.
He's careless, inefficient, unimportant.
He's just an average person.
He deserves no special consideration.
He's used to being pushed around.
When I stress respect your appearance in training programs, almost always I am asked the question,
I'm sold, appearance is important, but how do you expect me to afford the kind of clothing that really makes me feel right and that causes others to look up to me?
That question puzzles many people.
It plagued me for a long time.
But the answer is really a simple one.
Pay twice as much and buy half as many.
Commit this answer to memory, then practice it.
Apply it to hats, suits, shoes, socks, coats, everything you wear.
Insofar as appearance is concerned, quality is far more important than quantity.
When you practice this principle, you'll find that both your respect for yourself and the respect of others for you will zoom upward,
and you'll find you're actually ahead money-wise when you pay twice as much and buy half as many,
because 1.
Your garments will last more than twice as long because they are more than twice as good,
and as a rule they will show quality as long as they last.
2.
What you buy will stay in style longer.
Better clothing always does.
3.
You'll get better advice.
Merchants selling $200 suits are usually much more interested in helping you find the garment that is just right for you than are merchants selling $100 suits.
Remember, your appearance talks to you and it talks to others.
Make certain it says, here is a person who has self-respect.
He's important.
Treat him that way.
You owe it to others, but more important, you owe it to yourself to look your best.
You are what you think you are.
If your appearance makes you think you're inferior, you are inferior.
If it makes you think small, you are small.
Look your best and you will think and act your best.
Think your work is important.