The second thing I'd recommend is that you read Dr. Schindler's great book,
How to Live 365 Days a Year.
Dr. Schindler shows in this book that three out of every four hospital beds are occupied by people who have EII,
Emotionally Induced Illness.
Imagine, three out of four people who are sick right now would be well if they learned how to handle their emotions.
Read Dr. Schindler's book and develop your program for emotions management.
Third, I'd resolve to live until I die.
I went on to explain to this troubled fellow some sound advice I received many years ago from a lawyer friend who had an arrested case of tuberculosis.
This friend knew he would have to live a regulated life, but this hasn't stopped him from practicing law,
rearing a fine family, and really enjoying life.
My friend, who now is seventy-eight years old, expresses his philosophy in these words.
I'm going to live until I die, and I'm not going to get life and death confused.
While I'm on this earth, I'm going to live.
Why be only half alive?
Every minute a person spends worrying about dying is just one minute that fellow might as well have been dead.
I had to leave at that point, because I had to be on a certain plane for Detroit.
On the plane, the second but much more pleasant experience occurred.
After the noise of the take-off, I heard a ticking sound.
Rather startled, I glanced at the fellow sitting beside me, for the sound seemed to be coming from him.
He smiled a big smile and said, Oh, it's not a bomb.
It's just my heart.
I was obviously surprised, so he proceeded to tell me what had happened.
Just twenty-one days before, he had undergone an operation that involved putting a plastic valve into his heart.
The ticking sound, he explained, would continue for several months, until new tissue had grown over the artificial valve.
I asked him what he was going to do.
Oh, he said, I've got big plans.
I'm going to study law when I get back to Minnesota.
Someday I hope to be in government work.
The doctors tell me I must take it easy for a few months,
but after that I'll be like new.
There you have two ways of meeting health problems.
The first fellow, not even sure he had anything organically wrong with him,
was worried, depressed, on the road to defeat, wanting somebody to second his motion that he couldn't go forward.
The second individual, after undergoing one of the most difficult of operations, was optimistic, eager to do something.
The difference lay in how they thought toward health.
I've had some very direct experience with health excusitis.