Doctors use setbacks to pave the way to better health and longer life.
Often, when a patient dies for an uncertain reason, doctors perform a post-mortem to find out why.
In this way, they learn more about the functioning of the human body, and lives of other people are saved.
A sales executive friend of mine devotes one entire sales meeting a month to helping his salesman discover why they lost important sales.
The lost sale is reconstructed and carefully examined.
In this way, the salesman learns how to avoid losing similar sales in the future.
The football coach who wins more games than he loses goes over the details of each game with his team to point out their mistakes.
Some coaches have movies made of each game so the team can literally see its bad moves.
The purpose?
To play the next game better.
CAA officials, successful sales executives, physicians, football coaches, and professionals in every field follow this success principle.
Salvage something from every setback.
When a setback hits us personally, our first impulse is often to become so emotionally upset that we fail to learn the lesson.
Professors know that a student's reaction to a failing grade provides a clue to his success potential.
When I was a professor at Wayne State University in Detroit some years ago,
I had no choice but to turn in a failing grade for a graduating senior.
This was a real blow to the student.
He had already made graduation plans, and canceling was embarrassing.
He was left with two alternatives, retake and pass the course, and receive his degree at a later graduation,
or quit school without earning a degree.
I expected that the student would be disappointed, perhaps even somewhat belligerent, when he learned of his setback.
I was right.
After I explained that his work was far below passing standards, the student admitted that he hadn't put forth a serious effort in the course.
But, he continued, my past record is at least average.
Can't you consider that?
I pointed out that I could not, because we measure performance one course at a time.
I added that rigid academic codes prohibited changing grades for any reason other than an honest mistake on the part of the professor.
Then the student, realizing that all avenues toward a grade change were closed, became quite angry.
Professor, he said, I could name 50 people in this city who've succeeded in a big way without taking this course or even knowing about it.
What's so blasted important about this course?
Why should a few bad marks in one course keep me from getting my degree?
Thank God, he added, they don't look at things on the outside like you professors do.
After that remark, I paused for about 45 seconds.
I've learned that when you've been sniped at, one fine way to prevent a war of words is to take a long pause before answering.