Conquer luck excusitis in two ways.
Number one, accept the law of cause and effect.
Take a second look at what appears to be someone's good luck.
You'll find that not luck, but preparation, planning, and success-producing thinking preceded his good fortune.
Take a second look at what appears to be someone's bad luck.
Look, and you'll discover certain specific reasons.
Mr. Success receives a setback.
He learns and profits.
But when Mr. Mediocre loses, he fails to learn.
Number two, don't be a wishful thinker.
Don't waste your mental muscles dreaming of an effortless way to win success.
We don't become successful simply through luck.
Success comes from doing those things and mastering those principles that produce success.
Don't count on luck for promotions, victories, the good things in life.
Luck simply isn't designed to deliver these good things.
Instead, just concentrate on developing those qualities in yourself that will make you a winner.