Not all conversation is gossip.
Bull sessions, shop talk, and just batting the breeze are necessary at times.
They serve a good purpose when they are constructive.
You can test your proneness to be a gossiper by taking this test.
1.
Do I spread rumors about other people?
2.
Do I always have good things to say about others?
3.
Do I like to hear reports of a scandal?
4.
Do I judge others only on the basis of facts?
5.
Do I encourage others to bring their rumors to me?
6.
Do I proceed my conversations with, don't tell anybody?
7.
Do I keep confidential information confidential?
8.
Do I feel guilty about what I say concerning other people?
The right answers are obvious.
Meditate on this thought for just a moment.
Taking an axe and chopping your neighbor's furniture to pieces won't make your furniture look one bit better.
And using verbal axes and grenades on another person doesn't do one thing to make you a better you or me a better me.
Go first class.
That is an excellent rule to follow in everything you do, including the goods and services you buy.
Once, to prove the unconditional truth of the go-first-class thinking, I asked a group of trainees to give one example of how they had been penny-wise and pound-foolish.
Here are some sample replies.
I bought a low-priced suit from an offbeat retailer.
Thought I got a bargain, but the suit was simply no good.
My car needed a new automatic transmission.
Took it to an alley garage that agreed to do the job for $25 less than an authorized dealer.
The new transmission lasted 1,800 miles, and the garage wouldn't make it right.
For months, I ate at a real greasy spoon trying to save money.
The place wasn't clean, the food wasn't good, the service, well,
you couldn't call it that, and the clientele was a bunch of downed healers.
One day, a friend persuaded me to join him for lunch at one of the best restaurants in town.
He ordered the businessman's lunch, so I did too.
I was amazed at what I got.
Good food, good service, good atmosphere, and for just a little more than I had been paying at the Greasy Spoon.