Five or six years ago, a very capable professor told me of his plans for writing a book,
a biography of a controversial personality of a few decades ago.
His ideas were more than interesting, they were alive, fascinating.
The professor knew what he wanted to say, and he had the skill and energy to say it.
The project was destined to reward him with much inner satisfaction, prestige, and money.
Last spring I saw my friend again, and I innocently asked him whether the book was about finished.
This was a blunder.
It opened up an old wound.
No, he hadn't written the book.
He struggled with himself for a moment, as if he were debating with himself whether to explain why.
Finally, he explained that he had been too busy.
He had more responsibilities and just couldn't get to it.
In reality, what the professor had done was to bury the idea deep in his mental graveyard.
He let his mind grow negative thoughts.
He visualized the tremendous work and sacrifices that would be involved.
He saw all sorts of reasons why the project would fail.
Ideas are important, let's make no mistake about that.
We must have ideas to create and improve anything.
Success shuns the man who lacks ideas.
But let's make no mistakes about this point either.
Ideas in themselves are not enough.
That idea for getting more business, for simplifying work procedures, is of value only when it is acted upon.
Every day, thousands of people bury good ideas because they are afraid to act on them.
And afterward, the ghosts of those ideas come back to haunt them.
Put these two thoughts deep in your mind.
First, give your ideas value by acting on them.
Regardless of how good the idea, unless you do something with it, you gain nothing.
Second, act on your ideas and gain mind tranquility.
Someone once said that the saddest words of tongue or pen are these, it might have been.
Every day you hear someone saying something like, had I gone into business seven years ago,
I'd sure be sitting pretty now.
Or, I had a hunch it would work out like that.
I wish I had done something about it.
A good idea, if not acted upon, produces terrible psychological pain.
But a good idea acted upon brings enormous mental satisfaction.
Got a good idea?
Then do something about it.
Use action to cure fear and gain confidence.
Here's something to remember.