but the most efficient sources of education for most people are nearby colleges and universities.
Education is their business.
If you haven't been to college lately, you're in for some wonderful surprises.
You'll be pleased at the wide course offerings available.
You'll be even more pleased to discover who goes to school after work.
Not the phonies, but rather really promising persons, many of whom already hold very responsible positions.
In one evening class of twenty-five persons I conducted recently, there were an owner of a retail chain of twelve stores,
two buyers for a national food chain, four graduate engineers, an Air Force colonel,
and several others of similar status.
Many people earn degrees in evening programs these days, but the degree, which in the final analysis is only a piece of paper,
is not their primary motivation.
They are going to school to build their minds, which is a sure way to invest in a better future.
And make no mistake about this, education is a real bargain.
A moderate investment will keep you in school one night each week for a full year.
Compute the cost as a percentage of your gross income, and then ask yourself,
isn't my future worth this small investment?
Why not make an investment decision right now?
Call it school, one night a week for life.
It will keep you progressive, young, alert.
It will keep you abreast of your areas of interest, and it will surround you with other people who also are going places.
2.
Invest in idea starters.