For about 15 years, I've been close to a fellow I'll call Bob W. Bob is in his late 50s.
He came up the hard way.
With a hit-or-miss education and no money, Bob found himself out of work in 1931.
But he's always been a scrambler.
Not one to be idle, Bob started an upholstery shop in his garage.
Thanks to his untiring efforts, the business grew, and today it's a modern furniture manufacturing plant with over 300 employees.
Today, Bob is a millionaire.
Money and material things have ceased to be a concern.
But Bob is rich in other ways, too.
He's a millionaire in friends, contentment, and satisfaction.
Of Bob's many fine qualities, his tremendous desire to help other people stands out.
Bob is human, and he's a specialist in treating others the way human beings want to be treated.
One day, Bob and I were discussing the matter of criticizing people.
Bob's human way of doing it is a master formula.
Here's the way he put it.
I don't think you could find anybody who would say I'm a softie or a weakling.
I run a business.
When something isn't going right, I fix it.
But it's the way I fix it that's important.
If employees are doing something wrong or are making a mistake, I am doubly careful not to hurt their feelings and make them feel small or embarrassed.
I just use four simple steps.
First, I talk to them privately.
Second, I praise them for what they are doing well.
Third, I point out the one thing at the moment that they could do better and I help them find the way.
Fourth, I praise them again on their good points.
And this four-step formula works.
When I do it this way, people thank me because I've found that's exactly the way they like it.
When they walk out of this office, they have been reminded that they are not only pretty good,
they can be even better.
I've been betting on people all my life, Bob says, and the better I treat them,
the more good things happen to me.
I honestly don't plan it that way.
That's just the way it works out.
Let me give you an example.
Back about, oh, five or six years ago, one of the production men came to work drunk.
Pretty soon there was a commotion in the plant.
It seems this fellow had taken a five-gallon can of lacquer and was splashing it all over the place.
Well, the other workmen took the lacquer away from him, and the plant superintendent escorted him out.
I walked outside and found him sitting against the building in a kind of stupor.
I helped him up, put him in my car and took him to his home.
His wife was frantic.
I tried to reassure her that everything would be all right.
Oh, but you don't understand, she said.