2.
But you've got to have brains to succeed.
Intelligence excusitis, or I lack brains, is common.
In fact, it's so common that perhaps as many as 95% of the people around us have it in varying degrees.
Unlike most other types of excusitis, people suffering from this particular type of the malady suffer in silence.
Not many people will admit openly that they think they lack adequate intelligence.
Rather, they feel it deep down inside.
Most of us make two basic errors with respect to intelligence.
One, we underestimate our own brain power.
Two, we overestimate the other fellow's brain power.
Because of these errors, many people sell themselves short.
They fail to tackle challenging situations because it takes a brain.
But along comes the fellow who isn't concerned about intelligence, and he gets the job.
What really matters is not how much intelligence you have, but how you use what you do have.
The thinking that guides your intelligence is much more important than the quantity of your brain power.
Let me repeat, for this is vitally important.
The thinking that guides your intelligence is much more important than how much intelligence you may have.
In answering the question, Should your child be a scientist?
, Dr. Edward Teller, one of the nation's foremost physicists, said, A child does not need a lightning-fast mind to be a scientist.
nor does he need a miraculous memory, nor is it necessary that he get very high grades in school.
The only point that counts is that the child have a high degree of interest in science.
Interest, enthusiasm, is the critical factor even in science.
With a positive, optimistic, and cooperative attitude, a person with an IQ of 100 will earn more money,
win more respect, and achieve more success than a negative, pessimistic, uncooperative individual with an IQ of 120.
Just enough sense to stick with something—a chore, task, project—until it's completed pays off much better than idle intelligence,
even if idle intelligence be of genius caliber.
for stickability is 95% of ability.