Actually, in these modern times, belief is doing much bigger things than moving mountains.
The most essential element—in fact, the essential element—in our space explorations today is belief that space can be mastered.
Without firm, unwavering belief that man can travel in space, our scientists would not have the courage,
interest, and enthusiasm to proceed.
Belief that cancer can be cured will ultimately produce cures for cancer.
Currently, there is some talk of building a tunnel under the English Channel to connect England with the continent.
Whether this tunnel is ever built depends on whether responsible people believe it can be built.
Belief in great results is the driving force, the power behind all great books, plays, scientific discoveries.
Belief in success is behind every successful business, church, and political organization.
Belief in success is the one basic, absolutely essential ingredient of successful people.
Believe, really believe you can succeed, and you will.
Over the years, I've talked with many people who have failed in business ventures and in various careers.
I've heard a lot of reasons and excuses for failure.
Something especially significant unfolds as conversations with failures develop.
In a casual sort of way, the failure drops a remark like, to tell the truth,
I didn't think it would work, or I had my misgivings before I even started out,
or actually, I wasn't too surprised that it didn't work out.
The OK, I'll give it a try, but I don't think it will work attitude produces failures.
Disbelief is negative power.
When the mind disbelieves or doubts, the mind attracts reasons to support the disbelief.
Doubt, disbelief, the subconscious will to fail, the not really wanting to succeed, is responsible for most failures.
Think doubt and fail.
Think victory and succeed.