3.
It's no use.
I'm too old or too young.
Age excusitis, the failure disease of never being the right age, comes in two easily identifiable forms,
the I'm-too-old variety and the I'm-too-young brand.
You've heard hundreds of people of all ages explain their mediocre performance in life something like this.
I'm too old, or too young, to break in now.
I can't do what I want to do or am capable of doing because of my age handicap.
Really, it's surprising how few people feel they are just right, age-wise, and it's unfortunate.
This excuse has closed the door of real opportunity to thousands of individuals.
They think their age is wrong, so they don't even bother to try.
The I'm-too-old variety is the most common form of age excusitis.
This disease is spread in subtle ways.
TV fiction is produced about the big executive who lost his job because of a merger and can't find another because he's too old.
Mr. Executive looks for months to find another job, but he can't,
and in the end, after contemplating suicide for a while, he decides to rationalize that it's nice to be on the shelf.
Plays and magazine articles on the topic, why you are washed up at 40,
are popular, not because they represent true facts, but because they appeal to many worried minds looking for an excuse.
How to handle age excusitis.
Ajexcusitis can be cured.
A few years ago, while I was conducting a sales training program, I discovered a good serum that both cures this disease and vaccinates you so you won't get it in the first place.
In that training program, there was a trainee named Cecil.
Cecil, who was 40, wanted to shift over to set himself up as a manufacturer's representative,
but he thought he was too old.
After all," he explained, I'd have to start from scratch, and I'm too old for that now.
I'm forty.
I'd talked with Cecil several times about his old age problem.
I used the old medicine, you're only as old as you feel, but I found I was getting nowhere.
Too often people retort with, but I do feel old.
And finally, I discovered a method that worked.
One day, after a training session, I tried it on Cecil.
I said, Cecil, when does a man's productive life begin?
He thought a couple of seconds and answered, oh, when he's about twenty, I guess.
Okay, I said.
Now, when does a man's productive life end?
Cecil answered, well, if he stays in good shape and likes his work.
I guess a man is still pretty useful when he's seventy or so." "'All right,' I said.
"'A lot of folks are highly productive after they reach seventy.
But let's agree with what you've just said.
A man's productive years stretch from twenty to seventy.
That's fifty years in between, or half a century.' "'Cecil,' I said.
"'You're forty.
How many years of productive life have you spent?' "'Twenty,' he answered.
And how many have you left?
Thirty, he replied.
In other words, Cecil, you haven't even reached the halfway point.
You've used up only 40% of your productive years.
I looked at Cecil and realized he'd gotten the point.
He was cured of age excusitis.
Cecil saw he still had many opportunity-filled years left.
He switched from thinking, I'm already old, to, I'm still young.