Just as I was about to leave, in marched a delivery man with a gift of liquid refreshment from a local tire-recapping firm.
My friend was obviously provoked, and with a certain amount of chill in his voice,
asked the delivery man to return the gift to its sender.
After the delivery man left, my friend hastened to explain to me.
Don't misunderstand.
I like to give gifts, and I like to get them.
Then he named a number of gifts he had already received from business friends that Christmas.
But, he went on, when the gift is just an attempt to get my business,
an obvious bribe, I don't want it.
I quit doing business with that firm three months ago, because their work isn't what it should be,
and I don't like the employees.
But their salesman keeps on calling.
What burns me, he continued, is that last week that same blank salesman was in here and had the gall to say,
I sure would like to get your business back.
I'm going to tell Santa to be real good to you this year.
If I hadn't sent their booze back, the first thing that so and so would have said to me next time he's in is,
I'll bet you enjoyed our gift, didn't you?
Friendship can't be bought, and when we try, we lose in two ways.
One, we waste money.
Two, we create contempt.
Take the initiative in building friendships.
Leaders always do.
It's easy and natural for us to tell ourselves, let him make the first move.
Let them call us.
Let her speak first.
It's easy too, virtually, to ignore other people.
Yes, it's easy and natural, but it isn't right thinking toward people.
If you follow the rule of letting the other person build the foundation for friendship,
you may not have many friends.
Actually, it's a mark of real leadership to take the lead in getting to know people.
Next time you are in a large group, observe something very significant.