Often we blame luck for our setbacks.
We say, well, that's the way the ball bounces, and let it go at that.
But stop and think.
Balls don't bounce in certain ways for uncertain reasons.
The bounce of a ball is determined by three things, the ball, the way it is thrown,
and the surface it strikes.
Definite physical laws explain the bounce of a ball, not luck.
Suppose the CAA were to issue a report saying, we're sorry the crash occurred,
but folks, that's just the way the ball bounces.
You'd say it's time to get a new CAA.
Or suppose a doctor explained to a relative, I'm awfully sorry, I don't know what happened.
It's just one of those things.
You'd switch doctors when you or another relative became ill.
The that's the way the ball bounces approach teaches us nothing.
We are no better prepared to avoid a duplication of the mistake the next time we face a similar situation.
The football coach who takes Saturday's loss with, well boys, that's the way the ball bounces,
isn't helping his team avoid the same mistakes the next Saturday.
Orville Hubbard, mayor of Dearborn, Michigan for 17 consecutive years, is one of the nation's most colorful and respected urban administrators.
For ten years prior to becoming mayor of Dearborn, Mr. Hubbard could have used the bad luck excuse and stepped out of politics.
Before becoming a perennial winner, Orville Hubbard was unlucky three times in trying to get the nomination for mayor.
Three times he tried to get the nomination for state senator but failed.
Once he was beaten in a race for a congressional nomination.
But Orville Hubbard studied these setbacks.
He regarded them as part of his political education.
And today, he is one of the sharpest, most unbeatable politicians in local government.
Instead of blaming luck, research those setbacks.
If you lose, learn.
Lots of folks go through life explaining their mediocrity with hard luck, tough luck, sour luck, bad luck.
These people are still like children, immature, searching for sympathy.
Without realizing it, they fail to see opportunities to grow bigger, stronger, more self-reliant.
Stop blaming luck.
Blaming luck never got anyone where he wanted to go.
A friend, who is a literary consultant, writer, and critic, chatted with me recently about what it takes to be a successful writer.
A lot of would-be writers, he explained, simply aren't serious about wanting to write.
They try for a little while but give it up when they discover there is real work involved.
I haven't much patience with these people because they're looking for a shortcut and there just isn't one.
But, he went on, I don't want to imply that pure persistence is enough.
The plain truth is, often it isn't.
Just now, I'm working with a fellow who's written 62 short fiction pieces but hasn't sold one.
Obviously, he is persistent in his goal to become a writer.
But this fellow's problem is that he uses the same basic approach in everything he writes.
He's developed a hard format for his stories.