Big thinkers train themselves to see not just what is, but what can be.
Here are four examples to illustrate this point.
1.
What gives real estate value?
A highly successful realtor who specializes in rural property shows what can be done if we train ourselves to see something where little or nothing presently exists.
Most of the rural property around here, my friend began, is run down and not very attractive.
I'm successful because I don't try to sell my prospects a farm as it is.
I develop my entire sales plan around what the farm can be.
Simply telling the prospect, the farm has XX acres of bottom land and XX acres of woods and is XX miles from town,
doesn't stir him up and make him want to buy it.
But when you show him a concrete plan for doing something with the farm, he's just about sold.
Here, let me show you what I mean.
He opened his briefcase and pulled out a file.
This farm," he said, is a new listing with us.
It's like a lot of them.
It's forty-three miles from the center of the metropolitan area, the house is run down,
and the place hasn't been farmed in five years.
Now here's what I've done.
I spent two full days on the place last week, just studying it.
I walked over the place several times.
I looked at neighboring farms.
I studied the location of the farm with respect to existing and planned highways.
I asked myself, what's this farm good for?
I came up with three possibilities.
Here they are.
He showed them to me.
Each plan was neatly typed and looked quite comprehensive.
One plan suggested converting the farm into a riding stable.
The plan showed why the idea was sound.
A growing city, more love for the outdoors, more money for recreation, good roads.
The plan also showed how the farm could support a sizable number of horses,
so that the revenue from the rides would be largely clear.
The whole riding stable idea was very thorough, very convincing.
The plan was so clear and convincing, I could see a dozen couples riding horseback through the trees.
In similar fashion, this enterprising salesman developed a second thorough plan for a tree farm and a third plan for a combination tree and poultry farm.
Now, when I talk with my prospects, I won't have to convince them that the farm is a good buy as it is.
I help them to see a picture of the farm changed into a money-making proposition.
Besides selling more farms and selling them faster, my method of selling the property for what it can be pays off in another way.
I can sell a farm at a higher price than my competitors.
People naturally pay more for acreage and an idea than they do for just acreage.
Because of this, more people want to list their farms with me and my commission on each sale is larger.
The moral is this.
Look at things not as they are, but as they can be.
Visualization adds value to everything.