Oh, but you don't understand, she said.
Mr. W, me, doesn't stand for anyone being drunk on the job.
Jim's lost his job and now what will we do?
I told her Jim wouldn't be dismissed.
She asked how I knew.
The reason I explained is because I'm Mr. W. She almost fainted.
I told her I'd do all I could to help Jim at the plant,
and I hoped she'd do all she could at home, and just have him on the job in the morning.
When I got back to the plant, I went down to Jim's department and spoke to Jim's co-workers.
I told them, you've seen something unpleasant here today, but I want you to forget it.
Jim will be back tomorrow.
Be kind to him.
He's been a good worker for a long time, and we owe it to him to give him another chance.
Jim got back on the ball, and his drinking was never again a problem.
I soon forgot about the incident.
But Jim didn't.
Two years ago, the headquarters of the local union sent some men here to negotiate the contract for the local.
They had some staggering, simply unrealistic demands.
Jim, quiet, meek Jim, suddenly became a leader.
He got busy and reminded the fellows in the plant that they'd always gotten a fair deal from Mr. W.,
and we didn't need outsiders coming to tell us how to run our affairs.
The outsiders left, and as usual we negotiated our contract like friends, thanks to Jim.
Here are two ways to use the Be Human approach to make you a better leader.
First, each time you face a difficult matter involving people, ask yourself, what is the human way to handle this?
Ponder over this question when there is a disagreement among your subordinates or when an employee creates a problem.
Remember Bob W.'s formula for helping others correct their mistakes.
Avoid sarcasm.
Avoid being cynical.
Avoid taking people down a peg or two.
Avoid putting others in their place.
Ask, what is the human way to deal with people?
It always pays.
Sometimes sooner, sometimes later.
But it always pays.
A second way to profit from the Be Human rule is to let your actions show you put people first.
Show interest in your subordinates' off-the-job accomplishments.
Treat everyone with dignity.
Remind yourself that the primary purpose in life is to enjoy it.
As a general rule, the more interest you show in a person, the more he will produce for you,
and his production is what carries you forward to greater and greater success.
Praise your subordinates to your supervisor by putting in plugs for them at every opportunity.
It's an old American custom to admire the fellow who's on the side of the little man.
Your subordinates will appreciate your plugs, and their loyalty to you will grow.
And do not fear that this will lower your own importance in the eyes of your supervisor.
Rather, a man big enough to be humble appears more confident than the insecure man who feels compelled to call attention to his accomplishments.
A little modesty goes a long way.
Praise your subordinates personally at every opportunity.
Praise them for their cooperation.
Praise them for every extra effort they put forth.
Praise is the greatest single incentive you can give people, and it costs you nothing.
Besides, a write-in vote has often overthrown a powerful known candidate.
You never know when your subordinates can do you a turn by coming to your defense.
Practice praising people.
Rub people the right way.
Be human.