John got the smallest office and fizzled out.
Several years ago, I observed small thinking about an office assignment destroy a young fellow's chances for a profitable career in advertising.
Four young executives, all on the same status level, were moved into new offices.
Three of the offices were identical in size and decoration.
The fourth was smaller and less elaborate.
J.M. was assigned the fourth office.
This turned out to be a real blow to his pride.
Immediately, he felt discriminated against.
Negative thinking, resentment, bitterness, jealousy built up.
J.M. began to feel inadequate.
The result was that J.M. grew hostile toward his fellow executives.
Rather than cooperate, he did his best to undermine their efforts.
Things got worse.
Three months later, J.M. slipped so badly that management had no choice but to issue him a pink slip.
Small thinking over a very small matter stopped J.M. In his haste to feel he was discriminated against,
J.M. failed to observe that the company was expanding rapidly and office space was at a premium.
He didn't stop to consider the possibility that the executive who made the office assignments didn't even know which one was the smallest.
No one in the organization, except JM, regarded his office as an index of his value.
Small thinking about unimportant things, like seeing your name last on the department root sheet,
or getting the fourth carbon of an office memo, can hurt you.
Think big, and none of these little things can hold you back.
4.
Even stuttering is a detail.
A sales executive told me how even stuttering is a mere detail in salesmanship,
if the fellow has the really important qualities.
I have a friend, also a sales executive, who loves to play practical jokes,
though sometimes these jokes aren't jokes at all.
A few months ago, a young fellow called on my practical joking friend and asked for a sales job.
The fellow had a terrible stutter, though, and my friend decided right here was a chance to play a joke on me.
So the friend told the stammering applicant that he wasn't in the market for a salesman right now,
but one of his friends, me, had a spot to fill.
Then he phoned me, and boy did he give this fellow a build-up.
Not suspecting anything, I said, send him right over.
Thirty minutes later, in he walked.
The young fellow hadn't said three words before I knew why my friend was so eager to send him over.
I-I-I'm J-J-Jack R., he said.
Mr. X sent me over t-t-to talk t-t-to you about a j-j-job.
Almost every word was a struggle.
I thought to myself, this guy couldn't sell a dollar bill for ninety cents on Wall Street.
I was sore at my friend, but I really felt sorry for this fellow,
so I thought the least I could do was to ask him some polite questions while I thought up a good excuse as to why I couldn't use him.
As we talked on, however, I discovered this fellow was no stoop.
He was intelligent.
He handled himself very nicely.
But I just couldn't overlook the fact that he stuttered.
Finally, I decided I'd wind up the interview by asking one last question.
What makes you think you can sell?
Well, he said, I learn fast, I like people, I think you've got a good company,
and I want to make money.
Now, I do have a speech impairment, but that doesn't bother me, so why should it bother anybody else?
His answer showed me he had all the really important qualifications for a salesman.
I decided right then to give him a chance.
And you know, he's working out very well.
Even a speech impairment in a talker's profession is a triviality if the person has the big qualities.