Years ago I took on a daily writing and broadcasting chore that has totaled, now, more than two thousand scripts.
Had I been asked at the time to sign a contract to write two thousand scripts,
I would have refused in despair at the enormousness of such an undertaking.
But I was only asked to write one, the next one, and that is all I have ever done.
The principle of the next mile works for Eric Severide, and it will work for you.
The step-by-step method is the only intelligent way to attain any objective.
The best formula I have heard for quitting smoking, the one that has worked for more of my friends than any other,
I call the hour-by-hour method.
Instead of trying to reach the ultimate goal, freedom from the habit, just by resolving never to smoke again,
the person resolves not to smoke for another hour.
When the hour is up, the smoker simply renews his resolution not to smoke for another hour.
Later, as desire diminishes, the period is extended to two hours, later to a day.
Eventually, the goal is won.
The person who wants freedom from the habit all at once fails because the psychological pain is more than he can stand.
An hour is easy.
Forever is difficult.
Winning any objective requires a step-by-step method.
To the junior executive, each assignment, however insignificant it may appear, should be viewed as an opportunity to take one step forward.
A salesman qualifies for management responsibilities one sale at a time.
To the minister, each sermon, to the professor, each lecture, to the scientist,
each experiment, to the business executive, each conference, is an opportunity to take one step forward toward the large goal.
Sometimes it appears that someone achieves success all at once.
But if you check the past histories of people who seemed to arrive at the top suddenly,
you'll discover a lot of solid groundwork was previously laid, and those successful people who lose fame as fast as they found it simply were phonies who had not built a solid foundation.
Just as a beautiful building is created from pieces of stone, each of which in itself appears insignificant,
in like manner the successful life is constructed.
Do this.
Start marching toward your ultimate goal by making the next task you perform,
regardless of how unimportant it may seem, a step in the right direction.
Commit this question to memory and use it to evaluate everything you do.