A young fiction writer talked with me recently about her writing ambitions.
The name of one of the top writers in her field came up.
Oh, she said, Mr. X is a wonderful writer, but, of course, I can't be nearly as successful as he is.
Her attitude disappointed me very much, because I know the writer mentioned.
He is not super-intelligent nor super-perceptive, nor super-anything else except super-confident.
He believes he is among the best, and so he acts and performs the best.
It is well to respect the leader, learn from him, observe him, study him, but don't worship him.
Believe you can surpass.
Believe you can go beyond.
Those who harbor the second-best attitude are invariably second-best doers.
Look at it this way.
Belief is the thermostat that regulates what we accomplish in life.
Study the fellow who is shuffling down there in mediocrity.
He believes he is worth little, so he receives little.
He believes he can't do big things, and he doesn't.
He believes he is unimportant, so everything he does has an unimportant mark.
As time goes by, lack of belief in himself shows through in the way the fellow talks, walks, acts.
Unless he readjusts his thermostat forward, he shrinks, grows smaller and smaller in his own estimation.
And since others see in us what we see in ourselves, he grows smaller in the estimation of the people around him.
Now, look across the way at the person who is advancing forward.
He believes he is worth much, and he receives much.
He believes he can handle big, difficult assignments, and he does.
Everything he does, the way he handles himself with people, his character, his thoughts,
his viewpoints, all say, here is a professional.
He is an important person.
A person is a product of his own thoughts.
Believe big.
Adjust your thermostat forward.
Launch your success offensive with honest, sincere belief that you can succeed.
Believe big and grow big.