In 1936, Mr. Barrymore broke his hip.
The fracture never healed.
Most people thought Mr. Barrymore was finished, but not Mr. Barrymore.
He used the setback to pave the way to even greater acting success.
For the next 18 years, despite pain that never abated, he played dozens of successful roles in a wheelchair.
On March 15, 1945, W. Colvin Williams was walking behind a tank in France.
The tank hit a mine, exploded, and permanently blinded Mr. Williams.
But this didn't stop Mr. Williams from pursuing his goal to be a minister and counselor.
When he was graduated from college, and with honors, too, Mr. Williams said he thought his blindness will actually be an asset in my career.
I can never judge by appearances.
Therefore, I can always give a person a second chance.
My blindness keeps me from cutting myself off from a person because of the way he looks.
I want to be the kind of person to whom anyone can come and feel secure to express himself.
Isn't that a magnificent living example of cruel bitter defeat being turned into victory?
Defeat is only a state of mind and nothing more.
One of my friends, who is a substantial and successful investor in the stock market,
carefully appraises each investment decision in the light of his past experiences.
One time, he told me, when I first started investing 15 years ago, I really got singed a few times.
Like most amateurs, I wanted to get rich quick.
Instead, I got broke quick.
But that didn't stop me.
I knew the basic strengths of the economy, and that over the long pull,
well-selected stocks are about the best investment anybody can make.
So I just regarded those first bad investments as part of the cost of my education," he laughed.
On the other hand, I know a number of people who, having made an unwise investment or two,
are strictly anti-securities.
Rather than analyze their mistakes and join in a good thing, they reach the completely false conclusion that investing in common stocks is just a form of gambling,
and sooner or later everybody loses.
Decide right now to salvage something from every setback.
Next time things seem to go wrong on the job or at home,
calm down and find out what caused the trouble.