Here is a psychological principle that is worth listening to repeatedly until it absolutely saturates you.
To think confidently, act confidently.
The great psychologist, Dr. George W. Crane, said in his famous book, Applied Psychology,
remember, motions are the precursors of emotions.
You can't control the latter directly, but only through your choice of motions or actions.
To avoid this all-too-common tragedy, marital difficulties and misunderstandings, become aware of the true psychological facts.
Go through the proper motions each day, and you'll soon begin to feel the corresponding emotions.
Just be sure you and your mate go through those motions of dates and kisses,
the phrasing of sincere daily compliments, plus the many other little courtesies, and you need not worry about the emotion of love.
You can't act devoted for very long without feeling devoted.
Psychologists tell us we can change our attitudes by changing our physical actions.
For example, you actually feel more like smiling if you make yourself smile.
You feel more superior when you make yourself stand tall than when you slouch.
On the negative side, frown a really bitter frown and see if you don't feel more like frowning.
It is easy to prove that managed motions can change emotions.
People who are shy in introducing themselves can replace this timidity with confidence just by taking three simple actions simultaneously.
First, reach for the other person's hand and clasp it warmly.
Second, look directly at the other person.
And third, say, I'm very glad to know you.
These three simple actions automatically and instantaneously banish shyness.
Confident action produces confident thinking.
So, to think confidently, act confidently.
Act the way you want to feel.
Here are five confidence building exercises.