This laboratory supplies you with every possible example of human action.
And there is no limit to what you can learn once you see yourself as a scientist in your own lab.
What's more, there is nothing to buy.
There is no rent to pay.
There are no fees of any kind.
You can use this laboratory as much as you like for free.
As director of your own laboratory, you will want to do what every scientist does, observe and experiment.
Isn't it surprising to you that most people understand so little about why people act as they do,
even though they are surrounded by people all their lives?
Most people are not trained observers.
One important purpose of this book is to help you train yourself to observe,
to develop deep insight into human action.
You'll want to ask yourself questions like, Why is John so successful and Tom just getting by?
Why do some people have many friends and other people have only few friends?
Why will people gladly accept what one person tells them but ignore another person who tells them the same thing?
Once trained, you will learn valuable lessons just through the very simple process of observing.
Here are two special suggestions to help you make yourself a trained observer.
Select for special study the most successful and the most unsuccessful person you know.
Then, as the book unfolds, observe how closely your successful friend adheres to these success principles.
Notice also how studying the two extremes will help you see the unmistakable wisdom of following the truths outlined in this book.
Each contact you make with another person gives you a chance to see success development principles at work.
Your objective is to make successful action habitual.
The more we practice, the sooner it becomes second nature to act in the desired way.
Most of us have friends who grow things for a hobby.
And we've all heard them say something like, it's exciting to watch those plants grow.
Just look how they respond to plant food and water.
See how much bigger they are today than they were last week.
To be sure, it is thrilling to watch what can happen when men cooperate carefully with nature.
But it is not one-tenth as fascinating as watching yourself respond to your own carefully administered thought-management program.
It's fun to feel yourself growing more confident, more effective, more successful, day by day, month by month.
Nothing, absolutely nothing, in this life gives you more satisfaction than knowing you're on the road to success and achievement.
And nothing stands as a bigger challenge than making the most of yourself.