Here are examples of phrases that create small, negative, depressing thoughts.
And then, the same situation is discussed, but in a big, positive way.
As you listen to these, ask yourself, what mind pictures do I see?
Phrases that create small, negative mind images.
1.
It's no use.
We're whipped.
Or, phrases that create big, positive mind images.
We're not whipped yet.
Let's keep trying.
Here's a new angle.
Two, I was in that business once and failed.
Never again.
Or, I went broke, but it was my own fault.
I'm going to try again.
Three, I've tried, but the product won't sell.
People don't want it.
Or, so far I've not been able to sell this product, but I know it is good,
and I'm going to find the formula that will put it over.
4.
The market is saturated.
Imagine, 75% of the potential has already been sold.
Better get out.
Or, Imagine, 25% of the market is still not sold.
Count me in.
This looks big.
5.
Their orders have been small.
Cut them off.
Or, Their orders have been small.
Let's map out a plan for selling them more of their needs.