I worked with her to help her see joy and pleasure in her past, instead of total disappointment.
After six months, she began to show improvement.
At that point, I gave her a special assignment.
Each day, I asked her to think of and write down three specific reasons she has to be happy.
Then, at her next appointment with me, on Thursdays, I'd go over her list with her.
I continued this sort of treatment for three months.
Her improvement was very satisfactory.
Today, that woman is very well adjusted to her situation.
She's positive and certainly as happy as most people.
When this woman quit drawing negatives from her memory bank, she was headed toward recovery.
Whether the psychological problem is big or little, the cure comes when one learns to quit drawing negatives from one's memory bank and withdraws positives instead.
Don't build mental monsters.
Refuse to withdraw the unpleasant thoughts from your memory bank.
When you remember situations of any kind, concentrate on the good part of the experience.
Forget the bad.
Bury it.
If you find yourself thinking about the negative side, turn your mind off completely.
And here is something very significant and very encouraging.
Your mind wants you to forget the unpleasant.
If you will just cooperate, unpleasant memories will gradually shrivel and the teller in your memory bank will cancel them out.
Dr. Melvin S. Hatwick, noted advertising psychologist, in commenting on our ability to remember,
says, When the feeling aroused is pleasant, the advertisement has a better chance to be remembered.
When the feeling aroused is unpleasant, the reader or listener tends to forget the advertisement message.
The unpleasant runs counter to what we want.
We don't want to remember it.
In brief, it really is easy to forget the unpleasant if we simply refuse to recall it.
Withdraw only positive thoughts from your memory bank.
Let the others fade away, and your confidence, that feeling of being on top of the world, will zoom upward.
You take a big step forward toward conquering fear when you refuse to remember negative, self-deprecating thoughts.