Four.
But my case is different.
I attract bad luck.
Recently, I heard a traffic engineer discuss highway safety.
He pointed out that upward of 40,000 persons are killed each year in so-called traffic accidents.
The main point of his talk was that there is no such thing as a true accident.
What we call an accident is the result of human or mechanical failure, or a combination of both.
What this traffic expert was saying substantiates what wise men throughout the ages have said.
There is a cause for everything.
Nothing happens without a cause.
There is nothing accidental about the weather outside today.
It is the result of specific causes.
And there is no reason to believe that human affairs are an exception.
Yet hardly a day passes that you do not hear someone blame his problems on bad luck.
and it's a rare day that you do not hear someone attribute another person's success to good luck.
Let me illustrate how people succumb to luck excusitis.
I lunched recently with three young junior executives.
The topic of conversation that day was George C., who just yesterday had been picked from among their group for a major promotion.
Why did George get the position?
These three fellows dug up all sorts of reasons—luck, pull, bootlicking, George's wife and how she flattered the boss—everything but the truth.
The facts were that George was simply better qualified.
He had been doing a better job.
He was working harder.
He had a more effective personality.
I also knew that the senior officers in the company had spent much time considering which one of the four would be promoted.