As company policy, he said, we feel the best initial training is to start the young fellow,
who incidentally is usually a college graduate, as a male boy.
We don't do this, of course, because we feel a fellow needs four years of college to take mail from one office to another.
Our purpose is to give the new fellow maximum exposure to the many varied things which must be done in agency work.
After he knows his way around, we give him an assignment.
Now occasionally, even after we've carefully explained why we're starting him out in the mailroom,
a young fellow feels that carrying the mail is belittling and unimportant.
When this is the case, we know we've picked the wrong man.
If he doesn't have the vision to see that being a mailboy is a necessary practical step to important assignments,
then he has no future in the agency business.
Remember, executives answer the question, what would he do on that specific level,
by first answering the question, what kind of job is he doing where he is now.
Here is some logic.
Sounds straight and easy.
Listen to it a few times before you continue.
A person who thinks his job is important receives mental signals on how to do his job better.
And a better job means more promotions, more money, more prestige, more happiness.
We've all noticed how children quickly pick up the attitudes, habits, fears, and preferences of their parents.
whether it be food preferences, mannerisms, religious and political views, or any other type of behavior.
The child is a living reflection of how his parents or guardians think, for he learns through imitation.
And so do adults.
People continue to imitate others throughout life, and they imitate their leaders and supervisors.
Their thoughts and actions are influenced by these people.
You can check this easily.
Study one of your friends and the person he works for, and note the similarities in thinking and action.
Here are some of the ways your friend may imitate his boss or other associate.
Slang and word choice, the way he smokes cigarettes, some facial expressions and mannerisms, choice of clothing, and automobile preferences.
There are many, many more, of course.
Another way to note the power of imitation is to observe the attitudes of employees and compare them with those of the chief.
When the chief is nervous, tense, worried, his close associates reflect similar attitudes.
But when Mr. Chief is on top, feeling good, so are his employees.
The point is this.
The way we think toward our jobs determines how our subordinates think toward their jobs.
The job attitudes of our subordinates are direct reflections of our own job attitudes.
It's well to remember that our points of superiority and weakness show up in the behavior of those who report to us,
just as a child reflects the attitudes of his parents.
Consider just one characteristic of successful people—enthusiasm.