Then get the put service first attitude.
It's perfectly natural, in fact it's highly desirable, to want to make money and accumulate wealth.
Money is power to give your family and yourself the standard of living they deserve.
Money is power to help the unfortunate.
Money is one of the means to living life fully.
Once criticized for urging people to make money, the great minister Russell H. Conwell,
author of Acres of Diamonds, said, Money printed your Bible, money builds your churches,
money sends your missionaries, and money pays your preachers, and you would not have many of them either if you did not pay them.
The person who says he wants to be poor usually suffers from a guilt complex or a feeling of inadequacy.
He's like the youngster who feels he can't make A's in school or make the football team,
so he pretends he doesn't want to make A's or play football.
Money, then, is a desirable objective.
What's puzzling about money is the backward approach so many people use in trying to make it.
Everywhere you see people with a money-first attitude.
Yet these same people always have little money.
Why?
Simply this.
People with a money-first attitude become so money-conscious that they forget money can't be harvested unless they plant the seeds that grow the money.
And the seed of money is service.
That's why put service first is an attitude that creates wealth.
Put service first and money takes care of itself.
One summer evening, I was traveling by car through Cincinnati.
It was time for a gas up.
I stopped at an ordinary looking but surprisingly busy service station.
Four minutes later, I knew why this particular service station was so popular.
After filling my car with gasoline, checking under the hood, and cleaning the outside of my windshield,
the attendant walked around to my side of the car and said, Pardon me,
sir, it's been a dusty day.
Let me clean the inside of your windshield.
Quickly and efficiently, he did a thorough job of cleaning the inside of my windshield,
something not one service station attendant in a hundred ever does.
This little special service did more than improve my night visibility, and it improved a lot.
It made me remember this station.
It so happened that I made eight trips through Cincinnati during the next three months.
Each time, of course, I stopped at this station, and each time I got more service than I expected to get.
Interesting, too, was the fact that each time I stopped, once it was 4 a.m.,
there were other automobiles filling up also.
In all, I probably purchased about 100 gallons of gasoline from this station.
The first time I stopped, the attendant could have thought to himself, this guy is from out of state.
Odds are 20 to 1 that he'll never be back.
Why do more than give him the routine treatment?
He's only a one-time customer.
But the attendants in that station didn't think that way.
They put service first, and that's why they were busy pumping gasoline while other stations looked almost deserted.
If the gasoline was any better than a dozen other brands, I didn't notice it,
and the price was competitive.
The difference was service, and it was obvious that service was paying off in profits.
When the attendant on my first visit cleaned the inside of my windshield, he planted a money seed.
Put service first, and money takes care of itself, always.
The put service first attitude pays off in all situations.