During World War II, the Navy made sure that all of its new recruits either knew how to swim or learned how,
the idea being, of course, that the ability to swim might someday save the sailors' life at sea.
Non-swimming recruits were put into swimming classes.
I watched a number of these training experiences.
In a superficial sort of way, it was amusing to see young, healthy men terrified by a few feet of water.
One of the exercises, I recall, required the new sailor to jump, not dive,
from a board six feet in the air into eight or more feet of water,
while a half-dozen expert swimmers stood by.
In a deeper sense, it was a sad sight.
The fear those young men displayed was real.
Yet all that stood between them and the defeat of that fear was one drop into the water below.
On more than one occasion, I saw young men accidentally pushed off the board.
The result?
Fear defeated.
This incident, familiar to thousands of former Navy men, illustrates just one point.
Action cures fear.
Indecision, postponement, on the other hand, fertilize fear.
Jot that down in your success rule book right now.
Action cures fear.
Action does cure fear.