Grow the I'm activated attitude.
Results come in proportion to the enthusiasm invested.
Three things to do to activate yourself are, dig into it deeper.
When you find yourself uninterested in something, dig in and learn more about it.
This sets off enthusiasm.
Life up everything about you, your smile, your handshake, your talk, even your walk.
Act alive.
Broadcast good news.
No one ever accomplished anything positive telling bad news.
2.
Grow the you are important attitude.
People do more for you when you make them feel important.
Remember to do these things.
Show appreciation at every opportunity.
Make people feel important.
Call people by name.
3.
Grow the service-first attitude and watch money take care of itself.
Make it a rule in everything you do.
Give people more than they expect to get.