Chapter 9 Think Right Toward People Here is a basic rule for winning success.
Let's mark it in the mind and remember it.
The rule is, success depends on the support of other people.
The only hurdle between you and what you want to be is the support of others.
Look at it this way.
An executive depends on people to carry out his instructions.
If they don't, the company president will fire the executive, not the employees.
A salesman depends on people to buy his product.
If they don't, the salesman fails.
Likewise, a college dean depends on professors to carry forward his educational program.
A politician depends on voters to elect him.
A writer depends on people to read what he writes.
A chain store magnate got to be a chain store magnate because employees accepted his leadership and consumers accepted his merchandising program.
There were times in history when a person could gain a position of authority through force and hold it with force and or threats of force.
In those days, a man either cooperated with the leader or risked literally losing his head.
But today, remember, a person either supports you willingly or he doesn't support you at all.
Now it's time to ask, granted, I depend on others in order to achieve the success I want,
but what must I do to get these people to support me and accept my leadership?
The answer, wrapped up in one phrase, is, think right toward people.
Think right toward people, and they will like and support you.
This chapter shows how.
Thousands of times daily a scene like this takes place.