When is a person too young?
The I'm-too-young variety of age excusitis does much damage, too.
About a year ago, a twenty-three-year-old fellow named Jerry came to me with a problem.
Jerry was a fine young man.
He had been a paratrooper in the service and then had gone to college.
While going to college, Jerry supported his wife and son by selling for a large transfer and storage company.
He had done a terrific job, both in college and for his company.
But today Jerry was worried.
Dr. Schwartz, he said, I've got a problem.
My company has offered me the job of sales manager.
This would make me supervisor over eight salesmen.
Congratulations, that's wonderful news, I said.
But you seem worried.
Well, he continued, all eight men I'm to supervise are from seven to 21 years older than I. What do you think I should do?
Can I handle it?" Jerry, I said, the general manager of your company obviously thinks you're old enough or he wouldn't have offered you this job.
Just remember these three points and everything will work out just fine.
But first, don't be age-conscious.
Back on the farm, a boy became a man when he proved he could do the work of a man.
His number of birthdays had nothing to do with it, and this applies to you.
When you prove you are able to handle the job of sales manager, you're automatically old enough.
Second, don't take advantage of your new gold bars.
Show respect for the salesmen.
Ask them for their suggestions.
Make them feel they are working for a team captain, not a dictator.
Do this and the men will work with you, not against you.
Third, get used to having older persons working for you.
Leaders in all fields soon find they are younger than many of the people they supervise.
So get used to having older men work for you.
It will help you a lot in the coming years, when even bigger opportunities develop.
And remember, Jerry, your age won't be a handicap unless you make it one.
Today, Jerry's doing fine.
He loves the transportation business, and now he's planning to organize his own company in a few years.
Youth is a liability only when the youth thinks it is.