Suggestions come slowly at first.
Someone hesitantly says something like, well, you might cut down crime if you established more youth centers.
Before long, the group, which ten minutes ago was solidly against the idea, now begins to work up real enthusiasm.
Work to eliminate poverty.
Most crime stems from the low income levels.
Conduct research to spot potential criminals before they commit a crime.
Develop surgical procedures to cure some kinds of criminals.
Educate law enforcement personnel in positive methods of reform.
These are just samples of the 78 specific ideas I've tabulated that could help accomplish the goal of eliminating jails.
When you believe, your mind finds ways to do.
This experiment has just one point.
When you believe something is impossible, your mind goes to work for you to prove why.
But when you believe, really believe, something can be done, your mind goes to work for you and helps you find the ways to do it.
Believing something can be done paves the way for creative solutions.
Believing something can't be done is destructive thinking.
This point applies to all situations, little and big.
The political leaders who do not genuinely believe permanent world peace can be established will fail because their minds are closed to creative ways to bring about peace.
The economists who believe business depressions are inevitable will not develop creative ways to beat the business cycle.
In a similar fashion, you can find ways to like a person if you believe you can.
You can discover solutions to personal problems if you believe you can.
You can find a way to purchase that new larger home if you believe you can.
Belief releases creative powers.
Disbelief puts the brakes on.
Believe and you'll start thinking constructively.
Your mind will create a way if you let it.