Most important of all, he gives himself an opportunity to show he has special ability and ambition by volunteering.
By all means, volunteer for those special assignments.
Think about the leaders you know in business, the military, your community.
Do they fit the description of activationists, or would you say they are passivationists?
Ten times out of ten, they're activationists, people who do things.
The fellow who stands on the sidelines, who holds off, who is passive, does not lead.
But the doer, the fellow who thinks action, finds others want to follow him.
People place confidence in the fellow who acts.
They naturally assume he knows what he is doing.
I've never heard anyone complimented and praised because he doesn't disturb anyone,
he doesn't take action, or he waits until he's told what to do.
Have you?
Grow the action habit.
Practice these key points.