She didn't like teaching, so the pupils didn't like learning.
But the second teacher had high, positive standards.
She sincerely liked the children and wanted them to accomplish much.
She considered each one as an individual.
She obtained discipline easily because, in everything she did, she was well-disciplined.
And in each case, the pupils adjusted their conduct to fit the examples set by the teachers.
We find the same form of adjustment taking place every day in adult groups.
During World War II, military chiefs continually observed that the highest morale was not found in units where commanders were easy,
relaxed, and lackadaisical.
Crack units were led by officers with high standards who enforced military regulations fairly and properly.
Military personnel simply do not respect and admire officers with low standards.
College students, too, take their cue from the examples set by the professors.
Students under one professor cut classes, copy term papers, and connive in various ways to pass without serious study.
But the same students under another professor willingly work extra hard to master the subject.
In business situations, we again find individuals patterning their thinking after that of the superior.
Study a group of employees closely.
Observe their habits, mannerisms, attitudes toward the company, ethics, self-control.
Then, compare what you find with the behavior of their superior, and you discover amazing similarities.
Every year, many corporations that have grown sluggish and are headed downward are rebuilt.
And how?
By changing a handful of executives at the top.
Companies, and colleges, and churches, and clubs, and unions, and all other types of organizations are successfully rebuilt from the top down,
not from the bottom up.
Change the thinking at the top, and you automatically change the thinking at the bottom.
Remember this.
When you take over the leadership of a group, the persons in that group immediately begin to adjust themselves to the standards you set.
This is most noticeable during the first few weeks.
Their big concern is to clue you in, zero you in, find out what you expect of them.
They watch every move you make.
They think, how much rope will he give me?
How does he want it done?
What does it take to please him?
What will he say if I do this or that?
Once they know, they act accordingly.
Check the example you set.
Use this old but ever-accurate quatrain as a guide.
What kind of world would this world be, if everyone in it were just like me?
To add meaning to this self-imposed test, substitute the word company for world so it reads,