Each time you speak up, you strengthen yourself.
Come forward with your constructive ideas.
We all know how many college students prepare their assignments.
With fine intentions, Joe College sets aside a whole evening for some concentrated study.
Here is a general pattern of how, too often, the evening is spent.
Joe's ready to begin studying at 7 p.m., but his dinner seems just a bit heavy,
so he decides to get in a little TV.
A little turns out to be an hour's worth, since the program was pretty good.
At eight p.m., he sits down at his desk but gets right back up because he just remembered he promised to call his girl.
This shoots another forty minutes.
He hadn't talked to her all day.
An incoming call takes another twenty minutes.
On his way back to his desk, Joe is drawn into a ping-pong game.
Another hour gone.
The ping-pong makes him feel sweaty, so he takes a shower.
Next, he needs a snack.
The combined effect of the ping-pong and the shower have made him hungry.
And so the evening planned with good intentions drifts away.
Finally, at 1 a.m., he opens the book, but he's too sleepy to absorb the subject.
Finally, he surrenders completely.
Next morning, he tells the professor, I hope you give me a break.
I studied till 2 a.m. for this exam.
Joe College didn't get into action because he spent too much time getting ready to get into action.
And Joe College isn't alone in being a victim of over-preparedness.