It was easy for people I called to say, I'm not interested, and hang up.
Every Monday morning back then, our sales manager held a sales meeting.
It was a pretty inspirational affair, and it made me feel good.
And what's more, I always seemed to arrange more demonstrations on Monday than on any other day.
But the trouble was that little of Monday's inspiration carried over to Tuesday and the rest of the week.
Then I got an idea.
If the sales manager can pep me up, why can't I pep myself up?
Why not give myself a pep talk just before I start making those phone calls?
That day, I decided to try it.
Without telling anyone, I walked out on the lot and found a vacant car.
Then, for several minutes, I talked to myself.
I told myself, I'm a good car salesman and I'm going to be the best.
I sell good cars and I give good deals.
The people I'm phoning need those cars and I'm going to sell them.
Well, from the very beginning, this self-supercharging paid off.
I felt so good, I didn't dread making those calls.
I wanted to make them.
I no longer go out on the lot and sit in a car to give myself a pep talk,
but I still use the technique.
Before I dial a number, I silently remind myself that I'm a top-notch salesman and I'm going to get results,
and I do.
That's a pretty good idea, isn't it?
To be on top, you've got to feel like you're on top.
Give yourself a pep talk and discover how much bigger and stronger you feel.
Recently, in a training program I conducted, each person was asked to give a ten-minute talk on being a leader.
One of the trainees gave a miserable presentation.
His knees literally shook and his hands trembled.
He forgot what he was going to say.
After fumbling for five or six minutes, he sat down, thoroughly defeated.
After the session, I spoke to him just long enough to ask him to be there fifteen minutes early at the next session.
As promised, he was there fifteen minutes ahead of time for the next session.
The two of us sat down to discuss his talk of the night before.
I asked him to remember as clearly as he could exactly what he had thought about the five minutes just before he gave his talk.
Well, I guess all I thought about was how scared I was.
I knew I was going to make a fool of myself.
I knew I was going to be a flop.
I kept thinking, who am I to be talking about being a leader?
I tried to remember what I was going to say, but all I could think about was failing.
Right there, I injected, is the answer to your problem.
Before you got up to talk, you gave yourself a terrible mental beating.
You convinced yourself that you would fail.
Is it any wonder your talk didn't come off well?
Instead of developing courage, you developed fear.
Now this evening's session, I continued, starts in just four minutes.
Here's what I'd like you to do.
Give yourself a pep talk for the next few minutes.
Go in that vacant room across the hall and tell yourself, I'm going to give a great talk.
I've got something those people need to hear and I want to say.
Keep repeating those sentences forcefully, with complete conviction.
Then come into the conference room and give your talk again.
I wish you could have been there to hear the difference.
That brief, self-administered, hard-hitting pep talk helped him to make a splendid speech.
The moral?
Practice uplifting self-praise.
Don't practice belittling self-punishment.
You are what you think you are.
Think more of yourself and there is more of you.