Ever notice how an enthusiastic salesperson in a department store gets you, the customer, more excited about the merchandise?
Or have you observed how an enthusiastic minister or other speaker has a wide-awake, alert, enthusiastic audience?
If you have enthusiasm, those around you will have it too.
But how does one develop enthusiasm?
The basic step is simple.
Think enthusiastically.
Build in yourself an optimistic, progressive glow, a feeling that, this is great, and I'm 100% for it.
You are what you think.
Think enthusiasm, and you'll be enthusiastic.
To get high-quality work, be enthusiastic about the job you want done.
Others will catch the enthusiasm you generate, and you'll get first-class performance.
But if, in negative fashion, you cheat that company on expense money, supplies,
and time, and in other little ways, then what can you expect your subordinates to do?
habitually arrive late and leave early, and what do you think the troops will do?
And there is a major incentive for us to think right about our jobs so that our subordinates will think right about their jobs.
Our superiors evaluate us by measuring the quality and quantity of output we get from those reporting to us.
Look at it this way.
Whom would you elevate to division sales manager?
The branch sales manager whose salesmen are doing superior work, or the branch sales manager whose salesmen deliver only average performance?
Or whom would you recommend for promotion to production manager?
The supervisor whose department meets its quota, or the supervisor whose department lags behind?
Here are two suggestions for getting others to do more for you.
1.
Always show positive attitudes toward your job so that your subordinates will pick up right thinking.
2.
As you approach your job each day, ask yourself, am I worthy in every respect of being imitated?
Are all my habits such that I would be glad to see them in my subordinates?
Give yourself a pep talk several times daily.
Several months ago, an automobile salesman told me about the success-producing technique he's developed.
It makes sense.
Listen to it.
A big part of my job, for two hours a day, the salesman explained,
is telephoning prospects to arrange demonstration appointments.
When I first started selling cars three years ago, this was my big problem.
I was shy and afraid, and I know my voice sounded that way on the phone.