A committee or group is in session.
The purpose, to consider names for a promotion, a new job, a club membership,
an honor, someone to be the new company president, the new supervisor, the new sales manager.
A name is placed before the group.
The chairman asks, what is your feeling about so-and-so?
Comments come forth.
For some names, there are positive remarks, such as, He's a good fellow.
People there speak highly of him.
He has a good technical background, too.
Mr. F. Oh, he's a personable sort of man, very human.
I believe he would fit in well with our group.
Some names draw negative, lukewarm statements.
I think we should investigate that fellow carefully.
He doesn't seem to get along too well with people.
I know he has a good academic and technical background, I don't question his competence,
but I am concerned about the acceptance he would receive.
He doesn't command much respect from people.
Now, here is an exceptionally important observation.
In at least nine cases out of ten, the likability factor is the first thing mentioned.
And in an overwhelmingly large number of cases, the likability factor is given far more weight than the technical factor.
This holds true even in selecting scholars for university professorships.
In my own academic experience, I've sat in on a considerable number of occasions when names for new faculty personnel were under question.
When a name came up, the group would weigh most carefully thoughts such as, will he fit in?
Will students like him?
Will he cooperate with others on the staff?
Unfair?
Unacademic?
No.
If the fellow isn't likable, he can't be expected to get through to his students with maximum effectiveness.
Mark this point well.
A person is not pulled up to a higher level job, rather he is lifted up.
In this day and age, nobody has time or patience to pull another up the job ladder,
degree by painful degree.
The individual is chosen whose record makes him stand higher than the rest.
We are lifted to higher levels by those who know us as likable, personable individuals.
Every friend you make lifts you just one notch higher, and being likable makes you lighter to lift.
Successful people follow a plan for liking people, do you?
People who reach the top don't discuss much their techniques for thinking right toward people.
But you would be surprised how many really big people have a clear, definite, even written plan for liking people.
Consider the case of President Lyndon Johnson.
Long before he became president, Johnson, in the process of developing his amazing power of personal persuasion,
developed his own ten-point formula for success.
His rules, which even a casual observer of the President can see are practiced in everything he does,
are quoted directly.
1.
Learn to remember names.
Inefficiency at this point may indicate that your interest is not sufficiently outgoing.