The students had no interest in what the professor was saying, because the professor himself had no interest.
He was bored with history, and it showed through.
To activate others, to get them to be enthusiastic, you must first be enthusiastic yourself.
Over the years I've tested this principle in hundreds of different situations.
It always holds true.
A man who lacks enthusiasm never develops it in another.
But a person who is enthusiastic soon has enthusiastic followers.
The enthusiastic salesman need never worry about unenthusiastic buyers.
The enthusiastic teacher need never worry about disinterested students.
The activated minister need never be distressed by a sleepy congregation.
Enthusiasm can make things 1,100% better.
Two years ago, employees in a business I'm acquainted with donated $94.35 to the Red Cross.
This year, the same employees, with just about the same payroll, donated almost $1,100, an increase of 1,100%.
The drive captain who collected only $94.35 was totally lacking in enthusiasm.
He made remarks like, I suppose it's a worthwhile organization.
I've never had any direct contact with it.
It's a big organization and they collect a lot from the wealthy.
So I suppose it's not too important if you contribute.
If you can make a donation, see me.
This fellow did nothing to inspire anyone to want to join the Red Cross and do it in a big way.
This year's drive captain was a different sort.
He had enthusiasm.
He gave examples of case histories that showed how the Red Cross pitches in when disaster strikes.
He showed how the Red Cross depends on donations from everyone.
He asked the employees to be guided in giving by how much they would be willing to give their neighbor if disaster should strike him.
He said, look what the Red Cross has done.
Notice, he did not beg.
He did not say, each of you is expected to donate XX dollars.
All he did was to show enthusiasm about the importance of the Red Cross.