A special word of caution.
Be careful about your source of advice.
In most organizations you will encounter freelance advisors who know the ropes and are tremendously eager to clue you in.
One time I overheard a freelance advisor explaining the facts of office life to a bright young man just starting in.
said the advisor.
The best way to get along here is just stay out of everybody's way.
If they ever get to know you, all they'll do is pile more work on you.
Be especially careful to stay away from Mr. Z, the department manager.
If he thinks you haven't got enough to do, he'll really load you down.
This freelance advisor had been with the company for almost 30 years and was still bottom man on the totem pole.
What a consultant for a young man who wants to move upward in the business.
Make it a rule to seek advice from people who know.
There's a lot of incorrect thinking that successful people are inaccessible.
The plain truth is that they are not.
As a rule, it's the more successful people who are the most humble and ready to help.
Since they are sincerely interested in their work and success, they are eager to see that the work lives on and that somebody capable succeeds them when they retire.
It's the would-be big people who are most often the most abrupt and hard to get to know.
An executive made this clear.
I'm a busy woman, but there's no Do Not Disturb sign on my office door.
Counseling people is one of my key functions.
We give standardized training of one kind or another to everybody in the company.
But personal counseling or tutoring, as I like to call it, is available for the asking.
I stand ready to help the fellow who comes in here with either a company or a personal problem.
The fellow who displays curiosity and exhibits a real desire to know more about his job and how it relates to other jobs is the individual I like most to help.
But, she said, for obvious reasons, I can't spend time offering advice to anybody who isn't sincere in seeking it.
Go first class when you have questions.
Seeking advice from a failure is like consulting a quack on how to cure cancer.
Many executives today never employ persons for key jobs without first interviewing the fellow's wife.
One sales executive explained to me, I want to be sure the prospective salesman has his family behind him,