Some work because they have to, others are ambitious and work for advancement.
Some associates belittle everything the boss says or does, others are much more objective and realize they must be good followers before they can be good leaders.
how we think is directly affected by the group we're in.
Be sure you're in the flock that thinks right.
There are pitfalls to watch in your work environment.
In every group, there are persons who, secretly aware of their own inadequacies,
want to stand in your way and prevent you from making progress.
Many ambitious fellows have been laughed at, even threatened, because they tried to be more efficient and produce more.
Let's face it, some folks, being jealous, want to make you feel embarrassed because you want to move upward.
This often happens in factories, where fellow workers sometimes resent the fellow who wants to speed up production.
It happens in the military service, when a clique of negative-minded individuals poke fun at and try to humiliate the young soldier who wants to go to officer school.
It happens in business, too, when a few individuals not qualified to advance try to block the way for someone else.
You've seen it happen time and again in high schools when a group of lunkheads deride a classmate who has the good sense to make the most of his educational opportunities and come out with high grades.
Sometimes, and all too sadly often, the bright student is jeered at until he reaches the conclusion that it isn't smart to be intelligent.
Ignore such negative thinkers in your midst.
For often, the remarks made in your direction aren't so personal as you might at first think.
They are merely a projection of the speaker's own feeling of failure and discouragement.
Don't let negative thinkers pull you down to their level.
Let them slide by, like the water from the proverbial duck's back.
Cling to people who think progressively.
Move upward with them.
You can do it, simply by thinking right.
A special word of caution.