Three, walk 25% faster.
When I was a youngster, just going to the county seat was a big treat.
After all the errands were accomplished and we were back in the car,
my mother would often say, Davy, let's just sit here a while and watch the people walk by.
Mother was an excellent game player.
She'd say, see that fellow?
What do you suppose is troubling him?
Or what do you think that lady there is going to do?
or, look at that person, he just seems to be in a fog.
Watching people walk and move about became real fun.
It was a lot cheaper than the movies, which was one of the reasons,
I learned later, that Mother developed the game, and it was a lot more instructive.
I still am a walk-watcher.
In corridors, lobbies, on sidewalks, I still occasionally find myself studying human behavior simply by watching people move about.
Psychologists link slovenly posture and sluggish walking to unpleasant attitudes toward oneself, work, and the people around us.
But psychologists also tell us you can actually change your attitudes by changing your posture and speed of movement.
Watch, and you discover that body action is the result of mind action.
The extremely beaten people, the real down-and-outers, just shuffle and stumble along.
They have zero self-confidence.
Average people have the average walk.
Their pace is average.
They have the look of, I really don't have very much pride in myself.
Then there's a third group.
Persons in this group show super confidence.
They walk faster than the average.
There seems to be a slight sprint in the way they walk.
Their walk tells the world, I've got some place important to go, something important to do.
What's more, I will succeed at what I will do fifteen minutes from now.
Use the walk 25% faster technique to help build self-confidence.
Throw your shoulders back, lift up your head, move ahead just a little faster, and feel self-confidence grow.
Just try and see.