2.
Withdraw only positive thoughts from your memory bank.
I was closely associated several years ago in Chicago with a firm of psychological consultants.
They handled many types of cases, but mostly marriage problems and psychological adjustment situations, all dealing with mind matters.
One afternoon, as I was talking with the head of the firm about his profession and his techniques for helping the seriously maladjusted person,
he made this remark.
You know, there would be no need for my services if people would do just one thing.
What's that?
I asked eagerly.
Simply this.
Destroy their negative thoughts before those thoughts become mental monsters.
Most individuals I try to help," he continued, are operating their own private museum of mental horror.
Many marriage difficulties, for example, involve the honeymoon monster.
The honeymoon wasn't as satisfactory as one or both of the marriage partners had hoped,
but instead of burying the memory, they reflected on it hundreds of times until it was a giant obstacle to successful marital relationships.
They come to me as much as five or ten years later.
Usually, of course, my clients don't see where their trouble lies.
It's my job to uncover and explain the source of their difficulty to them and help them to see what a triviality it really is.
A person can make a mental monster out of almost any unpleasant happening, my psychologist friend went on.
a job failure, a jilted romance, a bad investment, disappointment in the behavior of a teenage child.
These are common monsters I have to help troubled people destroy.
It is clear that any negative thought, if fertilized with repeated recall, can develop into a real mind monster,
breaking down confidence and paving the way to serious psychological difficulties.
In an article in Cosmopolitan magazine, The Drive Toward Self-Destruction, Alice Mulcahy pointed out that upward of 30,000 Americans commit suicide each year and another 100,000 attempt to take their own lives.