Invest in idea starters.
Education helps you mold your mind, stretch it, train it to meet new situations and solve problems.
Idea starters serve a related purpose.
They feed your mind, give you constructive material to think about.
Where are the best sources of idea starters?
There are many, but to get a steady supply of high-quality idea material, why not do this?
Resolve to purchase at least one stimulating book each month and subscribe to two magazines or journals that stress ideas.
For only a minor sum and a minimum of time, you can be tuned in to some of the best thinkers available anywhere.
At a luncheon one day, I overheard one fellow say, but it costs too much.
I can't afford to take the Wall Street Journal.
His companion, obviously a much more success-minded person, replied, well, I've found that I can't afford not to take it.
Again, take your cue from the successful people.
Invest in yourself.
Let's take action.
Now, in a quick recap, put these success-building principles to work.
1.
Get a clear fix on where you want to go.
Create an image of yourself 10 years from now.
2.
Write out your 10-year plan.
Your life is too important to be left to chance.
Put down on paper what you want to accomplish in your work, your home, and your social departments.
Three, surrender yourself to your desires.
Set goals to get more energy.
Set goals to get things done.
Set goals and discover the real enjoyment of living.
Four, let your major goal be your automatic pilot.
When you let your goal absorb you, you'll find yourself making the right decisions to reach your goal.
5.
Achieve your goal one step at a time.
Regard each task you perform, regardless of how small it may seem, as a step toward your goal.
6.
Build 30-day goals.
Day-by-day effort pays off.
7.
Take detours in stride.
A detour simply means another route.
It should never mean surrendering the goal.
8.
Invest in yourself.
Purchase those things that build mental power and efficiency.
Invest in education.
Invest in idea starters.