What is the human way to handle this?
People use different approaches to leadership situations.
One approach is to assume the position of a dictator.
The dictator makes all decisions without consulting those affected.
He refuses to hear his subordinates side of a question because, deep down perhaps,
he's afraid the subordinate might be right and this would cause him to lose face.
Dictators don't last long.
Employees may fake loyalty for a while, but unrest soon develops.
Some of the best employees leave, and those remaining get together and plot against the tyrant.
The result is that the organization ceases to function smoothly.
This puts the dictator in a bad light with his superior.
A second leadership technique is the cold, mechanical, I'm-a-rule-book-operator approach.
The fellow using this approach handles everything exactly according to the book.
He doesn't recognize that every rule or policy or plan is only a guide for the usual cases.
This would-be leader treats human beings as machines, and of all things people don't like,
perhaps the most disliked is being treated like a machine.
The cold, impersonal efficiency expert is not an ideal.
The machines that work for him develop only part of their energy.
Persons who rise to tremendous leadership heights use a third approach that we call being human.
Several years ago, I worked closely with John S., who is an executive in the engineering development section of a large aluminum manufacturer.
John had mastered the Be Human approach and was enjoying its rewards.
In dozens of little ways, John made his actions say, You are a human being.
I respect you.
I'm here to help you in every way I can.
When an individual from another city joined his department, John went to considerable personal inconvenience to help him find suitable housing.
Working through his secretary and two other women employees, he set up office birthday parties for each member of the staff.
The thirty minutes or so required for this was not a cost.
Rather, it was an investment in getting loyalty and output.
When he learned that one of his staff members belonged to a minority faith,
John called him in and explained that he would arrange for him to observe his religious holidays that don't coincide with the more common holidays.
When an employee or someone in the employee's family was ill, John remembered.