Listen to these guides carefully, then make a conscious effort to practice them and build your confidence.
1.
Be a front-seater.
Ever notice in meetings, in church, classrooms, and other kinds of assemblies, how the back seats fill up first?
Most folks scramble to sit in the back rows so they won't be too conspicuous.
And the reason they are afraid to be conspicuous is that they lack confidence.
Sitting up front builds confidence.
Practice it.
From now on, make it a rule to sit as close to the front as you can.
Sure, you may be a little more conspicuous in the front, but remember, there is nothing inconspicuous about success.
Two, practice making eye contact.
How a person uses his eyes tells us a lot about him.
Instinctively, you ask yourself questions about the fellow who doesn't look you in the eye.
What's he trying to hide?
What's he afraid of?
Is he trying to put something over on me?
Is he holding something back?
Usually, failure to make eye contact says one of two things.
It may say, I feel weak beside you.
I feel inferior to you.
I'm afraid of you.
or avoiding another person's eyes may say, I feel guilty.
I've done something or I thought something that I don't want you to know.
I'm afraid if I let my eyes connect with yours, you'll see through me.
You say nothing good about yourself when you avoid making eye contact.
You say, I'm afraid.
I lack confidence.
Conquer this fear by making yourself look the other person in the eyes.
Looking the other person in the eye tells him, I'm honest and above board.
I believe in what I'm telling you.
I'm not afraid.
I'm confident.
Make your eyes work for you.
Aim them right at the other person's eyes.
It not only gives you confidence, it wins you confidence too.