But like all progressive companies, we need new products, new markets, new and more efficient ways of doing things.
We depend on people with initiative.
They're the ball carriers on our team.
Initiative is a special kind of action.
It's doing something worthwhile without being told to do it.
The person with initiative has a standing invitation to join the high-income brackets in every business and profession.
The Director of Marketing Research in a medium-sized drug manufacturing firm told me how he got to be a Director of Marketing Research.
It's a good lesson in the power of initiative.
Five years ago, I got an idea, he told me.
I was working then as a sort of missionary salesman, calling on wholesalers.
I discovered that one thing we lacked was facts about the consumers we wanted to buy our drug line.
I talked about the need for market research to everyone here.
At first, I got only deaf ears because management couldn't see the need for it.
I was pretty much obsessed with the idea of marketing research in our company,
so I sort of took the bull by the horns.
I asked and got permission to prepare a monthly report on facts of drug marketing.
I collected information from every source I could find.
I kept on with this, and pretty soon management and the other salesmen found themselves really interested in what I was doing.
Just one year after I started crusading for research, I was relieved of my regular duties and asked to concentrate on developing my ideas.
The rest, he continued, was just natural development.
Now I've got two assistants, a secretary, and about three times the yearly income I had five years ago.
Here are two special exercises for developing the initiative habit.
1.
Be a Crusader.
When you see something that you believe ought to be done, pick up the ball and run.
A new subdivision not far from where I live was about two-thirds built when expansion came almost to a standstill.
A few families with a don't-care attitude had moved in.
This prompted several of the finest families in the area to sell their homes at a loss and move on.