One day, I stopped in to see an old business friend.
She had just returned from a conference with several of her executives.
The moment I looked at her, I could tell there was something she wanted to get off her chest.
She had the look of a woman who had suffered real disappointment.
You know," she said, I called that conference this morning because I wanted some help on a proposed policy change.
But what kind of help did I get?
I had six men in there, and only one of them had anything to contribute.
Two others talked, but what they said was just an echo of what I had said.
It was like talking with a bunch of vegetables.
I confess it's hard for me to find out what those fellows think.
Really, she went on, you'd think those fellows would speak up and let me know what they think.
After all, it directly affects each of them.
My friend didn't get help in the conference.
But had you roamed the hall after the meeting broke up, you'd have heard her junior associates making remarks like,
I felt like saying, why didn't someone suggest, I don't think,
we ought to go ahead.
So, often the vegetables, those who have nothing to say in the conference room,
are full of talk after the meeting, when what they've got to say won't make any difference.
They're suddenly full of life when it's too late.
Business executives want comment.
The fellow who hides his light under a bushel hurts himself.
Get the speak-up habit.