A big thinker always visualizes what can be done in the future.
He isn't stuck with the present.
2.
How much is a customer worth?
A department store executive was addressing a conference of merchandise managers.
She was saying, I may be a little old-fashioned, but I belong to the school that believes the best way to get customers to come back is to give them friendly,
courteous service.
One day I was walking through our store when I overheard a salesperson arguing with a customer.
The customer left in quite a huff.
Afterward, the salesperson said to another, I'm not going to let a $1.98 customer take up all my time and make me take the store apart trying to find him what he wants.
He's simply not worth it.
I walked away, the executive continued.
But I couldn't get that remark out of my mind.
It is pretty serious, I thought, when our salespeople think of customers as being in the $1.98 category.
I decided right then that this concept must be changed.
When I got back to my office, I called our research director and asked him to find out how much the average customer spent in our store last year.
The figure he came up with surprised even me.
According to our research director's careful calculation, the typical customer spent $362 in our establishment.
The next thing I did was call a meeting of all supervisory personnel and explain the incident to them.
Then I showed them what a customer is really worth.
Once I got these people to see that a customer is not to be valued on a single sale,
but rather on an annual basis, customer service definitely improved.
The point made by the retailing executive applies to any kind of business.
It's repeat business that makes the profit.
Often there's no profit at all on the first several sales.
Look at the potential expenditures of the customers, not just what they buy today.
Putting a big value on customers is what converts them into big regular patrons.
Attaching little value to customers sends them elsewhere.