It's true that many factors outside your control do affect your destination.
There may be serious illness or death in your family, the job you're gunning for may be dissolved,
you may meet with an accident.
So here is a point we must fix firmly in mind.
Prepare to take detours in stride.
If you are driving down a road and you come to a road closed situation,
you wouldn't camp there nor would you go back home.
The road closed simply means you can't go where you want to go on this road.
You'd simply find another road to take you where you want to go.
Observe what military leaders do.
When they develop a master plan to take an objective, they also map out alternative plans.
If something unforeseen happens that rules out Plan A, they switch to Plan B. You rest easy in an airplane,
even though the airport where you plan to land is closed in, because you know the fellow up there driving the plane has alternative landing fields and a reserve fuel supply.
It's a rare person who has achieved high-level success who has not had to take detours,
many of them.
When we detour, we don't have to change our goals.
We just travel a different route.
You've probably heard many persons say something like, oh, how I wish I had bought XX stock back in 19 blank.
I'd have a pile of money today.
Normally, people think of investing in terms of stocks or bonds, real estate, or some other type of property.
But the biggest and most rewarding kind of investment is self-investment, purchasing things that build mental power and proficiency.