Chapter 6 You Are What You Think You Are It's obvious.
Much human behavior is puzzling.
Have you ever wondered why a salesperson will greet one customer with an alert,
yes sir, may I serve you, but virtually ignore another?
Or why a man will open a door for one woman, but not for another?
Or why an employee will consistently carry out the instructions of one superior,
but only grudgingly do what another superior requests?
Or why we will pay close attention to what one person says, but not to another?
Look around you.
You'll observe some people receiving the Hey Mac or Hey Buddy treatment,
while others receive the sincere and important Yes Sir treatment.
Watch.
You'll observe that some people command confidence, loyalty, and admiration, while others do not.
Look closer still, and you'll also observe that those persons who command the most respect are also the most successful.
What is the explanation?
It can be distilled into one word, thinking.
Thinking does make it so.
Others see in us what we see in ourselves.
We receive the kind of treatment we think we deserve.
Thinking does make it so.
The fellow who thinks he is inferior, regardless of what his real qualifications may be, is inferior.
for thinking regulates actions.
If a man feels inferior, he acts that way, and no veneer of cover-up or bluff will hide this basic feeling for long.
The person who feels he isn't important isn't.
On the other side, a fellow who really thinks he is equal to the task is.
To be important, we must think we are important, really think so.
Then others will think so too.
Here again is the logic.
How you think determines how you act.
How you act, in turn, determines how others react to you.
Like other phases of your personal program for success, winning respect is fundamentally simple.
To gain the respect of others, you must first think you deserve respect.
And the more respect you have for yourself, the more respect others will have for you.
Test this principle.
Do you have much respect for the fellow on Skid Row?
Of course not.
Why?
Because the poor fellow doesn't respect himself.
He's letting himself rot away from lack of self-respect.
Self-respect shows through in everything we do.
Let's focus our attention now on some of the specific ways we can increase self-respect and thereby earn more respect from others.