Ask yourself every day, what can I do today to make my wife and family happy?
This may seem almost too simple, but it is amazingly effective.
One evening, as part of a sales training program, I was discussing building the home environment for selling success.
To illustrate a point, I asked the salesmen, who were all married, when was the last time,
aside from Christmas, your wedding anniversary, or her birthday, that you surprised your wife with a special gift?
Even I was shocked at the answers.
Of the thirty-five salesmen, only one had surprised his wife in the past month.
Many of the group answered, between three and six months, and over a third said, I can't remember.
Imagine!
And some men wonder why their wives no longer treat them like Mr. King with a crown.
I wanted to impress these salesmen with the power of the thoughtful gift.
The next evening, I arranged to have a florist appear just before the close of the session.
I introduced him and leveled with them.
I want each of you to discover what a little unexpected remembrance will do to build a better home environment.
I've arranged with the florist for each of you to get a fine,
long-stemmed red rose for just fifty cents.
Now, if you don't have fifty cents, or if you think your wife isn't worth that,
" they laughed, "'I'll buy the flower for her myself.
All I ask is that you take the rose to your wife, and then tomorrow evening tell us what happened.
Don't, of course, tell her how you came to purchase this rose for her." They understood.
Without exception, every fellow testified the next evening that the mere investment of 50 cents had made his wife happy.