degree from a leading New York university.
How did he spend his three years in the Army?
Not as an officer.
Not as a staff specialist.
Instead, for three years, he drove a truck.
Why?
Because he was filled with negative attitudes toward fellow soldiers.
I'm superior to them.
Toward Army methods and procedures.
They are stupid.
Toward discipline?
It's for others, not me.
Toward everything, including himself.
I'm a fool for not figuring out a way to escape this wrap.
This fellow earned no respect from anyone.
All his vast store of knowledge lay buried.
His negative attitudes turned him into a flunky.
Remember, the thinking that guides your intelligence is much more important than how much intelligence you have.
Not even a Ph.D.
degree can override this basic success principle.
Several years ago, I became a close friend of Phil F., one of the senior officers of a major advertising agency.
Phil was director of marketing research for the agency, and he was doing a bang-up job.
Was Phil a brain?
Far from it.
Phil knew next to nothing about research technique.
He knew next to nothing about statistics.
He was not a college graduate, though all the people working for him were.
And Phil did not pretend to know the technical side of research.
What then enabled Phil to command $30,000 a year while not one of his subordinates earned $10,000?
This.
Phil was a human engineer.
Phil was 100% positive.
Phil could inspire others when they felt low.
Phil was enthusiastic.
He generated enthusiasm.
Phil understood people.
And because he could really see what made them tick, he liked them.
Not Phil's brains, but how he managed those brains made him three times more valuable to his company than men who rated higher on the IQ scale.
Out of every 100 persons who enroll in college, fewer than 50 will graduate.
I was curious about this, so I asked a director of admissions at a large university for his explanation.
It's not insufficient intelligence, he said.
We don't admit them if they don't have sufficient ability.
And it's not money.
Anyone who wants to support himself in college today can do so.
The real reason is attitudes.
You would be surprised, he said, how many young people leave because they don't like their professors,
the subjects they must take, and their fellow students.
The same reason, negative thinking, explains why the door to top-flight executive positions is closed to many young junior executives.
Sour, negative, pessimistic, depreciating attitudes, rather than insufficient intelligence, hold back thousands of young executives.
As one executive told me, it's a rare case when we pass up a young fellow because he lacks brains.
Nearly always it's attitude.
Once, I was retained by an insurance company to learn why the top 25% of the agents were selling over 75% of the insurance,
while the bottom 25% of the agents sold only 5% of total volume.
Thousands of personnel files were carefully checked.
The search proved beyond any question that no significant difference existed in native intelligence.
What's more, differences in education did not explain the difference in selling success.
The difference in the very successful and the very unsuccessful finally reduced to differences in attitudes or difference in thought management.
The top group worried less, was more enthusiastic, had a sincere liking for people.