Chapter 3 Build Confidence and Destroy Fear Friends mean well when they say,
it's only your imagination, don't worry, there's nothing to be afraid of.
But you and I know this kind of fear medicine never really works.
Such soothing remarks may give us fear relief for a few minutes or maybe even a few hours,
but the it's only in your imagination treatment doesn't really build confidence and cure fear.
Yes, fear is real and we must recognize it exists before we can conquer it.
Most fear today is psychological.
Worry, tension, embarrassment, panic, all stem from mismanaged negative imagination.
But simply knowing the breeding ground of fear doesn't cure fear.
If a physician discovers you have an infection in some part of your body, he doesn't stop there.
He proceeds with treatment to cure the infection.
The old it's only in your mind treatment presumes fear doesn't really exist, but it does.
Fear is real.
Fear is success enemy number one.
Fear stops people from capitalizing on opportunity.
Fear wears down physical vitality.
Fear actually makes people sick, causes organic difficulties, shortens life.
Fear closes your mouth when you want to speak.
Fear, uncertainty, lack of confidence, explains why we still have economic recessions.
Fear explains why millions of people accomplish little and enjoy little.
Truly, fear is a powerful force.
In one way or another, fear prevents people from getting what they want from life.
Fear of all kinds and sizes is a form of psychological infection.
We can cure a mental infection the same way we cure a body infection, with specific proved treatments.
First, though, as part of your pre-treatment preparation, condition yourself with this fact.
All confidence is acquired, developed.
No one is born with confidence.
Those people you know who radiate confidence, who have conquered worry, who are at ease everywhere and all the time,
acquired their confidence, every bit of it.
You can too.
This chapter shows how.