Several years ago, after addressing a group of businessmen in Detroit, I talked with one of the gentlemen who approached me,
introduced himself, and said, I really enjoyed your talk.
Can you spare a few minutes?
I'd like very much to discuss a personal experience with you.
In a few minutes, we were comfortably seated in a coffee shop, waiting for some refreshments.
I have a personal experience, he began, that ties in perfectly with what you said this evening about making your mind work for you instead of letting it work against you.
I've never explained to anyone how I lifted myself out of the world of mediocrity,
but I'd like to tell you about it.
And I'd like to hear it, I said.
Well, just five years ago, I was plodding along, just another guy working in the tool-and-die trade.
I made a decent living, by average standards, but it was far from ideal.
Our home was much too small, and there was no money for those many things we wanted.
My wife, bless her, didn't complain much, but it was written all over her that she was more resigned to her fate than she was happy.
Inside, I grew more and more dissatisfied.
When I let myself see how I was failing my good wife and two children, I really hurt inside.
But today things are really different, my friend continued.
Today we have a beautiful new home on a two-acre lot and a year-round cabin a couple hundred miles north of here.
There's no more worry about whether we can send the kids to a good college,
and my wife no longer has to feel guilty every time she spends money for some new clothes.
Next summer, the whole family is flying to Europe to spend a month's holiday.
We're really living.
How did all this happen, I ask?
It all happened, he continued, when, to use the phrase you used tonight, I harnessed the power of belief.
Five years ago I learned about a job with a tool-and-dye company here in Detroit.
We were living in Cleveland at the time.
I decided to look into it, hoping I could make a little more money.
I got here early on Sunday evening, but the interview was not until Monday.
After dinner I sat down in my hotel room and for some reason I got really disgusted with myself.
Why, I asked myself, am I just a middle-class failure?
Why am I trying to get a job that represents such a small step forward?
I don't know to this day what prompted me to do it,
but I took a sheet of hotel stationery and wrote down the names of five people I've known well for several years who had far surpassed me in earning power and job responsibility.
Two were former neighbors who had moved away to find subdivisions, two others were fellows I had worked for,