The more I can learn about other people, their ideas, interests, viewpoints, the better job I can do in giving them the merchandise and service they want and will buy.
Here are a few simple do's to help make your social environment first class.
1.
Do circulate in new groups.
Restricting your social environment to the same small group produces boredom, dullness, dissatisfaction.
Equally important, remember that your success-building program requires that you become an expert in understanding people.
Trying to learn all there is to know about people by studying one small group is like trying to master mathematics by reading one short book.
make new friends, join new organizations, enlarge your social orbit.
Then too, variety in people, like variety in anything else, adds spice to life and gives it a broader dimension.
It's good mind food.
2.
Do select friends who have views different from your own.
In this modern age, the narrow individual hasn't much future.
Responsibility and positions of importance gravitate to the person who is able to see both sides.
If you're a Republican, make sure you have some friends who are Democrats, and vice versa.
Get to know people of different religious faiths.
Associate with opposites, but just be sure they are persons with real potential.
3.
Do select friends who stand above petty, unimportant things.
Folks who are more concerned with the square footage of your home or the appliances you have or don't have than with your ideas and your conversation are inclined to be petty.
Guard your psychological environment.
Select friends who are interested in positive things.
Friends who really do want to see you succeed.
Find friends who breathe encouragement into your plans and ideals.
If you don't, if you select petty thinkers as your close friends,
you'll gradually develop into a petty thinker yourself.
We're a poison-conscious nation.
Body poison, that is.
Every restaurateur is on guard against food poisoning.
Just a couple of cases of it, and his patrons won't come near his place.
We've got tons of laws to protect the public against hundreds of body poisons.