You often hear that certain jobs require considerable physical maturity, jobs like selling securities and insurance.
That you've got to have either gray hair or no hair at all in order to gain an investor's confidence is plain nonsense.
What really matters is how well you know your job.
If you know your job and understand people, you're sufficiently mature to handle it.
Age has no real relation to ability, unless you convince yourself that years alone will give you the stuff you need to make your mark.
Many young people feel that they are being held back because of their youth.
Now, it is true that another person in an organization who is insecure and job-scared may try to block your way forward,
using age or some other reason.
But the people who really count in the company will not.
They will give you as much responsibility as they feel you can handle well.
Demonstrate that you have ability and positive attitudes, and your youthfulness will be considered an advantage.
In quick recap, the cure for age excusitis is, number one, look at your present age positively.
Think, I'm still young, not I'm already old.
Practice looking forward to new horizons and gain the enthusiasm and the feel of youth.
Number two, compute how much productive time you have left.
Remember, a person age 30 still has 80% of his productive life ahead of him.
And the 50-year-old still has a big 40%, the best 40%, of his opportunity years left.
Life is actually longer than most people think.
Three, invest future time in doing what you really want to do.
It's too late only when you let your mind go negative and think it's too late.
Stop thinking, I should have started years ago.
That's failure thinking.
Instead think, I'm going to start now.
My best years are ahead of me.
That's the way successful people think.