The most important person present is the one person most active in introducing himself.
It's always a big person who walks up to you, offers his hand,
and says, Hello, I'm Jack R. Digest this observation for a moment,
and you'll discover the reason the fellow is important is that he works at building friendships.
Think right toward people.
As a friend of mine expresses it, I may not be very important to him,
but he's important to me.
That's why I've got to get to know him.
Have you ever noticed how people freeze while waiting for elevators?
Unless they are with someone they know, most folks never say anything to the person standing beside them.
One day, I resolved to do a little experimenting.
I resolved to say something to the stranger who was waiting as I was.
I kept track of his reaction 25 consecutive times.
And 25 times, I got back a positive, friendly response.
Now, talking to strangers may not be very urbane, but most people like it nevertheless.
And here is the big payoff.
When you make a pleasant remark to a stranger, you make him feel one degree better.
This makes you feel better and helps you relax.
Every time you say something pleasant to another person, you compensate yourself.
It's like warming up your automobile on a cold morning.
Here are six ways to win friends by exercising just a little initiative.
1.
Introduce yourself to others at every possible opportunity, at parties, meetings, on airplanes, at work, everywhere.
2.
Be sure the other person gets your name straight.
3.
Be sure you can pronounce the other person's name the way he pronounces it.
4.
Write down the other person's name and be mighty sure you have it spelled correctly.
People have a fetish about the correct spelling of their own names.
If possible, get his address and phone number also.
5.
Drop a personal note or make a phone call to the new friends you feel you want to know better.
This is an important point.
Most successful people follow through on new friends with a letter or a phone call.
Six, and last but not least, say pleasant things to strangers.
It warms you up and gets you ready for the task ahead.
Putting these six rules to work is really thinking right about people.
To be sure, it is not the way the average person thinks.
Mr. Average never takes the initiative in making introductions.
He waits for the other person to introduce himself first.
Take the initiative.
Be like the successful.
Go out of your way to meet people.
And don't be timid.
Don't be afraid to be unusual.
Find out who the other person is, and be sure he knows who you are.
Recently, an associate and I were retained to do a preliminary screening of an applicant for an industrial sales job.
We found the applicant, whom we'll call Ted, to have some good qualifications.
He was exceptionally intelligent, made a fine appearance, and seemed to have a lot of ambition.
But we found something that forced us to disqualify him, at least temporarily.
Ted's big limitation was this.
He expected perfection in other people.
Ted was annoyed by many little things, like mistakes in grammar, people who were messy with cigarettes,
people who had bad taste in clothes, and so on.
Ted was surprised to learn this fact about himself, but he was eager to get into higher-paying work,
and he asked whether there was anything we could tell him to help overcome his weakness.