Successfully resist the temptation to argue and quarrel by 1.
Asking yourself, honestly now, is this thing really important enough to argue about?
2.
Reminding yourself you never gain anything from an argument, but you always lose something.
Think big enough to see that quarrels, arguments, feuds, and fusses will never help you get where you want to go.
D. When you feel defeated, think big.
It is not possible to achieve large success without hardships and setbacks, but it is possible to live the rest of your life without defeat.
Big thinkers react to setbacks this way.
1.
Regard the setback as a lesson.
Research it.
Use it to propel you forward.
Salvage something from every setback.
2.
Blend persistence with experimentation.
Back off and start afresh with a new approach.
Think big enough to see that defeat is a state of mind, nothing more.
E. When romance starts to slip, think big.
Negative, petty, she's-he's-unfair-to-me-so-I'll-get-even type of thinking slaughters romance,
destroys the affection that can be yours.
Do this when things aren't going right in the love department.
1.
Concentrate on the biggest qualities in the person you want to love you.
Put little things where they belong, in second place.
Two, do something special for your mate and do it often.
Think big enough to find the secret to marital joys.
F, when you feel your progress on the job is slowing down, think big.
No matter what you do and regardless of your occupation, higher status, higher pay come from one thing,
increasing the quality and quantity of your output.
Do this.
Think, I can do better.
The best is not unattainable.
There is room for doing everything better.
Nothing in this world is being done as well as it could be.
And when you think, I can do better, ways to do better will appear.
Thinking, I can do better, switches on your creative power.
Think big enough to see that if you put service first, money takes care of itself.
In the words of Publilius Cyrus, a wise man will be master of his mind,
a fool will be its slave.