Chapter 4 How to Think Big Recently, I chatted with a recruitment specialist for one of the nation's largest industrial organizations.
Four months each year, she visits college campuses to recruit graduating seniors for her company's junior executive training program.
The tenor of her remarks indicated that she was discouraged about the attitudes of many people she talked with.
Most days, I interview between eight and twelve college seniors, all in the upper third of their class,
all at least mildly interested in coming with us.
One of the main things we want to determine in the screening interview is the individual's motivation.
We want to find out if he or she is the kind of person who can,
in a few years, direct major projects, manage a branch office or plant,
or in some other way make a really substantial contribution to the company.
I must say I'm not too pleased with the personal objectives of most of those I talk with.
You'd be surprised," she went on.
How many 22-year-olds are more interested in our retirement plan than in anything else we have to offer?
A second favorite question is, will I move around a lot?
Most of them seem to define the word success as synonymous with security.
Can we risk turning our company over to people like that?
The thing I can't understand is why should young people these days be so ultra-conservative,
so narrow in their view of the future?
Every day there are more signs of expanding opportunity.
This country is making record progress in scientific and industrial development.
Our population is gaining rapidly.
If there ever was a time to be bullish about America, it's now.
The tendency for so many people to think small means there is less competition than you think for a very rewarding career.
Where success is concerned, people are not measured in inches or pounds or college degrees or family background.
They are measured by the size of their thinking.
How big we think determines the size of our accomplishments.
Now, let's see how we can enlarge our thinking.