Many, many potentially powerful people let petty, small, insignificant things block their way to achievement.
Let's look at four examples.
1.
What does it take to make a good speech?
Just about everyone wishes he had the ability to do a first-class job of speaking in public.
But most people don't get their wish.
Most folks are lousy public speakers.
Why?
The reason is simple.
Most people concentrate on the small, trivial things of speaking at the expense of the big, important things.
In preparing to give a talk, most people give themselves a host of mental instructions,
like, I've got to remember to stand straight, don't move around and don't use your hands,
don't let the audience see you use your notes, remember, don't make mistakes in grammar,
especially don't say, for he and I, say, for him and me,
be sure your tie is straight, speak loud but not too loud, and so on and so on.
Now, what happens when the speaker gets up to speak?
He's scared because he's given himself a terrific list of things not to do.
He gets confused in his talk and finds himself silently asking, have I made a mistake?
He is, in brief, a flop.
He's a flop because he concentrated on the petty, trivial, relatively unimportant qualities of a good speaker and failed to concentrate on the big things that make a good speaker.
knowledge of what he's going to talk about, and an intense desire to tell it to other people.
The real test of a speaker is not did he stand straight or did he make any mistakes in grammar,
but rather did the audience get the points he wanted to put across.
Most of our top speakers have petty defects.
Some of them even have unpleasant voices.
Some of the most sought-after speakers in America would flunk a speech course taught by the old negative,
don't do this and don't do that method.
Yet all these successful public speakers have one thing in common.
They have something to say and they feel a burning desire for other people to hear it.
Don't let concern with trivia keep you from speaking successfully in public.