We human beings are curious creatures.
We're quick to accept full credit for our victories.
When we win, we want the world to know about it.
It's natural to want others to look at you and say, there goes the fellow who did such and such.
But human beings are equally quick to blame someone else for each setback.
It's natural for salesmen to blame customers when sales are lost.
It's natural for executives to blame employees or other executives when things get out of gear.
It's natural for husbands to blame wives and wives to blame husbands for quarrels and family problems.
It is true that in this complex world, others may trip us.
But it is also true that more often than not, we trip ourselves.
We lose because of personal inadequacy, some personal mistake.
Condition yourself for success this way.
Remind yourself that you want to be as nearly perfect as is humanly possible.
Be objective.
Put yourself in a glass tube and look at yourself as a disinterested third party would look at the situation.
See if you have a weakness that you've never noticed before.
If you have, take action to correct it.
Many people become so accustomed to themselves that they fail to see ways for improvement.
The great Metropolitan Opera star Reza Stevens said in Reader's Digest, July 1955,
that at the unhappiest moment of her life, she received the best advice she's ever had.
Early in her career, Ms. Stevens lost the Metropolitan Opera auditions of the air.
After losing, Miss Stevens was bitter.
I longed to hear, she said, that my voice was really better than the other girls,
that the verdict was grossly unfair, that I had just lacked the right connections to win.
But Miss Stevens's teacher didn't coddle her.
Instead, she said to Miss Stevens, My dear, have the courage to face your faults.
Much as I wanted to fall back on self-pity, continued Miss Stevens,
they, those words, kept coming back to me.
That night they woke me.
I couldn't sleep until I faced my shortcomings.
Lying there in the dark, I asked myself, why did I fail?
How can I win next time?
And I admitted to myself that my voice range was not as good as it had to be,
that I had to perfect my languages, that I must learn more roles.
Miss Stevens went on to say how facing her faults not only helped her to succeed on stage,
but also helped her win more friends and develop a more pleasing personality.
Being self-critical is constructive.
It helps you to build the personal strength and efficiency needed for success.
Blaming others is destructive.
You gain absolutely nothing from proving that someone else is wrong.
Be constructively self-critical.
Don't run away from inadequacies.
Be like the real professionals.
They seek out their faults and weaknesses, then correct them.
That's what makes them professionals.
Don't, of course, try to find your faults so you can say to yourself,
here's another reason I'm a loser.
Instead, view your mistakes as, here's another way to make me a bigger winner.
The great Orville Hubbard once said, A failure is a man who has blundered but is not able to cash in on the experience.