We can't do much to change the amount of native ability, but we can certainly change the way we use what we have.
Knowledge is power when you use it constructively.
Closely allied to intelligence excusitis is some incorrect thinking about knowledge.
We often hear that knowledge is power, but this statement is only a half-truth.
Knowledge is only potential power.
Knowledge is power only when put to use, and then only when the use made of it is constructive.
The story is told that the great scientist Einstein was once asked how many feet are in a mile.
Einstein's reply was, I don't know.
Why should I fill my brain with facts I can find in two minutes in any standard reference book?
Einstein taught us a big lesson.
He felt it was more important to use your mind to think than to use it as a warehouse for facts.
One time Henry Ford was involved in a libel suit with the Chicago Tribune.
The Tribune had called Ford an ignoramus, and Ford said, in effect, prove it.
The Tribune asked him scores of simple questions, such as who was Benedict Arnold,
when was the Revolutionary War fought, and others, most of which Ford, who had little formal education,
could not answer.
Finally, he became quite exasperated and said, I don't know the answers to those questions,
but I could find a man in five minutes who does.
Henry Ford was never interested in miscellaneous information.
He knew what every major executive knows, that the ability to know how to get information is more important than using the mind as a garage for facts.
How much is a fact man worth?