Chapter 1 Believe You Can Succeed and You Will Success means many wonderful, positive things.
Success means personal prosperity, a fine home, vacations, travel, new things, financial security, giving your children maximum advantages.
Success means winning admiration, leadership, being looked up to by people in your business and social life.
Success means freedom, freedom from worries, fears, frustrations, and failure.
Success means self-respect, continually finding more real happiness and satisfaction from life,
being able to do more for those who depend on you.
Success means winning.
Success, achievement, is the goal of life.
Every human being wants success.
Everybody wants the best this life can deliver.
Nobody enjoys crawling, living in mediocrity.
No one likes feeling second class and feeling forced to go that way.