Step one, believe it can be done.
Here is a basic truth.
To do anything, we must first believe it can be done.
Believing something can be done sets the mind in motion to find a way to do it.
To illustrate this point of creative thinking in training sessions, I often use this example.
I ask the group, how many of you feel it is possible to eliminate jails within the next 30 years?
Invariably, the group looks bewildered, not quite sure they heard right and thinking they are listening to a real fuzzbrain.
So, after a pause, I repeat, how many of you feel it is possible to eliminate jails within the next thirty years?
Once they're sure I'm not joking, someone always blasts me with something like,
you mean to say you want to turn all those murderers, thieves, and rapists loose?
Don't you realize what this would mean?
Why none of us would be safe.
We have to have jails.
Then the others cut loose.
All order would break down if we didn't have jails.
Some people are born criminals.
If anything, we need more jails.
Did you read in this morning's paper about that murder?" And the group goes on,
telling me all sorts of good reasons why we must have jails.
One fellow even suggested we've got to have jails so the police and prison guards can have jobs.
After about ten minutes of letting the group prove why we can't eliminate the need for jails,
I say to them, Now, let me mention here that this question of eliminating jails is used to make a point.
Each of you has come up with reasons why we can't eliminate the need for jails.
Will you do me a favor?
Will you try extra hard for a few minutes to believe we can eliminate jails?
Joining in the spirit of the experiment, the group says, in effect, all well, but just for kicks.
Then I ask, now, assuming we can eliminate jails, how could we begin?