Take this test to measure the size of your thinking.
Here listed are several common situations of how petty thinkers and big thinkers see the same situation.
Check yourself, then decide, which will get me where I want to go?
Petty thinking or big thinking?
The same situation handled in two entirely different ways.
The choice is yours.
Situation.
Expense accounts.
The Petty Thinker's Approach figures out ways to increase income through chiseling on expense accounts.
The Big Thinker's Approach figures out ways to increase income by selling more merchandise.
Situation Conversation The Petty Thinker's Approach talks about the negative qualities of his friends,
the economy, his company, the competition.
The big thinkers approach talks about the positive qualities of his friends, his company, the competition.
Progress believes in retrenchment or at best the status quo or believes in expansion.
Future views the future as limited or sees the future as very promising.
looks for ways to avoid work, or looks for more ways and things to do, especially helping others.
Competition.
Competes with the average, or competes with the best.
Budget problems.
Figures out ways to save money by cutting down on necessary items, or figures out ways to increase income and buy more of the necessary items.
Goals – sets goals low or sets goals high.
Goals vision – sees only the short run or is preoccupied with the long run.
Security – is preoccupied with security problems or regards security as a natural companion of success.
Companionship surrounds himself with petty thinkers or surrounds himself with persons with large progressive ideas.
Mistakes magnifies minor errors, turns them into big issues, or ignores errors of little consequence.