Grow these three attitudes.
Make them your allies in everything you do.
1.
Grow the attitude of, I'm activated.
2.
Grow the attitude of, you are important.
3.
Grow the attitude of, service first.
Now, let's see how.
Years ago, when I was a college sophomore, I enrolled in an American history class.
I remember the class vividly, not because I learned much about American history,
but because, in an unusual way, I learned this basic principle of successful living.
To activate others, you must first activate yourself.
The history class was very large, and it was held in a fan-shaped auditorium.
The professor, who was a middle-aged fellow and apparently well-educated, was nevertheless pathetically dull.
Rather than interpret history as an alive, fascinating subject, the professor merely cited one dead fact after another.
It was a frightful wonder how he could possibly make such an interesting subject so terribly dull.
But he did.
You can imagine the effect the professor's boredom had on the students.
Talking and sleeping got so out of hand that the professor had two assistants patrol the aisles to break up student conversations and wake up those who had dozed off.
Occasionally, the professor would stop and, shaking his finger at the class, would say,
I'm warning you, you've got to pay attention to what I say.
You've got to stop this talking, and that's all there is to it.
This, of course, made little impression on his students, many of whom, as veterans,
had gambled their lives only months before, had made history on islands and in bombers.
As I sat there watching this potentially great, wonderful experience turn into a disgusting farce,
I found myself wrestling with the question, why are the students ignoring what the professor has to say?
The answer came.