Persons who reach the top rungs in business management, selling, engineering, religious work,
writing, acting, and in every other pursuit, get there by following conscientiously and continuously a plan for self-development and growth.
Any training program, and that's exactly what this book is, must do three things.
It must provide content, the what to do.
Second, it must supply a method, the how to do it.
And third, it must meet the ACID test, that is, get results.
The what of your personal training program for success is built on the attitudes and techniques of successful people.
How do they manage themselves?
How do they overcome obstacles?
How do they earn the respect of others?
What sets them apart from the ordinary?
How do they think?
The how of your plan for development and growth is a series of concrete guides for action.
These are found in each chapter.
These guides work.
Apply them and see for yourself.
What about the most important part of training?
Results?
Wrapped up briefly, conscientious application of the program presented here will bring you success and on a scale that may now look impossible.
Broken down into its components, your personal training program for success will bring you a series of rewards.
The reward of deeper respect from your family, the reward of admiration from your friends and associates,
the reward of feeling useful, of being someone, of having status, the reward of increased income and a higher standard of living.
Your training is self-administered.
There will be no one standing over your shoulder telling you what to do and how to do it.
This book will be your guide, but only you can understand yourself.
Only you can command yourself to apply this training.
Only you can evaluate your progress.
Only you can bring about corrective action should you slip a little.
In short, you are going to train yourself to achieve bigger and bigger success.
You already have a fully equipped laboratory in which you can work and study.
Your laboratory is all around you.
Your laboratory consists of human beings.