There's a story often told about the job attitudes of three bricklayers.
It's a classic, so let's go over it again.
When asked, what are you doing?
The first bricklayer replied, laying brick.
The second answered, making $9.30 an hour.
And the third said, me?
Why, I'm building the world's greatest cathedral.
Now, the story doesn't tell us what happened to these bricklayers in later years,
but what do you think happened?
Chances are that the first two bricklayers remained just that, bricklayers.
They lacked vision.
They lacked job respect.
There was nothing behind them to propel them forward to greater success.
But you can wager every cent you have, the bricklayer who visualized himself as building a great cathedral did not remain a bricklayer.
Perhaps he became a foreman, or perhaps a contractor, or possibly an architect.
He moved forward and upward.
Why?
Because thinking does make it so.
Bricklayer No.
3 was tuned to thought channels that pointed the way to self-development in his work.
Job thinking tells a lot about a person and his potential for larger responsibility.
A friend who operates a personnel selection firm said this to me recently.
One thing we always look for in appraising a job applicant for a client is how the applicant thinks about his present job.
We are always favorably impressed when we find that an applicant thinks his present job is important,
even though there may be something about it he doesn't like.
Why?
Simply this.
If the applicant feels his present job is important, odds are that he will take pride in his next job,
too.
We've found an amazingly close correlation between a person's job respect and his job performance.
Like your appearance, the way you think toward your work says things about you to your superiors, associates, and subordinates.
In fact, to everyone with whom you come in contact.
A few months ago I spent several hours with a friend who is personnel director for an appliance manufacturer.
We talked about building men.
He explained his personnel audit system and what he had learned from it.
We have about 800 non-production people, he began.
Under our personnel audit system, an assistant and I interview each employee every six months.
Our purpose is simple.
We want to learn how we can help him in his job.
We think this is a good practice because each person working with us is important,
else he wouldn't be on the payroll.
We are careful not to ask the employees any point-blank questions.
Instead, we encourage him to talk about whatever he wants to.
We aim to get his honest impressions.
After each interview, we fill out a rating form on the employee's attitudes toward specific aspects of his job.
Now here's something I've learned, he went on.
Our employees fit into one of two categories, Group A and Group B,
on the basis of how they think toward their jobs.
The persons in Group B talk mainly about security, company retirement plans, sick leave policy,
extra time off, what we're doing to improve the insurance program, and if they will be asked to work overtime next March as they were last March.
They also talk a lot about disagreeable features of their job, things they don't like in fellow workers,
and so on.
People in Group B, and they include close to eighty percent of all non-production personnel,
view their jobs as a sort of necessary evil.
The Group A fellow sees his job through different glasses.
He is concerned about his future and wants concrete suggestions on what he can do to make faster progress.
He doesn't expect us to give him anything except a chance.
The Group A people think on a broader scale.
They make suggestions for improving the business.
They regard these interviews in my office as constructive.
But the Group B people often feel our personnel audit system is just a brainwashing affair,
and they're glad to get it over with.