Chapter 5 How to Think and Dream Creatively First, let's clear up a common fallacy about the meaning of creative thinking.
For some illogical reason, science, engineering, art, and writing got tabbed as about the only truly creative pursuits.
Most people associate creative thinking with things like the discovery of electricity, or a polio vaccine,
or the writing of a novel, or the development of color television.
Certainly, accomplishments like these are evidence of creative thinking.
Each forward step made in the conquest of space is the result of creative thinking, lots of it.
But creative thinking is not reserved for certain occupations, nor is it restricted to super-intelligent people.
Well then, what is creative thinking?
A low-income family devises a plan to send their son to a leading university.
That's creative thinking.
A family turns the street's most undesirable lot into the neighborhood beauty spot.
A minister develops a plan that doubles his Sunday evening attendance.
That's creative thinking.
Figuring out ways to simplify record-keeping, selling the impossible customer, keeping the children occupied constructively,
making employees really like their work, or preventing a certain quarrel.
All of these are examples of practical, everyday creative thinking.
Creative thinking is simply finding new improved ways to do anything.
The rewards of all types of success, success in the home, at work,
in the community, hinge on finding ways to do things better.
Now, let's see what we can do to develop and strengthen our creative thinking ability.