Put this principle to work next time you must do something you don't want to do.
Put this principle to work next time you find yourself becoming bored.
Just dig in deeper and you dig up interest.
2.
In everything you do, life it up.
Enthusiasm, or lack of it, shows through in everything you do and say.
Life up your handshaking.
When you shake hands, shake.
Make your hand clasp say, I'm glad to know you.
I am glad to see you again.
A conservative mouse-like handshake is worse than no handshake at all.
It makes people think, this guy is more dead than alive.
Try to find a highly successful person with a conservative handshake.
You'll have to look a long, long time.
Life up your smiles.
Smile with your eyes.
Nobody likes an artificial, pasted-on, rubbery smile.
When you smile, smile.
Show a few teeth.
Maybe your teeth aren't attractive, but that's really unimportant.
For when you smile, people don't see your teeth.
They see a warm, enthusiastic personality, someone they like.
Life up your thank yous.
A routine, automatic thank you is almost like saying, GLEEP GLEEP.
It's just an expression.
It says nothing.
It doesn't accomplish results.
Make your thank you mean thank you very much.
Life up your talk!
Dr. James F. Bender, the noted speech authority, in his excellent book, How to Talk Well,
says, Is your good morning really good?
Are your congratulations enthusiastic?
Does your how are you sound interested?
When you make a habit of coloring your words with sincere feelings, you'll notice a great uptake in your ability to hold attention.
People go along with the fellow who believes what he says.
Say it with life.
Put vitality into your speaking.
Whether you are talking to a garden club, a prospect, or your children, put enthusiasm behind what you say.
A sermon delivered enthusiastically may be remembered for months, even years.
But a sermon delivered without enthusiasm will be mostly forgotten 167 hours before next Sunday rolls around.
And when you put life in your talk, you automatically put more life in you.
Just try this right now.
Say out loud with force and vigor, I feel great today.
Now, don't you actually feel better than you did before you said it?
Make yourself alive all over.
Life it up.
Be sure everything you do and say tells people that fellow is alive.
He means it.
He's going places.
3.