1.
Be an activationist.
Be someone who does things.
Be a doer, not a don'ter.
2.
Don't wait until conditions are perfect.
They never will be.
Expect future obstacles and difficulties, and solve them as they arise.
3.
Remember, ideas alone won't bring success.
Ideas have value only when you act upon them.
Four, use action to cure fear and gain confidence.
Do what you fear and fear disappears.
Just try it and see.
Five, start your mental engine mechanically.
Don't wait for the spirit to move you.
Take action, dig in, and you move the spirit.
6.
Think in terms of now.
Tomorrow, next week, later, and similar words often are synonymous with the failure word, never.
Be an, I'm starting right now, kind of person.
7.
Get down to business, pronto.
Don't waste time getting ready to act.
Start acting instead.
8.
Seize the initiative.
Be a crusader.
Pick up the ball and run.
Be a volunteer.
Show that you have ability and ambition to do.
Get in gear and go.