Why do people fear other people?
Why do many folks feel self-conscious around others?
What's behind shyness?
What can we do about it?
Fear of other people is a big fear, but there is a way to conquer it.
You can conquer fear of people if you will learn to put them into proper perspective.
A business friend, who was doing exceptionally well operating his own wood novelty plant,
explained to me how he got the proper perspective of people.
This example is interesting.
Before I went into the army in World War II, I was scared of just about everybody.
You just wouldn't believe how shy and timid I was.
I felt everyone else was a lot smarter.
I worried about my physical and mental inadequacies.
I thought I was born to fail.
Then by some fortunate quirk of fate, I lost my fear of people in the army.
During part of 1942 and 1943, when the Army was inducting men at a terrific clip,
I was stationed as a medic at one of the big induction centers.
Day after day, I assisted in examining those men.
The more I looked at these recruits, the less afraid of people I became.
All those men lined up by the hundreds, naked as jaybirds, looked so much alike.
Oh, sure, there were fat ones and skinny ones, tall ones and short ones,
but they all were confused, all were lonesome.
Just a few days before, some of these were rising young executives.
Some were farmers, some were salesmen, drifters, blue-collar workers.
A few days before, they had been many things, but at the induction center, they were all alike.
I figured out something pretty basic back then.
I discovered people are alike in many, many more ways than they are different.
I discovered the other fellow is pretty much like me.
He likes good food, he misses his family and friends, he wants to get ahead,
he has problems, he likes to relax.
So if the other fellow is basically like me, there's no point in being afraid of him.
Now, doesn't that make sense?
If the other fellow is basically like me, there's no reason to be afraid of him.
Here are two ways to put people in proper perspective.