Now he owns five, and he has purchased seventeen acres for his country estate.
He's thinking and progressing right along toward his goal.
The three departments of your life are closely interrelated.
Each depends on the others to some extent, but the one department that has the most influence over the other departments is your work.
Thousands of years ago, the caveman who had the happiest home life and was most respected by his cavemates was the fellow who was most successful as a hunter.
As a generalization, the same point holds true today.
The standard of living we provide our families, and the social and community respect we attain,
depends largely on our success in the work department.
Not long ago, the McKinsey Foundation for Management Research conducted a large-scale study to determine what it takes to become an executive.
Leaders in business, government, science, and religion were questioned.
Over and over again, in different ways, these researchers kept getting one answer.
The most important qualification for an executive is the sheer desire to get ahead.
Remember this advice of John Wanamaker.
A man is not doing much until the cause he works for possesses all there is of him.
Desire, when harnessed, is power.
Failure to follow desire, to do what you want to do most, paves the way to mediocrity.
I recall a conversation with a very promising young writer on a college newspaper.
This fellow had ability.
If anyone showed promise for a career in journalism, it was he.
Shortly before his graduation, I asked him, Well, Dan, what are you going to do,
get into some form of journalism?
Dan looked at me and said, heck no.
I like writing and reporting very much, and I've had a lot of fun working on the college paper.
But journalists are a dime a dozen, and I don't want to starve.
I didn't see or hear from Dan for five years.
Then one evening I chanced to meet him in New Orleans.
Dan was working as an assistant personnel director for an electronics company.
And he was quick to let me know that he was quite dissatisfied with his work.
Oh, I'm reasonably well paid, I'm with a wonderful company, and I've got reasonable security.
But you know, my heart isn't in it.
I wish now I'd gone with a publisher or a newspaper when I finished school.
Dan's attitude reflected boredom, uninterest.
He was cynical about many things.
He will never achieve maximum success until he quits his present job and gets into journalism.
Success requires heart and soul effort, and you can put your heart and soul only into something you really desire.
Had Dan followed his desire, he could have risen to the very top in some phase of communication,
and over the long pull he would have made much more money and achieved far more personal satisfaction than he will find in his present kind of work.
Switching from what you don't like to do to what you do like to do is like putting a 500 horsepower motor in a ten-year-old car.
All of us have desires.
All of us dream of what we really want to do.
But few of us actually surrender to desire.
Instead of surrendering to desire, we murder it.
Five weapons are used to commit success suicide.
Destroy them.
They're dangerous.
1.