Ever ask yourself, what is my greatest weakness?
Probably the greatest human weakness is self-deprecation, that is, selling oneself short.
Self-deprecation shows through in countless ways.
John sees a job advertisement in the paper.
It's exactly what he would like.
But he does nothing about it because he thinks, I'm not good enough for that job, so why bother?
Or Jim wants a date with Joan, but he doesn't call her because he thinks he wouldn't rate with her.
Tom feels Mr. Richards would be a very good prospect for his product, but Tom doesn't call.
He feels Mr. Richards is too big to see him.
Pete is filling out a job application form.
One question asks, what beginning salary do you expect?
Pete puts down a modest figure because he feels he really isn't worth the bigger sum he would like to earn.
Philosophers for thousands of years have issued good advice, know thyself.
But most people, it seems, interpret this suggestion to mean know only thy negative self.
Most self-evaluation consists of making long mental lists of one's faults, shortcomings, inadequacies.
It's well to know our inabilities, for this shows us areas in which we can improve.
But if we know only our negative characteristics, we're in a mess.
Our value is small.
Here is an exercise to help you measure your true size.
I've used it in training programs for executives and sales personnel.
It works.
1.
Determine your five chief assets.
Invite some objective friend to help, possibly your wife, your superior, a professor,
some intelligent person who will give you an honest opinion.
Examples of assets frequently listed are education, experience, technical skills, appearance, well-adjusted home life, attitudes, personality, initiative.
2.
Next, under each asset, write the names of three persons you know who have achieved large success but who do not have this asset to as great a degree as you.
When you've completed this exercise, you will find you outrank many successful people on at least one asset.
There is only one conclusion you can honestly reach.
You're bigger than you think.
So fit your thinking to your true size.
Think as big as you really are.
Never, never, never sell yourself short.