We've got tons of laws to protect the public against hundreds of body poisons.
We put, or should put, poisons on the top shelves so the kids can't reach them.
We go to any extreme to avoid body poison, and it's good that we do.
But there's another type of poison, perhaps a little more insidious, thought poison, commonly called gossip.
Thought poison differs from body poison in two ways.
It affects the mind, not the body, and is more subtle.
The person being poisoned usually doesn't know it.
Thought poison is subtle, but it accomplishes big things.
It reduces the size of our thinking by forcing us to concentrate on petty, unimportant things.
It warps and twists our thinking about people because it is based on a distortion of facts,
and it creates a guilt feeling in us that shows through when we meet the person we've gossiped about.
Thought poison is 0% right thinking.
It is 100% wrong thinking.
And contrary to lots of opinion, women have no exclusive franchise on gossip.
Every day, many men, too, live in a partially poisoned environment.
Every day thousands of gossip fests staged by men take place on such topics as the boss's marital or financial problems,
Bill's politicking to get ahead in business, the probability of John being transferred,
the reasons for special favors being awarded Tom, and why they brought in that new man.
Gossiping goes something like this.
Say, I just heard.
No, why?
Well, it doesn't surprise me.
He had it coming to him.
Of course, this is confidential.
Conversation is a big part of our psychological environment.
Some conversation is healthy.
It encourages you.
It makes you feel like you're taking a walk in the warm sunshine of a spring day.
Some conversation makes you feel like a winner.
But other conversation is more like walking through a poisonous radioactive cloud.
It chokes you, it makes you feel ill, it turns you into a loser.
Gossip is just negative conversation about people, and the victim of thought poison begins to think he enjoys it.
He seems to get a form of poisoned joy from talking negatively about others,
not knowing that to successful people, he is becoming increasingly unlikable and unreliable.
One of these thought poison addicts walked into a conversation some friends and I were having about Benjamin Franklin.
As soon as Mr. Killjoy learned the topic of our chat, he came through with choice bits about Franklin's personal life in a negative way.
Perhaps it's true that Franklin was a character in some ways, and he might have made the scandal magazines,
had they been around in the 18th century.
But the point is, Benjamin Franklin's personal life had no bearing on the discussion at hand,
and I couldn't help being glad that we weren't discussing somebody whom we knew intimately.
Talk about people?
Yes, but stay on the positive side.
Let's make one point clear.
Not all conversation is gossip.