You and I have been in many situations when someone burst in and said, I've got good news.
Immediately, this person gets 100% attention from everyone present.
Good news does more than get attention.
Good news pleases people.
Good news develops enthusiasm.
Good news even promotes good digestion.
Just because there are more broadcasters of bad news than there are broadcasters of good news, don't be misled.
No one ever won a friend, no one ever made money, no one ever accomplished anything by broadcasting bad news.
Transmit good news to your family.
Tell them the good that happened today.
Recall the amusing, pleasant things you experienced and let the unpleasant things stay buried.
Spread good news.
It's pointless to pass on the bad.
It only makes your family worry, makes them nervous.
Bring home some sunlight every day.
Ever notice how seldom children complain about the weather?
They take hot weather in stride until the negative news core educate them to be conscious of unpleasant temperatures.
Make it a habit always to speak favorably about the weather, regardless of what the weather actually is.
Complaining about the weather makes you more miserable, and it spreads misery to others.
Broadcast good news about how you feel.
Be an I-feel-great person.
Just say, I feel great, at every possible opportunity, and you will feel better.
By the same token, tell people, I feel awful, just awful, and you will feel worse.
How we feel is in large part determined by how we think we feel.
Remember, too, that other people want to be around alive, enthusiastic people.
Being around complainers and half-dead people is uncomfortable.
Transmit good news to the people you work with.
Give them encouragement.
Compliment them at every opportunity.
Tell them about the positive things the company is doing.
Listen to their problems.
Be helpful.
Encourage people and win their support.