We aimlessly drift through the day, glad when it's finally over.
But when we face the day with a plan, we get things done.
This common experience provides an important lesson.
To accomplish something, we must plan to accomplish something.
Before World War II, our scientists saw the potential power locked in the atom.
but relatively little was known about how to split the atom and unleash that tremendous power.
When the United States entered the war, forward-thinking scientists saw the potential power of an atomic bomb.
A crash program was developed to accomplish just one goal, build an atomic bomb.
The result is history.
In just a few years, the concentrated effort paid off.
The bombs were dropped and the war was ended.
But without that crash program to accomplish a goal, splitting the atom would have been delayed perhaps a decade,
maybe longer.
Set Goals to Get Things Done Our great production system would be hopelessly bogged down if production executives did not establish and adhere to target dates and production schedules.
Sales executives know salesmen sell more when they are given a carefully defined quota to sell.
Professors know students get term papers written on time when a deadline is set.
Now, as you press forward to success, set goals, deadlines, target dates, self-imposed quotas.
You will accomplish only what you plan to accomplish.
According to Dr. George E. Birch of the Tulane University School of Medicine,
an expert in the study of human longevity, many things determine how long you will live.
Weight, heredity, diet, psychic tension, personal habits.
But Dr. Birch says, the quickest way to the end is to retire and do nothing.
Every human being must keep an interest in life just to keep living.
Each of us has a choice.
Retirement can be the beginning or the end.
The do-nothing-but-eat-sleep-and-rock attitude is the poison-yourself-fast form of retirement.
Most folks who regard retirement as the end of purposeful living soon find retirement is the end of life itself.
With nothing to live for, no goals, people waste away fast.
The other extreme, the sensible way to retire, is the I'm-going-to-pitch-ride-in-and-start-fast method.