Some of the most practical success-building wisdom is found in that biblical quotation stating that faith can move mountains.
Believe, really believe you can move a mountain, and you can.
Not many people believe that they can move mountains, so, as a result, not many people do.
On some occasion, you've probably heard someone say something like, it's nonsense to think you can make a mountain move away just by saying,
mountain, move away.
It's simply impossible.
People who think this way have belief confused with wishful thinking.
And true enough, you can't wish away a mountain.
You can't wish yourself into an executive suite.
Nor can you wish yourself into a five-bedroom, three-bath house or the high-income brackets.
You can't wish yourself into a position of leadership.
But you can move a mountain with belief.
You can win success by believing you can succeed.
There is nothing magical or mystical about the power of belief.
Belief works this way.
Belief, the I'm positive I can attitude, generates the power, skill, and energy needed to do.
When you believe I can do it, the how to do it develops.
Every day, all over the nation, young people start working in new jobs.
Each of them wishes that someday he could enjoy the success that goes with reaching the top.
But the majority of these young people simply don't have the belief that it takes to reach the top rungs.
And they don't reach the top.
Believing it's impossible to climb high, they do not discover the steps that lead to great heights.
Their behavior remains that of the average person.
But a small number of these young people really believe they will succeed.
They approach their work with the I'm-going-to-the-top attitude,
and with substantial belief they reach the top.