When an architect gets an idea for a new building, he makes a preliminary drawing.
When a creative advertising person gets an idea for a new TV commercial,
he puts it into storyboard form, a series of drawings that suggest what the idea will look like in finished form.
Writers with idea prepare a first draft.
NOTE Shape up the idea on paper.
There are two excellent reasons for this.
When the idea takes tangible form, you can literally look at it, see the loopholes,
see what it needs in the way of polish.
Then, too, ideas have to be sold to someone—customers, employees, the boss, friends, fellow club members, investors.
Somebody must buy the idea, else it has no value.
One summer, I was contacted by two life insurance salesmen.
Both wanted to work on my insurance program.
Both promised to return with a plan for making the needed changes.
The first salesman gave me strictly an oral presentation.
He told me in words what I needed.
But I soon was confused.
He brought in taxes, options, social security, all the technical details of insurance programming.
Frankly, he lost me, and I had to say no.
The second salesman used a different approach.
He had charted his recommendations.
All the details were shown in diagram form.
I could grasp his proposal easily and quickly because I could literally see it.
He sold me.
Resolve to put your ideas in saleable form.
An idea written or in some sort of picture or diagram form has many times more selling power than the idea presented only in oral form.