I'm a diabetic.
Right after I discovered I had this ailment, about 5,000 hypodermics ago,
I was warned, Diabetes is a physical condition, but the biggest damage results from having a negative attitude about it.
Worry about it, and you may have real trouble.
Naturally, since the discovery of my own diabetes, I've gotten to know a great many other diabetics.
Let me tell you about two extremes.
One fellow who has a very mild case belongs to that fraternity of the living dead.
Obsessed with the fear of the weather, he is usually ridiculously bundled up.
He's afraid of infection, so he shuns anybody who has the slightest sniffle.
He's afraid of overexertion, so he does almost nothing.
He spends most of his mental energy worrying about what might happen.
He bores other people, telling them how awful his problem really is.
His real ailment is not diabetes.
Rather, he's a victim of health excusitis.
He has pitied himself into being an invalid.
The other extreme is a division manager for a large publishing company.
He has a severe case.
He takes about thirty times as much insulin as the fellow just mentioned.
But he is not living to be sick.
He is living to enjoy his work and have fun.
One day he said to me, Sure, it is an inconvenience, but so is shaving.
But I'm not going to think myself to bed.
When I take those shots, I just praise the guys who discovered insulin.
A good friend of mine, a widely known college educator, came home from Europe in 1945, minus one arm.
Despite his handicap, John is always smiling, always helping others.
He's about as optimistic as anyone I know.
One day, he and I had a long talk about his handicap.
It's just an arm," he said.
Sure, two are better than one, but they just cut off my arm.
My spirit is one hundred percent intact.
I'm really grateful for that.
Another amputee friend is an excellent golfer.
One day I asked him how he had been able to develop such a near-perfect style with just one arm.
I mentioned that most golfers with two arms can't do nearly as well.
His reply says a lot.
Well, it's my experience, he said, that the right attitude and one arm will beat the wrong attitude and two arms every time.
The right attitude and one arm will beat the wrong attitude and two arms every time.
Think about that for a while.