Chapter 10 Get the Action Habit Here's something leaders in every field agree on.
There is a shortage of top-flight, expertly qualified persons to fill key positions.
There really is, as the saying goes, plenty of room at the top.
As one executive explained, there are many almost qualified people, but there is one success ingredient often missing,
that is, the ability to get things done, to get results.
Every big job, whether it be operating a business, high-level selling, in science,
the military, or the government, requires a man who thinks action.
Principal executives looking for a key person demand answers to questions like, will he do the job?
Will he follow through?
Is he a self-starter?
Can he get results or is he just a talker?
All these questions have one aim, to find out if the fellow is a man of action.
Excellent ideas are not enough.
An only fair idea acted upon and developed is one hundred percent better than a terrific idea that dies because it isn't followed up.
The great self-made merchant John Wanamaker often said, Nothing comes merely by thinking about it.
Think of it.
Everything we have in this world, from satellites to skyscrapers to baby food, is just an idea acted upon.
As you study people, both the successful and the just average, you find they fall into two classes.
The successful are active.
We'll call them activationists.
The just average, the mediocre, the unsuccessful, are passive.
We'll call them passivationists.
We can discover a success principle by studying both groups.
Mr. Activationist is a doer.
He takes action, gets things done, follows through on ideas and plans.
Mr. Passivationist is a donter.
He postpones doing things until he has proved he shouldn't or can't do them,
or until it's too late.
The difference between Mr. Activationist and Mr. Passivationist shows through in countless little ways.