Between now and tomorrow at this time, another 11,500 new consumers will have made their grand entry into the USA.
Population is growing at a record rate.
In the next 10 years, the increase is conservatively estimated at 35 million.
That's equal to the present combined metropolitan population of our five biggest cities,
New York, Chicago, Los Angeles, Detroit, and Philadelphia.
Imagine.
New industries, new scientific breakthroughs, expanding markets, all spell opportunity.
This is good news.
This is a most wonderful time to be alive.
All signs point to a record demand for top-level people in every field.
people who have superior ability to influence others, to direct their work, to serve them in a leadership capacity.
And the people who will fill these leadership positions are all adults or near-adults right now.
One of them is you.
The guarantee of a boom is not, of course, a guarantee of personal success.
Over the long pull, the United States has always been booming.
But just a fast glance shows that millions and millions of people—in fact,
a majority of them—struggle, but don't really succeed.
The majority of folks still plug along in mediocrity, despite the record opportunity of the last two decades.
And in the boom period ahead, most people will continue to worry, to be afraid,
to crawl through life feeling unimportant, unappreciated, not able to do what they want to do.
As a result, their performance will earn them petty rewards, petty happiness.
Those who convert opportunity into reward, and let me say, I sincerely believe you are one of those,
else you'd rely on luck and not bother with this book, will be those wise people who learn how to think themselves to success.
Walk in.
The door to success is open wider than ever before.
Put yourself on record now that you are going to join that select group that is getting what it wants from life.