Remember, it pays in every way to think big.
Don't sell yourself short.
Conquer the crime of self-deprecation.
Concentrate on your assets.
You're better than you think you are.
2.
Use the big thinkers vocabulary.
Use big, bright, cheerful words.
Use words that promise victory, hope, happiness, pleasure.
Avoid words that create unpleasant images of failure, defeat, grief.
3.
Stretch your vision.
See what can be, not just what is.
Practice adding value to things, to people, and to yourself.
4.
Get the big view of your job.
Think, really think your present job is important.
That next promotion depends mostly on how you think toward your present job.
5.
Think above trivial things.
Focus your attention on big objectives.
Before getting involved in a petty matter, ask yourself, is it really important?
Grow big by thinking big.