Four ways to develop the Big Thinker's vocabulary.
Here are four ways to help you develop a Big Thinker's vocabulary.
One.
Use big, positive, cheerful words and phrases to describe how you feel.
When someone asks, how do you feel today?
And you respond with an, I'm tired, I have a headache, I wish it were Saturday,
I don't feel so good.
You actually make yourself feel worse.
Practice this.
It's a very simple point, but it has tremendous power.
Every time someone asks you, how are you, or how are you feeling today,
respond with a, just wonderful, thanks, and you, or say, great, or fine.
Say you feel wonderful at every possible opportunity, and you will begin to feel wonderful, and bigger, too.
Become known as a person who always feels great.
It wins friends.
2.
Use bright, cheerful, favorable words and phrases to describe other people.
Make it a rule to have a big, positive word for all your friends and associates.
When you and someone else are discussing an absent third party, be sure you compliment him with big words and phrases like,
he's really a fine fellow.
They tell me he's working out wonderfully well.
Be extremely careful to avoid the petty cut him down language.
Sooner or later, third parties hear what's been said, and then such talk only cuts you down.
Three.
Use positive language to encourage others.
Compliment people personally at every opportunity.
Everyone you know craves praise.
Have a special good word for your wife or husband every day.
Notice and compliment the people who work with you.
Praise, sincerely administered, is a success tool.
Use it.
Use it again and again and again.
Compliment people on their appearance, their work, their achievements, their families.
Four, use positive words to outline plans to others.
When people hear something like this, here is some good news, we face a genuine opportunity,
their minds start to sparkle.
But when they hear something like, whether we like it or not, we've got a job to do.
The mind movie is dull and boring, and they react accordingly.
Promise victory and watch eyes light up.
Promise victory and win support.
Build castles, don't dig graves.
See what can be, not just what is.