One of the reviewers of an early version of this book is a close personal friend who owns his own business management consulting firm.
When he read the above illustration, he commented, That's the positive result of liking and respecting people.
Let me give you a personal experience of a friend of mine which shows what happens if you don't like and admire people.
His experience has a big point.
Here it is.
My firm obtained a contract to provide consulting services to a relatively small soft drink bottling concern.
The contract was substantial.
The client had little formal education.
His business was in bad shape, and in recent years he had made some very costly mistakes.
Three days after we had got the contract, an associate and I were driving out to his plant,
which was about 45 minutes from our offices.
To this day I don't know how it started, but somehow we began talking about the negative qualities of our client.
Before we realized it, we were talking about how his own stupidity had brought about the mess he was in,
instead of discussing how we could best approach solving his problems.
I remember one remark I made which I thought particularly clever.
The only thing holding up Mr. F is fat.
My associate laughed and came up with an equally choice observation.
And that son of his, Junior must be all of thirty-five, but the only qualification he has for the job he's holding is he speaks English.
The whole drive out, we talked about nothing else but what a weak-minded numbskull we had as a client.
Well, the conference that afternoon was cold.
Looking back, I think our client sensed somehow the way we felt toward him.
He must have thought, these fellows think I'm stupid or something, and all they're going to do for my money is give me some smooth-sounding talk.
Two days later, I got a two-sentence letter from this client.
It said, I've decided to cancel our contract for your consulting services.
If there is a charge for your services to date, please bill me.
Printing ourselves with negative thoughts for only 40 minutes cost us a contract.
What made it even more painful was learning, about a month later, that this former client had contracted with an out-of-town firm for the professional assistance he needed.
We would never have lost him had we concentrated on his many fine qualities.
And he has them.
Most people do.
Here's how you can have some fun and discover a basic success principle at the same time.
For the next two days, listen in on as many conversations as you can.
Note two things.
Which person in the conversation does the most talking, and which person is the more successful?
Hundreds of my own little experiments have revealed this.
The person who does the most talking and the person who is the most successful are rarely the same person.
Almost without exception, the more successful the person, the more he practices conversation generosity,
that is, he encourages the other person to talk about himself, his views,
his accomplishments, his family, his job, his problems.
Conversation generosity paves the way to greater success in two important ways.
One, conversation generosity wins friends.
Two, conversation generosity helps you learn more about people.
Remember this, the average person would rather talk about himself than anything else in this world.