5.
Smile Big.
Most folks have heard at one time or another that a smile will give them a real boost.
They've been told that a smile is excellent medicine for confidence deficiency.
But lots of people still don't really believe this because they've never tried smiling when they feel fear.
Make this little test.
Try to feel defeated and smile big at the same time.
You can't.
A big smile gives you confidence.
A big smile beats fear, rolls away worry, defeats despondency.
And a real smile does more than cure just your ill feeling.
A real smile melts away the opposition of others, and instantly too.
Another person simply can't be angry with you if you give them a big sincere smile.
Just the other day, a little incident happened to me that illustrates this.
I was parked at an intersection, waiting for the light to change, when bam,
the driver behind me had let his foot slip the brake and put my rear bumper to a test.
I looked back through my mirror and saw him getting out.
I got out too, and forgetting the rule book, started preparing myself for verbal combat.
I confess I was ready verbally to bite him to pieces.
But fortunately, before I got the chance, he walked up to me, smiled,
and said in the most earnest voice, Friend, I really didn't mean to do that.
That smile, matched with his sincere comment, melted me.
I mumbled something about, that's okay, happens all the time.
Almost in less time than it takes to wink an eye, my opposition turned into friendship.
Smile big and you feel like happy days are here again.
But smile big.
A half-developed smile is not fully guaranteed.
Smile until your teeth show.
That large-size smile is fully guaranteed.
I've heard many times, yes, but when I fear something or when I'm angry,
I don't feel like smiling.
Of course you don't.
No one does.
The trick is to tell yourself forcefully, I'm going to smile.
Then, smile.
Harness the power of smiling.