Consider which producers make the money from movies.
The get-rich-quick producer proceeds to make a picture.
Putting money ahead of entertainment, service, he cuts corners everywhere.
He buys a poorly written script and employs second-rate writers to adapt it.
In employing actors, arranging sets, even recording sound, he puts money first.
This producer thinks the moviegoer is a sucker, someone who can't tell good from bad.
But the get-rich-quick producer seldom does get rich quick.
There never is a bandwagon movement to buy anything second-class, especially when it is given a first-class price.
The producer who enjoys the largest profits from pictures puts entertainment ahead of money.
Rather than chisel the moviegoer, he does everything possible to give people more and better entertainment than they expect to get.
The result?
People like the movie, it gets talked about, it gets good reviews, and it makes money.
Again, put service first, and money takes care of itself.
The waitress, who concentrates on giving the best possible service, needn't worry about tips.
They'll be there.
But her counterpart, who overlooks the empty coffee cups, why refill them?
They don't look like tippers, won't find any gratuities.
The secretary, who resolves to make those letters look better than the boss expects,
will do all right on future paychecks.
But the secretary who thinks, why worry about a few smudges?
What do they expect for $65 a week?
She is stuck at $65 a week.
The salesman who gives full service to an account need harbor no fears he'll lose the account.
Here is a simple but powerful rule that will help you to develop the put-service-first attitude.
Always give people more than they expect to get.
Each little extra something you do for others is a money seed.
Volunteering to work late and get the department out of a tight spot is a money seed.
Giving customers extra service is a money seed because it brings customers back.
Advancing a new idea that will increase efficiency is a money seed.
Money seeds, of course, grow money, plant service, and harvest money.
Spend some time each day answering this question.
How can I give more than is expected of me?
Then apply the answers.
Put service first, and money takes care of itself.