Much lack of self-confidence can be traced directly to a mismanaged memory.
Your brain is very much like a bank.
Every day you make thought deposits in your mind bank.
These thought deposits grow and become your memory.
When you settle down to think or when you face a problem, in effect you say to your memory bank,
what do I already know about this?
Your memory bank automatically answers and supplies you with bits of information relating to the situation that you deposited on previous occasions.
Your memory, then, is the basic supplier of raw material for your new thought.
The teller in your memory bank is tremendously reliable.
He never crosses you up.
If you approach him and say, Mr. Teller, let me withdraw some thoughts I'd deposited in the past,
proving I'm inferior to just about everybody else, he'll say, Certainly,
sir.
Recall how you failed two times previously when you tried this?
Recall what your sixth grade teacher told you about your inability to accomplish things?
Recall what you overheard some fellow workers saying about you?
Recall And on and on, Mr. Teller goes, digging out of your brain thought after thought that proves you are inadequate.
But suppose you visit your memory teller with this request.
Mr. Teller, I face a difficult decision.
Can you supply me with any thoughts which will give me reassurance?
And again, Mr. Teller says, certainly, sir.
But this time, he delivers thoughts you deposited earlier that say you can succeed.
Recall the excellent job you did in a similar situation before?
Recall how much confidence Mr. Smith placed in you?
Recall what your good friends said about you?
Recall...
Mr. Teller, perfectly responsive, lets you withdraw the thought deposits you want to withdraw.
After all, it is your bank.