Three easy ways to cure intelligence excusitis are, number one, never underestimate your own intelligence and never overestimate the intelligence of others.
Don't sell yourself short.
Concentrate on your assets.
Discover your superior talents.
Remember, it's not how many brains you've got that matters.
Rather, it's how you use your brains that counts.
Manage your brains instead of worrying about how much IQ you've got.
2.
Remind yourself several times daily, my attitudes are more important than my intelligence.
At work and at home, practice positive attitudes.
See the reasons why you can do it, not the reasons why you can't.
Develop an I'm winning attitude.
Put your intelligence to creative positive use.
Use it to find ways to win, not to prove you will lose.
3.
Remember that the ability to think is of much greater value than the ability to memorize facts.
Use your mind to create and develop ideas, to find new and better ways to do things.
Ask yourself, am I using my mental ability to make history, or am I using it merely to record history made by others?