People who have bulldog persistence, who can grab something and not let go, have an essential success quality.
Here are two suggestions for developing greater power to experiment, the ingredient that, when blended with persistence, gets results.
1.
Tell yourself there is a way.
All thoughts are magnetic.
As soon as you tell yourself, I'm beaten, there's no way to conquer this problem,
negative thoughts are attracted, and each of these helps convince you that you are right,
that you are whipped.
Believe instead there is a way to solve this problem and positive thoughts rush into your mind to help you find a solution.
It's believing there is a way that is important.
Marriage counselors report no success in saving marriages until one and preferably both partners see that it is possible to win back happiness.
Psychologists and social workers say an alcoholic is doomed to alcoholism until he believes he can beat his thirst.
This year, thousands of new businesses are being formed.
Five years from now, only a small portion will be still in operation.
Most of those who fail will say, competition was just too much, we had no choice but to quit.
The real problem is that when most people hit the tar, things are rough,
barrier, they think only defeat, and so they are defeated.
When you believe there is a way, you automatically convert negative energy, let's quit,
let's go back, into positive energy, let's keep going, let's move ahead.
A problem, a difficulty, becomes unsolvable only when you think it is unsolvable.
Attract solutions by believing solutions are possible.
Refuse.
Simply refuse to even let yourself say or think that it's impossible.
2.
Back off and start afresh.
Often we stay so close to a problem for so long that we can't see new solutions or new approaches.