a cooperative family that won't object to travel, irregular hours, and other inconveniences which are part of selling,
a family that will help the salesman over those inevitable rough spots.
Executives today realize that what happens on weekends and between 6 p.m. and 9 a.m. directly affects a person's performance from 9 a.m. to 6 p.m. The person with a constructive off-the-job life nearly always is more successful than the person who lives in a dull,
dreary home situation.
Let's look in on the traditional way two co-workers, John and Milton, spend their weekends.
Let's look, too, at the ultimate results.
John's psychological diet on weekends is something like this.
Usually, one evening is spent with some carefully selected, interesting friends.
Another evening is generally spent out, perhaps at a movie, a civic or community project, or some friend's house.
John devotes Saturday morning to Boy Scout work.
Saturday afternoon he does errands and chores around the house.
Often he works on some special project.
Currently it's building a patio in the backyard.
On Sundays, John and his family do something special.
One Sunday, recently, they climbed a mountain.
Another Sunday, they visited a museum.
Occasionally, they drive into the nearby countryside, for John wants to buy some country property in the not-too-distant future.
Sunday evening is spent quietly.
John usually reads a book and catches up on the news.
Wrapped up, John's weekends are planned.
His many refreshing activities keep boredom locked out.
John gets plenty of psychological sunshine.
Milton's psychological diet is much less well balanced than John's.
His weekends are unplanned.
Milton is usually pretty tired on Friday night, but he goes through the motions of asking his wife,
want to do anything tonight?
But the plan dies there.
Rarely do Milton and his wife entertain, and rarely are they invited out.
Milton sleeps late on Saturday morning, and the rest of the day is taken up with chores of one kind or another.
Saturday night, Milton and his family usually go to a movie or watch TV.
What else is there to do?
Milton spends most of Sunday morning in bed.
Sunday afternoon, they drive over to Bill and Mary's, or Bill and Mary drive over to see them.
Bill and Mary are the only couple Milton and his wife visit regularly.
Milton's entire weekend is marked by boredom.
By the time Sunday evening rolls around, the whole family is on each other's nerves as a result of cabin fever.
There are no knock-down, drag-out fights, but there are hours of psychological warfare.
Milton's weekend is dull, dreary, boring.
Milton gets no psychological sunshine.